<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: communication | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/communication/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-29T00:42:18+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Is Asynchronous Communication Superior?]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="last article">last article</a>
I detailed why synchronous communication is not
appropriate for work: it leads to interruptions, involves moving or
shouting, drifts and leaves no trace.<br/>
To solve this communication problem I believe in the asynchronous way of
doing it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/6370949347/"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6052/6370949347_a66d54d217_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/" title="Author">Modestas J</a></em></p>

<h2>Asynchronous?</h2>

<p>WTF is this? In an asynchronous communication
interlocutors can exchange and continue their discussion
whenever they want it. Examples of
asynchronous communication media are letter, text message, email,
chat. They all share a common something in common: they are <strong>written communication
media</strong>.</p>

<h2>Asynchronous Channels Are Superior</h2>

<p>The massive use of text messages illustrates the <strong>usefulness and the
advantages an asynchronous communication offers over an oral conversation.</strong>
It's quick, efficient, you can respond hours later and  keep track of the history.
You should use different asynchronous communication media for different usecases. Your day-to-day conversation?
Do it by chat. A code review? Use Github and Pull Requests. Important annoucements? Write an email. Organize
your communication and insert it in your workflow. Segmenting your communication will help you manage it efficiently
and will diminish the pressure of a single overloaded inbox.</p>

<h2>Why Does Email Kill Your Productivity?</h2>

<p>At work, people seem to use email as the sole form of asynchronous communication. Emails are adapted for
internal communication like <strong>reports, formal announcements</strong>. If you write less-than-two-lines emails
you are doing it wrong. Do you really need an email to say <em>"Ok I'll do it"</em> or <em>"Thanks"</em>?
For everyday use they are counter productive. You end up receiving tons
of emails a day, <strong>spending hours responding, deleting and archiving.</strong></p>

<h2>The Right Communication Medium: the Chat Room</h2>

<p>Setting up a chat room for your team is probably one of the most important
action you can do to improve its efficiency and productivity.
90% of its communication should occur there. With a chat room solution
<strong>conversations history is easily accessible, you can simultaneously participate to
multiple groups of discussions, sending a message is so much easier</strong>! Aren't you bored of
clicking <em>New Message</em>, filling in recipients addresses? Even clicking on <em>Respond</em>
is painful.<br/>
Chat rooms are really the most adequate medium to communicate for your team.
<a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="Previous post">Even</a>
if you work at the same place.</p>

<p><strong>Don't waste more time and set up your private chat room.</strong>
<a href="http://www.hipchat.com" title="HipChat">HipChat</a> is a great tool for that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Shouldn't Use Synchronous Communication At Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a recent <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/" title="Article">post</a>,
James Slavet (Greylock Partners) describes metrics we should consider to
be more productive. The top one is called Flow State Percentage and
measures the relative time we are deeply concentrated on what we are doing. Flow state has
an amazing impact on development cycles times. A big threat to flow state lies in synchronous communication.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/1226209342/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1209/1226209342_ad08767199_m.jpg" alt="Muzzle" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/" title="Author">This Year Love</a></em></p>

<h2>Synchronous communication?</h2>

<p>Synchronous forms of communication include face
to face conversation or phone discussion.
Synchronous because people talking do it at the
same exact moment: ever tried answering your colleagues
2 minutes or 1 hour after they asked you a question? That's impossible
as oral conversations don't work with delay.
Asynchronous communication solves that problem
by relies on a written exchange.</p>

<h2>What for?</h2>

<p>Oral conversations are <strong>only appropriate when a written exchange could take
much longer than it should</strong>: conflict resolution, detailed
explanation of a topic, etc. For other situations
synchronous communication is counter-productive.</p>

<h2>The pitfalls of synchronous communication at work</h2>

<p>For your everyday work conversations you should think twice
before having an oral discussion. Why? Here are <strong>4 reasons</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Oral discussion = interruption</strong> When somebody
asks you something it drains all your attention. You have to switch your
focus to provide the adequate answer which means you lose all the
concentration you had in your work.
The ten-seconds question becomes a ten-minutes perturbation, taking into
account the time you need to refocus (if you even manage to refocus)
and recall what your were doing.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>It involves moving and/or shouting in the office</strong>. Depending on
your work office configuration talking with somebody means moving to his
desk or shouting through the open space. In the former case it
magnifies your work interruption. In the latter case you'll manage
to effectively disturb everyone of your coworkers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fatally you drift</strong> Oral conversations drift more than
a bobsleigh on ice. Have you ever started a conversation about
the crucial decision you should take and ended up speaking of the last
hilarious meme you read?</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Exchanges are lost for the posterity</strong> Oral conversations are not actionable, for you
or your teammates. What if you need to recall all the points
stated? How do you keep track of the history of your conversation?
What if the following week you'll have the same question?
Won't you feel bad disturbing your colleagues again?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Before engaging in any kind of communication there is one thing
you should try: <strong>find an answer by yourself</strong>.
But sometimes it's more efficient
to ask for somebody's help instead of googling to find the appropriate
answer. In that case <strong>go for asynchronous communication.</strong></p>

<p>In a later post I'll cover asynchronous communication
especially the pitfalls of emails and the benefits of having a chat room
for your team.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
