<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-29T12:35:34+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capitalize on What You Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T14:27:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a lot, probably an average of 15 blogposts a day and a book every
two weeks. I find that I sometimes have a lot of trouble
remembering the things I just read. Well it&#8217;s
usually not completely forgotten, the information is likely stored in my
unconscious brain and will trickle back to my consciousness when
somethings triggers it, such as a question or a situation that matches
the pattern my brain stored when I read said content. So that means I
just need a little prodding in order to remember. However there is I
think a more interesting question: how do you build upon what you read?
How do you effectively turn information into knowledge? The secret lies in
having an active attitude towards remembering things, and not just passively consume content.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/2641415853/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3061/2641415853_325ea48e8e_n.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/" title="Author">Shishberg</a></em></p>

<h2>Write it Down</h2>

<p>Writing things down has a number of wonderful consequences.</p>

<p>First of all
the information is &#8220;safer&#8221; in the sense that it is now written down in a
place from which it is easier to retrieve in its actual form than from
your unconscious brain. Not only that but it also ensures that the
information stays put and doesn&#8217;t change. One cannot say the same holds
true for memories, as the brain changes them all the time. Memories are
very volatile and often the brain tampers with them to spin them more
positively or make them more relevant to the context. Writing down will prevent
information from being distorted by your unconscious brain.</p>

<p>Additionally, writing things down will actually strengthen your memories.
When you write full sentences that
are grammatically correct (or close to correct at least), you must
formalize relationships between facts, entities, people, and concepts.
The brain being better suited to memorize relationships and patterns,
it will be easier for you to memorize that way instead of simply highlighting a few
words or numbers here and there that aren&#8217;t linked together by explicit relationships. (Think of a graph.)</p>

<p>Last but not least, text is universal. Information in writing is easily
accessible and shareable. This is important because for instance say you
store information in other formats such as audio or video, it
won&#8217;t be as easily retrieved and accessed. This is why I love blogposts
but am not a fan of podcasts or videos that don&#8217;t include a &#8220;textified&#8221;
version.</p>

<p>In that regard, I write summaries of what I read and find most
interesting and useful. It is important to summarize relationships and
not facts only, so that it matches the brain&#8217;s memorizing process.</p>

<h2>Practice</h2>

<p>Musicians are known for their disciplined rehearsals. When I was 10
years old I started learning to play the piano. My parents would pay
this private tutor that came once a week and insisted I play 3 hours of
piano per day. At this time I was of course way to enthralled by my
Playstation to care, but I do regret it now. So I didn&#8217;t practice like I
should have, and the promising career as a pianist that lied ahead of me
ground to a screeching halt. However some of my friends heroically put in the
effort and I can see now that practice makes perfect.</p>

<p>Where does that all fit with memorizing and building knowledge? The goal is to
apply the methods of musicians to the practice of building knowledge. In that
case, practicing means a few things:
* Write an interesting bit of knowledge down in different ways, targetting varied audiences (yourself, your family,
  friends, colleagues, etc.)
* Talk about it to people who have a varying level of understanding of
  that particular topic. They will ask you questions you didn&#8217;t expect
  and force you to dig deeper and strengthen your knowledge.
* Weave blobs of knowledge together. By that I mean think about what one
  relationship in a given domain means if applied to another one. (For
  instance Math and Computer Science, or Sociology and Networks,
  Math and Art, etc.) Bridging domains will often make great insights and
  ideas pop in your head and further strengthen your understanding and
  memory of a bit of knowledge.</p>

<p>Capitalizing on what you read by writing it down and practicing will
slowly (but surely!) turn you in a walking encyclopedia. You will be able to remember
a lot more things than you are used to, and gradually gain a deeper
understanding of what you memorize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tutorial: Domain Name System for Beginners]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/22/dns-redirections/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/22/dns-redirections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you build a website, you will want your own domain name, which means
you will need to manage your Domain Name System (DNS). While there is nothing very
complicated here, the info is scattered across the Internet, so I decided
to write a &#8220;cheat sheet&#8221;-like tutorial which will hopefully save you some time!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/49502986585@N01/277341190/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/122/277341190_3f098a08a4_n.jpg" alt="Code" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ezu/" title="Author">Ezu</a></em></p>

<h2>What is the DNS?</h2>

<p>The DNS is a system that helps your computer translate human-readable <strong>domain names</strong>
into computer-usable <strong>IP addresses</strong> (4 numbers between 0 and 255
identifying a server).</p>

<p>A domain name must have two parts, separated by a dot: the <strong>actual domain</strong> (e.g. <em>google</em>) and the
<strong>top-level domain</strong> (e.g. <em>com</em>). In this example, the domain name is
<em>google.com</em>. Optionally, you can also use different <strong>subdomains</strong>, so
that users typing <em>subdomain1.domain.tld</em> and <em>subdomain2.domain.tld</em>
arrive on two different pages. The well-known <em>www</em> is a subdomain of
<em>google.com</em> in the address <em>www.google.com</em>.</p>

<p>To use your own custom domain name, you need
to buy one from a <strong>registrar</strong> (such as <a href="https://www.gandi.net/">Gandi</a>).</p>

<h2>How to manage it: the zone file</h2>

<p>Most registrars will let you use Web forwardings, which are simple
redirections (what happens when the webpage you are looking at automatically changes to another page). However, you should
avoid those for the following reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>Simple redirections will replace your domain name by your IP address,
which is the best way to scare off users</li>
<li>Masked redirections will not scare off users, but they will give you a
very poor search-engine rating</li>
</ul>


<p>You will need to use the <strong>zone file</strong>. It is a simple text file
describing the structure of your DNS zone (usually your domain) to the global DNS
(i.e. the world). Let&#8217;s take a look at a sample zone file (the zone file on
Gandi for our blog <a href="http://needforair.com">needforair.com</a>.</p>

<p>These are the DNS rules for our domain <code>needforair.com</code>:</p>

<pre><code>@ 3600 IN A 184.106.20.102
www 3600 IN CNAME needforair.com.
wik 3600 IN CNAME fr.wikipedia.org.
</code></pre>

<p>You usually also find lines similar to the following in a zone file.
They manage the email server your registrar provides you, and shouldn&#8217;t
touch them:</p>

<pre><code>@ 3600 IN MX 10 spool.mail.gandi.net.
@ 3600 IN MX 50 fb.mail.gandi.net.
smtp 3600 IN CNAME relay.mail.gandi.net.
webmail 3600 IN CNAME agent.mail.gandi.net.
pop 3600 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
imap 3600 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
</code></pre>

<p>The most important points here are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Each line corresponds to one rule (a record)</li>
<li>The <code>@</code> character represents your bare domain (needforair.com in our example) as opposed
to subdomains such as <code>test.needforair.com</code> or <code>www.needforair.com</code></li>
<li>An <code>A</code> record points to an IP address, usually your server. In our example, <code>@ 3600 IN A 184.106.20.102</code>
indicates that a user typing &#8216;needforair.com&#8217; in his address bar will request content from the IP address 184.106.20.102.
The <code>3600</code> number is the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_to_live#DNS_records">Time To Live (TTL)</a> of the record,
the time (in seconds) during which a nameserver will cache the record and not ask the authoritative server (Gandi here)
if queried again</li>
<li>A <code>CNAME</code> record points to any domain or subdomain, either in your zone or outside.
In our example, <code>www 3600 IN CNAME needforair.com.</code> means that a user typing <code>www.needforair.com</code> will request content
from the same IP address as needforair.com (that&#8217;s not the case by default). You can of course use a CNAME to any other
domain, in our example <code>wik 3600 IN CNAME fr.wikipedia.org.</code> which will make users typing &#8220;wik.needforair.com&#8221; in their
address bar go to the French version of Wikipedia instead (don&#8217;t try it
we removed it!)</li>
<li><strong>Don&#8217;t forget the period (&#8216;.&#8217;) at the end of your CNAMEs !!!</strong> For example, use &#8220;needforair.com.&#8221;, and NOT &#8220;needforair.com&#8221;.
If you forget the period, the record simply won&#8217;t work, and you will
spend an awful lot of time to figure out why</li>
</ul>


<p>There are lots of other types of rules, but this should be enough to set up your DNS.</p>

<p>Last note: keep in mind that <strong>changes to the zone file take some time</strong>,
usually a few hours, to propagate through the Internet. So don&#8217;t make a
mistake or they will take some time to spot and correct!</p>

<h2>Discover more</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://continuations.com/post/16405180072/tech-tuesday-dns">A great primer on DNS for the non-technical</a></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zone_file">Wikipedia&#8217;s article on the Zone file</a></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System">Wikipedia&#8217;s article on the DNS</a>.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Lets You Talk to World-Class Experts]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/20/twitter-lets-you-talk-to-wordclass-experts/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-20T04:35:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/20/twitter-lets-you-talk-to-wordclass-experts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I had a conversation on Twitter with <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rjs">Ryan
Singer</a> of <a href="http://37signals.com">37 Signals</a>
fame. Ryan is a world-class expert in product design and had just posted an <a href="http://feltpresence.com/articles/16-managing-product-development-by-integrating-around-concerns">article</a>
on his excellent <a href="http://feltpresence.com/">blog</a>. The thing is I am a
nobody in product design or in the tech scene in general. I&#8217;m not saying
I&#8217;m dumb or anything, just that nobody knows me. And yet I was
still able to have a great and stimulating conversation with an expert
who&#8217;s email inbox is presumably very full, lives thousands of kilometers
away from me and doesn&#8217;t know anything about me. This was not the first
time I&#8217;ve been amazed by the power of Twitter, so I decided to blog about
it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brajeshwar/3428525318/in/photostream"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3393/3428525318_0729579705_n.jpg" alt="Twitter Mosaic" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brajeshwar/" title="Author">Brajeshwar</a></em></p>

<h2>140 characters Enable Improbable Conversations</h2>

<p>That length constraint compels people to get straight to the point.
There is no fluff. No awkward openings, no pompous endings, no walls of
text. People expect direct questions and answers and wouldn&#8217;t have it any other
way.</p>

<p>This magically enables you to talk to some people you would never have sent an
email to. And busy people that don&#8217;t know you at all, that might be
thought leaders or experts, will answer you if
you ask an interesting question. Because the constraint also works for
the response: they don&#8217;t have to send you a long well thought-out answer,
they don&#8217;t need to get context to answer, they can just type 140
characters.</p>

<p>I have asked questions to succesful entrepreneurs, or VCs, and almost
always gotten a quick answer. This is incredibly cool and powerful. And
these people don&#8217;t know me at all.</p>

<h2>No Social Pressure or Awkwardness</h2>

<p>The Twitter feed moves so swiftly that conversations are extremely
ephemeral. I think this is key to enabling these kinds of improbable
conversations. The fact that it moves so quickly reduces the social
pressure: few people will see it, it will not mark your Twitter profile
for a long time, and nobody will assume that the two people conversing
are great friends or anything. Twitter enables conversations in a
vacuum, without having to build up a relationship. There is no pressure
for the expert to become friend with the person he is talking to.</p>

<p>When you try to email or talk on the phone to an expert, you always want to be super apologetic,
respectful and you don&#8217;t really focus on the content of the
conversation you&#8217;re trying to have but instead you focus on the
asymmetry of the relationship and that makes you uncomfortable. Twitter makes all these concerns vanish.</p>

<p>I love Twitter for these opportunities.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Game of Go: a Programmer's Perspective]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/18/game-of-go/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/18/game-of-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The game of go is very interesting from an AI programmer&#8217;s point of
view, because of how difficult it is to make a computer compete against
a strong human and how researchers approached the problem. Paradoxically, the use of randomly played games has helped computers get much stronger.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/92544159@N00/322662164/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/134/322662164_0260e91add_n.jpg" alt="Go" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/obli/" title="Author">oblivionz</a></em></p>

<h2>Game of Go: a (very) brief overview</h2>

<p>Go is wildly popular in Asia but little known in the Western world. Similar to Chess, it is a strategy game where two players take
turn placing stones on a board. The key differences between these
two are:</p>

<ul>
<li>In Go, the board starts empty, and you add stones at each turn whereas in
chess you start with an army and try to destroy the other one</li>
<li>The <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?RulesOfGoIntroductory">rules</a> are much simpler in Go than in Chess: in particular there is only one type of stone while Chess uses six different pieces</li>
</ul>


<p>I really encourage you to check it out, you can <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/?RulesOfGoIntroductory">learn to play here</a> and <a href="http://www.gokgs.com/">play here</a>.</p>

<h2>Compexity, comparison to chess</h2>

<p>Even though the rules are simple, it has proven to be very hard to
build a good Go-playing program. In fact, while top Chess-playing
softwares can compete with the best humans (remember how Deep Blue beat
Gary Kasparov in 1997), even strong amateurs can beat the top Go-playing
programs. And strong amateurs are much weaker than top pros. There are three main reasons for this:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Game-tree complexity</strong>: there are about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shannon_number">10<sup>123</sup> possible games
in Chess</a>. As for Go,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_and_mathematics">estimates vary</a> but
the <a href="http://www.usgo.org/resources/topten.html">American Go Association reckons there are 10<sup>700</sup> possible
games</a>. This is because there
are more turns in a Go game than in a Chess game (200 vs 50 on average),
and more possibilities at each turn in Go (up to 350 vs 50).</li>
<li><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evaluation_function">Lack of a good heuristic</a></strong>: Chess programs are able to evaluate quite accurately and quickly whether a given position is better than another one. On the contrary, no good heuristic has been found for Go yet.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern-recognition</strong>: strong Go players rely heavily on recognizing
the shapes the stones take. There are too many of them for a computer
to try and recognize in a game timeframe, and <a href="http://curiosity.discovery.com/question/humans-better-than-computers">humans are much better than them at this</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Key ideas behind current Go-playing programs</h2>

<p>This complexity is what makes the study of Go algorithms so interesting.
A few years ago we saw a spectacular improvement, led by a
program called <a href="http://www.lri.fr/~teytaud/mogo.html">MoGo</a>. The key
ideas behind MoGo are:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Position evaluation using random games</strong>: paradoxically, it was
found that the best way to evaluate a position is to play, from this
position, a lot of games were each player puts stones at random
on the board. A position&#8217;s score is simply the percentage of won
random games.</li>
<li><strong>Use of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-armed_bandit">multi-armed bandit</a> algorithms</strong> to decrease the branching factor (the number of moves the program has to consider at each turn). The goal here is to optimize the trade-off between exploration (trying new moves) and exploitation (further testing the most promising moves to select the best one). The computer begins with a prior probability distribution for every possible move. It picks one according to this distribution, plays a random game from the corresponding position and uses the result to update the probability for this move. It then selects another possible move according to the updated distribution and so on.</li>
<li><strong>Use of a little expert knowledge</strong>: the prior distribution used in the
multi-armed bandit is calculated so as to avoid trivially stupid moves.
For the opening of the game, classic starting positions are also
favored. And the random games are not completely random since they avoid
certain moves according to simple patterns. Nonetheless, expert
knowledge is used scarcely as it really hurts the exploration part of
the algorithm.</li>
<li><strong>Parallelization</strong>: MoGo and the likes can become very good on
computer clusters, since the random game part can be run on mutliple
CPUs. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amdahl's_law">speedup factor</a> is
about 8x.</li>
<li><strong>Reinforcement learning</strong>: MoGo learns during the game and the
randoms play-outs that some kind of responses to his opponent&#8217;s moves are likely to have a bad
result, and assigns them a lower probability.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can learn more on MoGo <a href="http://www.pleinsud.u-psud.fr/specialR2008/en/12_GOthique.pdf">in this article</a>.</p>

<h2>Current strength of computers</h2>

<p>Today, Go-playing programs are able to compete with professional players on small (9x9) boards, and with strong amateurs (5d KGS) on normal boards (19x19). This is quite an achievement, but there is still a long way to go before they can face professional players on normal boards!</p>

<p><em>I am a Go player myself, even though not very good! During an
internship in a Computer Science laboratory, I worked on <a href="http://www.lri.fr/~teytaud/mogo.html">MoGo</a> for 2 months in 2008.</em><br/>
<em>Special thanks to <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/arpad-rimmel/b/9a7/847">Arpad Rimmel</a> for having reviewed this article. He spent 3 years working on Mogo when he was a PhD student.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup, Music and Buzz]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/15/startup-music-and-buzz/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T11:33:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/15/startup-music-and-buzz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Various creative initiatives face the same challenges as startups.
In its
<a href="http://leanpub.com/manifesto">manifesto</a>, <a href="http://leanpub.com/">Leanpub</a> points out the similarities
between writing a book and launching a startup: <em>both are risky, creative
processes, often undertaken in stealth mode and with hit-driven economics.</em></p>

<p>The same parallel can be drawn with the music industry or more generally
with independant creative activities. Crowdfunding platforms
<a href="http://www.mymajorcompany.com/">MyMajorCompany</a> or <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/">KickStarter</a>
illustrate the similarities between all these processes.
Independant singers who are not supported by famous productors bear the risk,
have to build their <em>product</em> and develop their marketing
strategy on their own.</p>

<p>Once the beta version of the product is ready to showcase, a single in
the case of singers, the difficulty is to market it. How can one achieve
some traction? One option that seems profitable is to place the
product in a favourable context by attaching it to an event which
benefits from a good media coverage. Mainstream and new medias alike have such a big impact
on the crowd that they can drain lots of attention. Leveraging these
media can be key.</p>

<p>Recently in France a singer succeeded in creating a buzz
on the internet, hitting more than 600 000 views on Youtube, with its
single on a candidate for the presidential elections. In the same vein
as <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKsoXHYICqU"><em>I got a crush on Obama</em></a> she drew the media attention in a very
effective way by leveraging the current context.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/40084651"><img src="http://www.lalsace.fr/fr/images/A7098988-85DA-4603-8E31-654249FE82BB/ALS_03/capture-d-ecran-du-clip-musical-de-victoire-passage-prends-le-pouvoir-sur-moi-jean-luc-melenchon.jpg" width="400" alt="Video" /></a></p>

<p>Making a buzz gives the impression of success. But how can we be assured it is going to last? Does a spike in the audience really help to succeed with
one&#8217;s product? When one realize that <a href="http://simply.io/blog/2012/03/welcome-to-the-real-world-just-because-youre-on-techcrunch-doesnt-mean-youve-won/">90% of the companies appearing on TC
are abandoned within 6 months</a>
one can question the relevance of the press coverage and the buzz one
can create to build a durable success. Instead, one should be focused
on building one&#8217;s audience. Successfull startups and creators don&#8217;t
rely on a single shot try, they build their success gradually at the same
time as their audience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Golden Age Of Community Organizing Platforms]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T08:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/">already wrote</a> about how
you can leverage some <a href="https://github.com/">social platforms</a> to build
your visibility on the internet, but they offer much more.
They provide appropriate tools that help people to be more productive
and better organized. They are much more functional than pure social networks
and even more valuable as the communities are active.</p>

<p><img src="http://cardview.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/nation-builder.jpg" height="220" alt="Keep the gist" /></p>

<h2>Platforms structure communities</h2>

<p>We can call such a platform a <em>community organizing platform</em> because
it allows a community to have a place to gather, discuss and share. It
provides the global structure the community needs to get organized.
Ten years ago the forums laid the foundation but today these platforms
achieve what&#8217;s been initiated.</p>

<p>Using these platforms everyone creates and manages a business card that
is accessible by everyone else.
People can easily be identified, followed, consulted and appraised. You
don&#8217;t have to go to as many conferences or events to meet new people
because it can be done very efficiently online.</p>

<h2>Community organizing platforms offer more than pure social networks</h2>

<p>Pure social networks like Twitter offer ways to
organize communities but don&#8217;t provide the structure
and tools needed for effective collaboration. They are mainly focus on
sharing.</p>

<p>While community organizing platforms provide a social layer they
also offer services geared towards the community itself. This
combination is what&#8217;s really valuable.
<a href="http://nationbuilder.com/">Nation Builder</a>
is the perfect example: it features volunteer organization, donation
monitoring, website creation&#8230; a comprehensive package
political leaders need to interact with their audience.</p>

<h2>Active communities are driven by knowledge</h2>

<p>We can distinguish communities built upon friendship, professional
activity or common interests. The most active
are the ones based on a common interest, where knowledge and
feedback is a valuable resource. In these ones people spend a lot of time
looking for information. They also create a lot of content in order to
improve their reputation. Such platforms are even more
important for small communities because the resources they want to access are not always well
indexed by search engines.</p>

<p>As sharing information, working collaboratively and giving feedbacks to peers is key in
these communities even a very little one
can be very active.
There is still lots of
them to structure out there, lots of people waiting to
share and collaborate with their peers. Who are they? What can we do for
them?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Pirate Party Will Help Improve Internet Regulation]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/09/why-the-pirate-party-will-help-improve-internet-regulation/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T10:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/09/why-the-pirate-party-will-help-improve-internet-regulation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past years, we have seen a lot of developped countries
governments pushing for more regulation of the Internet, and less
privacy for users. There are three main reasons: protection of
children, prevention of terrorism and <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture/">fight against illegal downloading</a>. This has led to very repressive and usually inefficient laws, for example in Australia, in France (Hadopi) and <a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/hillicon-valley/technology/220181-dodd-says-sopa-can-live-again">possibly soon</a> in the US. I think that a big part of this problem is that a very large portion of the people making these laws understand next to nothing about the Internet, and are thus afraid of it. What can we do about it?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/20888197@N00/103031916/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/43/103031916_5c6c0a51af_m.jpg" alt="Pirate" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/opid/" title="Author">sereneonion</a></em></p>

<h2>Direct education is not enough</h2>

<p>Direct education is the most natural answer. Initiatives like Google&#8217;s
<a href="http://www.20thingsilearned.com/en-US">20 things I learned about browsers and the Web</a> for example, aim at explaining very simply the basics to beginners. More focused initiatives like the <a href="http://www.eg8forum.com/en/">electronic G8 forum</a>, which was held last year in Paris are interesting too. But unfortunately, none of these will make a real impact as long as politicians have so little interest for this world. What we really need is to make them <strong>want</strong> to learn about the Internet.</p>

<h2>The Pirate Party can play a significant role</h2>

<p>What politicians really care about is of course to get (re)elected. And
since they are busy people, they only tackle the subjects they feel are the
most importants for voters, which are nowadays the economic crisis and
unemployment. This is where I think the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pirate_Party">Pirate Party</a> has a huge role to play. Even though they are still a fringe party today, they <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/09/20/world/europe/in-berlin-pirates-win-8-9-percent-of-vote-in-regional-races.html">have had some electoral success</a> and have shown the political world that voters do care about Internet-related issues. If they continue to be successful, I am pretty sure that mainstream politicians, who hold the real power, will want to understand the Internet better, leading to a more fruitful public debate.</p>

<p>It will surely take some time, but I think <strong>it will happen</strong>, because it already happened in the past: 30 years ago, neither voters nor politicians cared about the environment, and the Green parties were regarded the same way the Pirate party is today. Now, ecology is a significant political topic in many European countries. The Internet is next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Computers in Text Summarization]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Stanislas explained in <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/" title="Information Overload">this previous post</a>, we believe we are dealing with too much information to keep up on the Internet. The natural solution is text summarization, and computers can help us there.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/3558255554/sizes/l/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3376/3558255554_9f9c480132_n.jpg" alt="Summary" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/" title="Author">Xeeiliz</a></em></p>

<p>There are roughly two kinds of summaries: the ones that consist of a few of
the most important sentences extracted from the text, the keyphrases, and the ones that
are written from scratch without necessarily using the same phrasing, called abstract summaries.</p>

<h2>Finding the most relevant content: keyphrase extraction</h2>

<p>The big advantage of keyphrase-based summaries is that there is no risk
of miscomprehension since they are composed of unrephrased pieces of the
text. Moreover, computers are able to compute them and get decent
results. There are two main ways to do it: supervised and unsupervised
extraction.</p>

<h3>When you know the context: extraction as supervised learning</h3>

<p>One way to perform this task is described by Peter Turney in <a href="http://webdocs.cs.ualberta.ca/~lindek/650/papers/turney.pdf">this paper</a>. He found that using a custom-designed algorithm that incorporates specialized domain knowledge on a text generates yields very good results: 80% of keyphrases are deemed acceptable by human readers. The problem with this approach is that it requires the computer to know the topic beforehand. It is possible to use a prior first step to determine what it is, but this is difficult and the results are terrible if we get it wrong.</p>

<h3>Applicable to any text: unsupervised keyphrase extraction</h3>

<p>This approaches enables us to extract keyphrases from a text without any
prior knowledge, which is a tremendous improvement upon the previous method. There a several algorithms, and one notable current example is <a href="http://www.summly.com/">Summly</a>. I will explain one of those, named TextRank, to give you a feeling of the kind of techniques used in this field.</p>

<p>The TextRank algorithm was developped by Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau in
<a href="http://acl.ldc.upenn.edu/acl2004/emnlp/pdf/Mihalcea.pdf">this paper</a>. The key idea is that a text
unit (word or phrase depending on the need) that is close to a lot of other important text units is likely a keyphrase. Using the parallel between the &#8220;close to&#8221; relation and the &#8220;referred to by&#8221; relation of hyperlinks, TextRank uses Google&#8217;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">PageRank</a> to determine which text units are the most important. It works well, its main author was even awarded a $100k grant by Google for her work on keyphrase extraction.</p>

<h2>The best: abstract summarization</h2>

<p>Even though they can be very useful, keyphrase-based summaries are still
rudimentary compared to abstract summaries, because they are much nicer
to read, and we are sure no important information was &#8220;left behind&#8221; (i.e a keyphrase was not extracted). Also, keyphrase extraction algorithms still find it hard to
summarize technical articles.</p>

<p>Abstract summarization is the limit of what computers can do today. The
main reason for this is that they struggle with the following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Coreferences understanding</strong>. For example, who does &#8216;he&#8217;
references in the sentence &#8216;Paul told John he should play squash&#8217;?</li>
<li><strong>Word sense disambiguation</strong>. In &#8216;I need batteries for
my mouse&#8217;, are we talking about the animal or the device?</li>
<li><strong>Sentiment analysis</strong>. Understanding the mood of the writer is often
key to understanding a text, all the more when there is sarcasm.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Computers can help humans summarize a text</h2>

<p>To sum it up, I believe that humans still cannot be replaced by
algorithms if we want to produce quality summaries. Nonetheless, a
computer really can help a us by providing a keyphrase-based summary,
so that we spend less time scanning the text for them. In addition, if
we were able to train algorithms by comparing their output with a human
summary a lot of times for articles on a certain topic, I think it is possible we see significant improvements.</p>

<p><em>Note: some examples were taken from <a href="https://class.coursera.org/nlp/">Stanford&#8217;s Natural Language
Processing online class</a>. If you couldn&#8217;t take
it this quarter, look for it, it is a terrific place to learn about this
topic</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Didn't Learn In College]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T23:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Albert Wenger is right:
<a href="http://continuations.com/post/20112755144/students-are-woefully-prepared-for-internet-age-job">we are woefully prepared for internet age job market</a>.
The three of us graduated in Computer Science in college, following a solid
engineering cursus. But during the
numerous courses we took we never heard of <a href="http://github.com/">Github</a> nor <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">StackOverflow</a>.
People attending creative and artistic
formation don&#8217;t hear of <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a> neither.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7044/7046351459_53d8ed3283.jpg" alt="Jeff Atwood" /></p>

<p>You could argue: &#8220;What&#8217;s the problem with that? You aren&#8217;t supposed to learn
how to use these platforms in school but core skills in your field!&#8221;</p>

<p>But that would be missing a point. The education we all receive has one final
goal: be prepared to get the best job as possible. In our current
era <strong>finding a job doesn&#8217;t come down to respond to job offers by sending
cover letters and resume</strong> nor spam by email all our contacts in the industry
to get an interview.</p>

<p>We are lucky to live through the emergence and the
expansion of specialized platforms which can help us build our personal
and professional identity. With these platforms <strong>we can easily have a
professional visibility, expose our skills so they can be assessed by
everyone and acquire real experience with real work.</strong></p>

<p>The very first recommendation we should receive beginning a course in
a topic is registering on all the platforms related to this topic. The
professors should foster us to leverage these platform to develop our
skills, build our expertise and gain some fame. Such platforms work this way: they play with
our ego to encourage us to contribute more and more and make our
achievements visible for everyone in return. <strong>They are built to be our showcase</strong> and
we should take advantage of it. We do so many interesting projects in
school, sometimes state of the art implementations in CS, that get lost
on our machine. They should be public to catch recruiters&#8217; attention on
our profile and skills or help us <a href="http://cdixon.org/2012/02/26/the-internet-is-reshaping-our-economy-from-one-of-huge-corporations-with-lots-of-jobs-to-huge-platforms-with-lots-of-income-streams/">create our future income streams</a>.</p>

<p>So at which level can we improve the promotion of such platforms? At the school&#8217;s level?
At the professors&#8217; level? They should all keep up with the internet economy like they
usually keep up with the <em>real</em> economy. Schools should increase professors&#8217; awareness, who
are mainly researchers in engineering schools for example, to this
concern but it&#8217;s up to the professors to promote personaly the right
platforms. Professors do already a great job teaching us their
knowledge, <strong>they should go further and encourage us to capitalize on their
teaching</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siri or the Reinvention of Mobile Search User Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T17:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Search is a behavior, it is what people do when they want to find
something and don&#8217;t know exactly what they&#8217;re looking for, or when they
know what they&#8217;re looking for but don&#8217;t know where to find it.
But search on computers or on the web has traditionally been either
intuitive and useless or unintuitive and powerful, as I&#8217;m going to show
you.
Even searching on Google used to be <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2003/10/search.html">hard and
unintuitive</a>
for the layperson. But Google improved the UX and it was so
powerful that people just learned to use it.</p>

<p>Until now
search was basically equated to Google (a single-entry point to all of
the resources available on the web), but with the major
<a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/03/welcome-to-the-post-pc-era.html">shift</a> from computers to mobile devices,
search UX needs to be reinvented.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/6751892711/"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7143/6751892711_f59c0452e8.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/" title="Author">Yogesh Mhatre</a></em></p>

<h2>Fact: Mobile Search User Experience Sucks</h2>

<p>Searching on smartphones is currently a terrible user experience. Screens are
tiny, typos frequent, missclicks incredibly annoying. Search results
don&#8217;t account well for the fact that smartphones are not simply smaller versions of
computers. Recently for instance, an <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/bw/app/quickmaps/id506283203?mt=8">iphone app</a> that is a
simple user interface for frequent
Google Maps queries received a very positive feedback and was an instant
success.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s why most search on mobile is done on vertically differentiated
apps: one searches for places to stay on the Airbnb app, and looks for movies on the IMDB
app. These apps provide a better search experience, from the query to
the results &#8220;page&#8221;. The problem with that scheme is when you don&#8217;t know
the particular app that suits your needs. Unless you follow Techcrunch
or HackerNews religiously it can get tricky. The beauty of Google and
other search engines was that they provided a single entry point for web
content. You didn&#8217;t have to know anything else, and a lot of people
still google &#8220;facebook&#8221; to reach the facebook website.</p>

<p>But the UX of single entry point search is so bad on mobile that people
don&#8217;t bother using it. Instead they&#8217;re left with discovering content
through social media apps which offer a very decent UX for that. But they
cannot look for something from a single-entry point unless they muster
enough courage to deal with Google&#8217;s web app, and that&#8217;s too bad.</p>

<h2>Lets Go Back In Time</h2>

<p>When Windows arrived on the market, it represented a major shift in UX.
Before Windows, people interacted with computers using a command-line
interface(CLI), otherwise known as the shell. Command-line means that instead
of clicking around, navigating in your folders and moving files
visually, you gave a command to the computer and it executed your
command. The CLI was (and still is) a great UX for search of files in a
computer. Windows&#8217; graphical user interface, on the other hand, was absolutely terrible at this.</p>

<p>Can you remember when you still had Windows? Looking for a file was
absurdly hard and difficult, borderline impossible. That&#8217;s why most
people just used their brain to remember where they put their files on
their hard drive, and went looking for it by opening folder after
folder. So Windows was a huge regression in search UX from the days when there was no graphical
interface.</p>

<p>Windows was arguably more intuitive than the CLI, you didn&#8217;t have to
learn any commands to use it. All you had to do is click buttons and move your cursor
around. But as you gained intuitiveness, you lost the power of the CLI.</p>

<p>The reason why I&#8217;m talking about
all this is we are currently witnessing a similar change of paradigms
as websites are becoming webapps or even native mobile apps, that cannot
be cleanly separated into different pages anymore. And again search UX
is getting the bitter end of the deal.</p>

<p>Apps are more intuitive, there are no more files, no more links, it&#8217;s
pure visual and intuition heaven such that 2-year olds are comfortable with iPads,
but powerful search is not part of the experience.</p>

<h2>Enters Siri</h2>

<p>Siri is the new personal assistant that lives in all iPhones 4S. You
talk to her and she executes your wishes to the best of her abilities.</p>

<p>A lot of people say it&#8217;s a gadget, it&#8217;s not actionable,
it&#8217;s an Apple marketing ploy to sell you an iPhone 4 at a 20% premium. I
think however that it&#8217;s much more than that and that these critics are
missing the elephant in the room. For me, Siri is the new
command-line interface.</p>

<p>Think about what Siri does. You ask her to set your
alarm, to give you the weather, to find a restaurant, to look for places, all from a single entry point.
Basically, it&#8217;s a <strong>vocal recognition enabled command interface</strong>.
And even though it&#8217;s still rough on the
edges, I&#8217;m positive it&#8217;s going to become much more powerful in the near
future. Vocal commands are the ultimate user experience, everybody gets
it. The sole interface that beat vocal commands would be a mind-reading
interface.
So for the first time we have a <strong>search UX that is both intuitive
and powerful</strong> (or promising to be at least). Siri is abstracting links
and complicated queries from the end-user. Most people don&#8217;t care about
links, they just want the data, the resource that the links point to.</p>

<p>Siri is going to bring search back to mobile devices, and make search a
huge part of the mobile ecosystem once it opens its API to developers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SOPA, the entertainment industry and the future of culture]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T08:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The entertainment industry is busy trying to make the US adopt the SOPA
law which is considered dangerous for the Internet by <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2012/jan/18/sopa-wikipedia-blackout-google-reddit" title="many">many</a>. This brings two questions:</p>

<ul>
<li>What can the future model for accessing culture look like? Will today&#8217;s
giants be part of it?</li>
<li>How can we ensure that laws are made by people with sufficient
knowledge of the field they try to regulate?</li>
</ul>


<p>I give my consumer and tech enthusiast point of view on the first question in this post and I will tackle the second one in a few days.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/27539822@N05/3697785107/"><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2608/3697785107_579dac8a0f_n.jpg" alt="Concert" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.christianholmer.com/" title="Author">Christian Holmer</a></em></p>

<h2>How the Internet disrupted the entertainment industry&#8217;s business model</h2>

<p>The major movie and music producers (Hollywood, Sony, Universal to name a few) engage in the <a href="http://musicfacts2.wordpress.com/2010/06/25/15-analysis-of-the-cost-structure/">following activities</a>: content production (recording in the case of music), royalties payments to artists and copyrights holders,  marketing and promotion, purchase, manufacturing, warehousing and distribution. The first four can be referred to as &#8220;creating the content and making it known&#8221;, and the Internet didn&#8217;t have much impact on them.</p>

<p>On the contrary, the last four (&#8220;bringing the content to consumers&#8221;), have been completely disrupted by the arrival of the Internet, which brings these costs close to zero. In my opinion, the major labels have failed to accept this fact, which is why they took such a long time to open downloading services. And even then, the online prices have not gone down by as much as they could. They may have every right to tell consumers that they always have the option not to get music/videos, but I think that&#8217;s not a <a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/02/25/right-vs-pragmatic" title="pragmatic">pragmatic approach</a>. I want to listen to music and watch movies, but I don&#8217;t like to pay for CDs that are DRM-locked, or for a zone 1 DVD that only works in 2 countries and begins with an <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OWPfcEOr2Yg" title="Bender piracy warning">&#8220;illegal downloading is ripping out a beating human heart&#8221; ad</a>. In fact, I don&#8217;t even want to have to drive to the nearest Virgin Megastore to get the latest season of Game of Thrones. <em>What I want is to be able to get access to music and videos freely from my home</em>.</p>

<h2>People still want to pay for what they love</h2>

<p>Does that mean that labels and artists are doomed to be left destitute as we all get their work for free? I really don&#8217;t think so. People (myself included) <em>want</em> to pay for what they love. For example, you can look at <a href="http://flattr.com/" title="Flattr">Flattr</a>. Or you can consider the fact that <a href="http://www.wired.com/listening_post/2007/10/estimates-radio/" title="Radiohead">Radiohead made between $6M and $10M from a
&#8220;pay-what-you-want&#8221; downloadable album</a>.</p>

<p>But what I love is music, movies, tv series. In a word, <em>culture</em>. Now that I&#8217;ve seen how easy it is to access it on the Internet, I want the paying offer to be at least as good as the free one: a large choice, fast downloads and unlimited access from anywhere. I am sick of DVDs rendered unreadable due to copy-protection (happened again last week), and music I can&#8217;t copy however I wish.</p>

<h2>How labels and artists can get paid</h2>

<p>In my opinion, a <em>global subscription model</em>, much like Spotify&#8217;s, would be a very nice solution. I estimate the number of Internet subscriptions in North America to be 80M (it was <a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/am/us.htm">70M in the US alone in 2009</a>). The <a href="http://grabstats.com/statmain.asp?StatID=74">music industry made a total of $26.5B in the same region in 2011</a>, which corresponds to about $28 per subscribtion and per month. I share one subscription with my girlfriend whom I live with, so that means I would have to pay $14 per month for unlimited and legal music. I would do that gladly!</p>

<p>The exchanges could be
monitored so that the most downloaded artists receive more money than
the others. This redistribution system could also be tweaked in favor of smaller, unknown artists to support discovery.</p>

<p>The above only concerns personal content consumption. <em>There
are alternative revenue streams for artists and labels that cannot be copied nor downloaded</em>: concerts, movie theatres, goodies and so on. For example, <a href="http://grabstats.com/statmain.asp?StatID=73">the total 2011 revenue for live music in North America is $10.3B</a>. It seems to be enough to sustain music creation, doesn&#8217;t it?</p>

<p><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/">In a nutshell</a>, I think that major labels still have a role to play, but should focus on content creation and marketing, where their true value addition resides. I fear that if they continue to try to keep the old business model in place, they will be replaced by more suited players.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell&#8230;</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader&#8217;s curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It&#8217;s like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] BizDev vs SEO - Google+ value]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T16:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and then to encourage you to go read the complete post
should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h2><a href="http://also.roybahat.com/post/19307918051/bd-is-the-new-seo" title="Source">BizDev is the new SEO</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/roybahat">@roybahat</a> - Mar 16, 2012</em></p>

<p>Roy Bahat writes a follow up to Roger and Mike&#8217;s
<a href="http://rogerandmike.com/post/18870279638/what-is-the-hypernet" title="Hypernet">article on the Hypernet</a>.
He explains why business development may replace SEO in the next
Internet era.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Changes</strong>

<ul>
<li>the iPhone changed the internet, by taking us away from the SEO-driven world of URLs and websites</li>
<li>Search wont come first. New services succeed without ever really needing to master search (Pinterest, Angry Birds etc.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New perspectives</strong>

<ul>
<li>Some think social media optimization will replace search engine optimization but that&#8217;s not all</li>
<li>In the next era, you can get discovered merely by having a strong relationship with one of the platforms of discovery</li>
<li>Business development may take the place of SEO.  This could be great for companies with well-known brands based on a quality service</li>
<li>Thats awful for new services with great content but no way to get an <em>in</em>  but its great for wonderful brands who might otherwise have struggled with the strange world of search algorithms</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases" title="Source">What you could do if you were google and had their databases</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a> - Mar 15, 2012</em></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij thinks about the value of Google+ for Google and why
they are pushing it so hard. This article outlines a hypothetical way in which Google+ could be of major strategic value for Google in its core business, search.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The value of links is decreasing</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>People that relied on links will now rely on Google reducing the value of links between sites</li>
<li>People that realize that Google values links will create lots of them still further reducing the value of links between sites</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Why Google is promoting Google+</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>analytics + social network tells you what social circles are reading which articles</li>
<li>Someone that is professionally engaged in a certain field carefully studying an article in that same field is likely a good indicator that such an article is at least worthy of some notice</li>
<li>There is no algorithm as good at discriminating bad content from good content as the human mind</li>
<li>Every user in Google+ is actually now an unpaid Google employee whose actions are used to influence the google search results as a way to stop further erosion of the results due to spam</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn&#8217;t consolidated in
some fashion. That&#8217;s why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author&#8217;s reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You&#8217;re asking that person for too much work. She doesn&#8217;t have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it&#8217;s high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you&#8217;ll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it&#8217;s spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Will Your Last Holidays Photos Become?]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my wife&#8217;s grand father funeral. Those moments are intense
family time where everybody gathers together and tells all the anecdotes they
have. The best place to dig into the past is the attic. That&#8217;s where my
wife found family photographic slides.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/917626896/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1203/917626896_dc53081d31_m.jpg" alt="Rosetta Stone" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/" title="Author">Nathan Wong</a></em></p>

<p>Those slides were from 35 to 50 years old. My wife and I were skeptical
about the state of the slides, could we get something out of them?
Definitely. They were in perfect state and I&#8217;m sure they will still be 50
years from now.  In the living room, we set up the slide projector which was still in great shape
as well. We spent hours and hours viewing 15 years of photos,
laughing at everybody that looked so young, trying to identify people we
had forgotten, remembering good moments spent together. Despite the
circumstances everyone had a great time and forgot one&#8217;s sadness for a
while.</p>

<p>This episode made me think that today people store their thousands of
photos they take a year on DVDs, hard drives and the cloud. Do you know anyone who has developed their last
holidays photos? I know I haven&#8217;t. Those new technologies
make for false advertising. They don&#8217;t last more than 10 to 15 years maximum under
optimal conditions. And at the current pace we won&#8217;t find an optical
disk reader in 15 years.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s why I was wondering if our grandchildren will live such
moments. They won&#8217;t find any usable DVDs nor our Dropbox password in
the attic. What will be the physical media storage support of our generation
that will allow our grandchildren to dive into our memories?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Article on Improving the Discoverability of Good Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/17/great-article-on-improving-the-discoverability-of-good-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T18:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/17/great-article-on-improving-the-discoverability-of-good-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases">What could you do if you were Google and had their databases?</a>
by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij explains his point of view on how Google+ is making its
user base work collaboratively towards better Google search results, for
free!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why so Many French are Not Entrepreneurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>France&#8217;s higher education trains world-class engineers, but is home to very few successful start-ups. Having studied engineering in France and then at Stanford University, I will try to explain this apparent paradox.</em></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/2417001179/"><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2168/2417001179_d5ce2d9362_m.jpg" alt="Test taking" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/" title="Author">billaday</a></em></p>

<h2>Party hard, study a bit, get straight As</h2>

<p>When I took my first classes at Stanford University, I was very
surprised by the difficulty level of engineering classes. My French friends and I found the material to be straightforward, the assignments and exams were easy and the grading more than forgiving. We would party a lot, study a bit, and still get close to 4.0 GPAs. Simply put, we thought we were on top of the world. Of course, we were wrong.</p>

<h2>The hard reality</h2>

<p>But then we took an entrepreneurship class (&#8220;hey, how hard can that
be ?&#8221;), and the professor asked us who had already created a company.
&#8220;What a joke, who creates a company at 22 ?&#8221; was the question that
crossed my mind. But three quarters of the class raised their hand,
and we realized that we were indeed not at the top of the world.</p>

<h2>Hone your test-taking skills</h2>

<p>If you are not French, you probably don&#8217;t know anything about its arcane
higher education, and you can read <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=1292">this PhD comic</a>
for a very good introduction. To sum it up, there is only one way to be part of the academic elite after high school,
and it is to enter the <em>&#8220;prepa&#8221;</em>, a two years long very intensive cursus at the end of which you take a competitive exam and get into the best school
(<em>&#8220;grande ecole&#8221;</em>) your rank enables you to. Once you get into one of these, you are assured you will easily land
one of the best/most well-paid jobs available.</p>

<p>There are good points to this system. It teaches us rigor, hard
work, how to handle pressure and a lot about theoretical science. But what we learn
best is how to do well at tests. And since it is so hard,
people from this system are still very proud of their
achievement 20 years later.</p>

<h2>&#8220;I can do it!&#8221;</h2>

<p>Basically in France, a lot of people believe that we can measure an
individual&#8217;s skills by how well he fared in a test 20 years ago. We tend
to favorably view people with a perfect pedigree: the best school, and
then a job at an elite consulting or investment-banking firm. Trying to create a start-up but failing is
not well preceived at all.</p>

<p>Americans are very different. They believe that you should use the most
recent achievements to judge a person&#8217;s skills, and that if you try, you
can do it. Where many a Frenchman would not even try for fear of failing,
Americans believe that success is inevitably down the road. And so
they try. And so they end up winning.</p>

<h2>The best of both worlds</h2>

<p>I don&#8217;t think the French system is inherently bad. It produces very good engineers with a strong Math background that is useful to become a good coder. But it is time we stopped having this &#8220;everything is a test&#8221;
mentality, and understand that <strong>failing is not necessarily a bad thing, if you seriously
tried</strong>. Thinking like this would radically change the French start-up
ecosystem: not only would we have more entrepreneurs, but also less
risk-adverse investors, and more ambitious ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Is Asynchronous Communication Superior?]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="last article">last article</a>
I detailed why synchronous communication is not
appropriate for work: it leads to interruptions, involves moving or
shouting, drifts and leaves no trace.<br/>
To solve this communication problem I believe in the asynchronous way of
doing it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/6370949347/"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6052/6370949347_a66d54d217_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/" title="Author">Modestas J</a></em></p>

<h2>Asynchronous?</h2>

<p>WTF is this? In an asynchronous communication
interlocutors can exchange and continue their discussion
whenever they want it. Examples of
asynchronous communication media are letter, text message, email,
chat. They all share a common something in common: they are <strong>written communication
media</strong>.</p>

<h2>Asynchronous Channels Are Superior</h2>

<p>The massive use of text messages illustrates the <strong>usefulness and the
advantages an asynchronous communication offers over an oral conversation.</strong>
It&#8217;s quick, efficient, you can respond hours later and  keep track of the history.
You should use different asynchronous communication media for different usecases. Your day-to-day conversation?
Do it by chat. A code review? Use Github and Pull Requests. Important annoucements? Write an email. Organize
your communication and insert it in your workflow. Segmenting your communication will help you manage it efficiently
and will diminish the pressure of a single overloaded inbox.</p>

<h2>Why Does Email Kill Your Productivity?</h2>

<p>At work, people seem to use email as the sole form of asynchronous communication. Emails are adapted for
internal communication like <strong>reports, formal announcements</strong>. If you write less-than-two-lines emails
you are doing it wrong. Do you really need an email to say <em>&#8220;Ok I&#8217;ll do it&#8221;</em> or <em>&#8220;Thanks&#8221;</em>?
For everyday use they are counter productive. You end up receiving tons
of emails a day, <strong>spending hours responding, deleting and archiving.</strong></p>

<h2>The Right Communication Medium: the Chat Room</h2>

<p>Setting up a chat room for your team is probably one of the most important
action you can do to improve its efficiency and productivity.
90% of its communication should occur there. With a chat room solution
<strong>conversations history is easily accessible, you can simultaneously participate to
multiple groups of discussions, sending a message is so much easier</strong>! Aren&#8217;t you bored of
clicking <em>New Message</em>, filling in recipients addresses? Even clicking on <em>Respond</em>
is painful.<br/>
Chat rooms are really the most adequate medium to communicate for your team.
<a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="Previous post">Even</a>
if you work at the same place.</p>

<p><strong>Don&#8217;t waste more time and set up your private chat room.</strong>
<a href="http://www.hipchat.com" title="HipChat">HipChat</a> is a great tool for that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Shouldn't Use Synchronous Communication At Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a recent <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/" title="Article">post</a>,
James Slavet (Greylock Partners) describes metrics we should consider to
be more productive. The top one is called Flow State Percentage and
measures the relative time we are deeply concentrated on what we are doing. Flow state has
an amazing impact on development cycles times. A big threat to flow state lies in synchronous communication.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/1226209342/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1209/1226209342_ad08767199_m.jpg" alt="Muzzle" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/" title="Author">This Year Love</a></em></p>

<h2>Synchronous communication?</h2>

<p>Synchronous forms of communication include face
to face conversation or phone discussion.
Synchronous because people talking do it at the
same exact moment: ever tried answering your colleagues
2 minutes or 1 hour after they asked you a question? That&#8217;s impossible
as oral conversations don&#8217;t work with delay.
Asynchronous communication solves that problem
by relies on a written exchange.</p>

<h2>What for?</h2>

<p>Oral conversations are <strong>only appropriate when a written exchange could take
much longer than it should</strong>: conflict resolution, detailed
explanation of a topic, etc. For other situations
synchronous communication is counter-productive.</p>

<h2>The pitfalls of synchronous communication at work</h2>

<p>For your everyday work conversations you should think twice
before having an oral discussion. Why? Here are <strong>4 reasons</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Oral discussion = interruption</strong> When somebody
asks you something it drains all your attention. You have to switch your
focus to provide the adequate answer which means you lose all the
concentration you had in your work.
The ten-seconds question becomes a ten-minutes perturbation, taking into
account the time you need to refocus (if you even manage to refocus)
and recall what your were doing.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>It involves moving and/or shouting in the office</strong>. Depending on
your work office configuration talking with somebody means moving to his
desk or shouting through the open space. In the former case it
magnifies your work interruption. In the latter case you&#8217;ll manage
to effectively disturb everyone of your coworkers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fatally you drift</strong> Oral conversations drift more than
a bobsleigh on ice. Have you ever started a conversation about
the crucial decision you should take and ended up speaking of the last
hilarious meme you read?</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Exchanges are lost for the posterity</strong> Oral conversations are not actionable, for you
or your teammates. What if you need to recall all the points
stated? How do you keep track of the history of your conversation?
What if the following week you&#8217;ll have the same question?
Won&#8217;t you feel bad disturbing your colleagues again?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Before engaging in any kind of communication there is one thing
you should try: <strong>find an answer by yourself</strong>.
But sometimes it&#8217;s more efficient
to ask for somebody&#8217;s help instead of googling to find the appropriate
answer. In that case <strong>go for asynchronous communication.</strong></p>

<p>In a later post I&#8217;ll cover asynchronous communication
especially the pitfalls of emails and the benefits of having a chat room
for your team.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makers Don't Work With Deadlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A maker is someone who likes to make stuff, to build things. It can be
an artist, a craftsman, an architect, a designer. But it can also be a
software developer. I&#8217;m talking about good developers. Those that take
pride in their work.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aidanmorgan/2331754875/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3140/2331754875_e6a2a81429_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/24742305@N00/" title="Author">John-Morgan</a></em></p>

<h2>How we work</h2>

<p>Often times, people ask me how we work, how we manage things, and more
generally how software should be managed. And my response always
suprises them: no deadlines, <a href="http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch07_Meetings_Are_Toxic.php">no meetings</a>, we just make stuff as we go.</p>

<h2>Why French project managers mostly do it wrong</h2>

<p>In France most people think
software is a commodity, meaning they try to find the cheapest person
out there that will do the job. If your site is selling socks, that&#8217;s
probaly a decent bet because their isn&#8217;t a lot of technology involved
and your core business is selling socks, not your website.</p>

<p>So the problem with that thinking is that the premise is utterly wrong.
Good software is not a commodity, it comes at a price and not
everyone can do it. Even people who sell <a href="http://dollarshaveclub.com">shaving kits</a> have figured that
out.</p>

<h2>Let your artists work for you</h2>

<p>My point is good developers are not mere factory workers. They are elite
craftsmen or even artists, and they should be managed as such. Craftsmen
and artists can&#8217;t measure their work by the hour, they can&#8217;t follow a
well-defined schedule, you can&#8217;t tell them what are the priorities. They
will figure it out by themselves! Just let them work. If a bug needs to
be fixed, they will fix it because they care about the quality of their
code.</p>

<h2>Productivity cannot be commanded</h2>

<p>Developers, like artists, need to get &#8221;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_%28psycholog%29">in the zone</a>)&#8221; in order to be
productive. You can&#8217;t make them get in the zone, you let them do it. So
stop handing them a todolist lovingly prioritised with strict deadlines,
it is useless. They are makers, they will work becauses they like what
they do and they love building things. There is no need to tell them to
do it. And if they want to work from 3pm to 3am because that&#8217;s when they
are the most productive, let them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
