<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-06T10:23:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Computers in Text Summarization]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Stanislas explained in <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/" title="Information Overload">this previous post</a>, we believe we are dealing with too much information to keep up on the Internet. The natural solution is text summarization, and computers can help us there.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/3558255554/sizes/l/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3376/3558255554_9f9c480132_n.jpg" alt="Summary" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/" title="Author">Xeeiliz</a></em></p>

<p>There are roughly two kinds of summaries: the ones that consist of a few of
the most important sentences extracted from the text, the keyphrases, and the ones that
are written from scratch without necessarily using the same phrasing, called abstract summaries.</p>

<h2>Finding the most relevant content: keyphrase extraction</h2>

<p>The big advantage of keyphrase-based summaries is that there is no risk
of miscomprehension since they are composed of unrephrased pieces of the
text. Moreover, computers are able to compute them and get decent
results. There are two main ways to do it: supervised and unsupervised
extraction.</p>

<h3>When you know the context: extraction as supervised learning</h3>

<p>One way to perform this task is described by Peter Turney in <a href="http://webdocs.cs.ualberta.ca/~lindek/650/papers/turney.pdf">this paper</a>. He found that using a custom-designed algorithm that incorporates specialized domain knowledge on a text generates yields very good results: 80% of keyphrases are deemed acceptable by human readers. The problem with this approach is that it requires the computer to know the topic beforehand. It is possible to use a prior first step to determine what it is, but this is difficult and the results are terrible if we get it wrong.</p>

<h3>Applicable to any text: unsupervised keyphrase extraction</h3>

<p>This approaches enables us to extract keyphrases from a text without any
prior knowledge, which is a tremendous improvement upon the previous method. There a several algorithms, and one notable current example is <a href="http://www.summly.com/">Summly</a>. I will explain one of those, named TextRank, to give you a feeling of the kind of techniques used in this field.</p>

<p>The TextRank algorithm was developped by Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau in
<a href="http://acl.ldc.upenn.edu/acl2004/emnlp/pdf/Mihalcea.pdf">this paper</a>. The key idea is that a text
unit (word or phrase depending on the need) that is close to a lot of other important text units is likely a keyphrase. Using the parallel between the &#8220;close to&#8221; relation and the &#8220;referred to by&#8221; relation of hyperlinks, TextRank uses Google&#8217;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">PageRank</a> to determine which text units are the most important. It works well, its main author was even awarded a $100k grant by Google for her work on keyphrase extraction.</p>

<h2>The best: abstract summarization</h2>

<p>Even though they can be very useful, keyphrase-based summaries are still
rudimentary compared to abstract summaries, because they are much nicer
to read, and we are sure no important information was &#8220;left behind&#8221; (i.e a keyphrase was not extracted). Also, keyphrase extraction algorithms still find it hard to
summarize technical articles.</p>

<p>Abstract summarization is the limit of what computers can do today. The
main reason for this is that they struggle with the following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Coreferences understanding</strong>. For example, who does &#8216;he&#8217;
references in the sentence &#8216;Paul told John he should play squash&#8217;?</li>
<li><strong>Word sense disambiguation</strong>. In &#8216;I need batteries for
my mouse&#8217;, are we talking about the animal or the device?</li>
<li><strong>Sentiment analysis</strong>. Understanding the mood of the writer is often
key to understanding a text, all the more when there is sarcasm.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Computers can help humans summarize a text</h2>

<p>To sum it up, I believe that humans still cannot be replaced by
algorithms if we want to produce quality summaries. Nonetheless, a
computer really can help a us by providing a keyphrase-based summary,
so that we spend less time scanning the text for them. In addition, if
we were able to train algorithms by comparing their output with a human
summary a lot of times for articles on a certain topic, I think it is possible we see significant improvements.</p>

<p><em>Note: some examples were taken from <a href="https://class.coursera.org/nlp/">Stanford&#8217;s Natural Language
Processing online class</a>. If you couldn&#8217;t take
it this quarter, look for it, it is a terrific place to learn about this
topic</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Didn't Learn In College]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T23:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Albert Wenger is right:
<a href="http://continuations.com/post/20112755144/students-are-woefully-prepared-for-internet-age-job">we are woefully prepared for internet age job market</a>.
The three of us graduated in Computer Science in college, following a solid
engineering cursus. But during the
numerous courses we took we never heard of <a href="http://github.com/">Github</a> nor <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">StackOverflow</a>.
People attending creative and artistic
formation don&#8217;t hear of <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a> neither.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7044/7046351459_53d8ed3283.jpg" alt="Jeff Atwood" /></p>

<p>You could argue: &#8220;What&#8217;s the problem with that? You aren&#8217;t supposed to learn
how to use these platforms in school but core skills in your field!&#8221;</p>

<p>But that would be missing a point. The education we all receive has one final
goal: be prepared to get the best job as possible. In our current
era <strong>finding a job doesn&#8217;t come down to respond to job offers by sending
cover letters and resume</strong> nor spam by email all our contacts in the industry
to get an interview.</p>

<p>We are lucky to live through the emergence and the
expansion of specialized platforms which can help us build our personal
and professional identity. With these platforms <strong>we can easily have a
professional visibility, expose our skills so they can be assessed by
everyone and acquire real experience with real work.</strong></p>

<p>The very first recommendation we should receive beginning a course in
a topic is registering on all the platforms related to this topic. The
professors should foster us to leverage these platform to develop our
skills, build our expertise and gain some fame. Such platforms work this way: they play with
our ego to encourage us to contribute more and more and make our
achievements visible for everyone in return. <strong>They are built to be our showcase</strong> and
we should take advantage of it. We do so many interesting projects in
school, sometimes state of the art implementations in CS, that get lost
on our machine. They should be public to catch recruiters&#8217; attention on
our profile and skills or help us <a href="http://cdixon.org/2012/02/26/the-internet-is-reshaping-our-economy-from-one-of-huge-corporations-with-lots-of-jobs-to-huge-platforms-with-lots-of-income-streams/">create our future income streams</a>.</p>

<p>So at which level can we improve the promotion of such platforms? At the school&#8217;s level?
At the professors&#8217; level? They should all keep up with the internet economy like they
usually keep up with the <em>real</em> economy. Schools should increase professors&#8217; awareness, who
are mainly researchers in engineering schools for example, to this
concern but it&#8217;s up to the professors to promote personaly the right
platforms. Professors do already a great job teaching us their
knowledge, <strong>they should go further and encourage us to capitalize on their
teaching</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siri or the Reinvention of Mobile Search User Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T17:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Search is a behavior, it is what people do when they want to find
something and don&#8217;t know exactly what they&#8217;re looking for, or when they
know what they&#8217;re looking for but don&#8217;t know where to find it.
But search on computers or on the web has traditionally been either
intuitive and useless or unintuitive and powerful, as I&#8217;m going to show
you.
Even searching on Google used to be <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2003/10/search.html">hard and
unintuitive</a>
for the layperson. But Google improved the UX and it was so
powerful that people just learned to use it.</p>

<p>Until now
search was basically equated to Google (a single-entry point to all of
the resources available on the web), but with the major
<a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/03/welcome-to-the-post-pc-era.html">shift</a> from computers to mobile devices,
search UX needs to be reinvented.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/6751892711/"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7143/6751892711_f59c0452e8.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/" title="Author">Yogesh Mhatre</a></em></p>

<h2>Fact: Mobile Search User Experience Sucks</h2>

<p>Searching on smartphones is currently a terrible user experience. Screens are
tiny, typos frequent, missclicks incredibly annoying. Search results
don&#8217;t account well for the fact that smartphones are not simply smaller versions of
computers. Recently for instance, an <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/bw/app/quickmaps/id506283203?mt=8">iphone app</a> that is a
simple user interface for frequent
Google Maps queries received a very positive feedback and was an instant
success.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s why most search on mobile is done on vertically differentiated
apps: one searches for places to stay on the Airbnb app, and looks for movies on the IMDB
app. These apps provide a better search experience, from the query to
the results &#8220;page&#8221;. The problem with that scheme is when you don&#8217;t know
the particular app that suits your needs. Unless you follow Techcrunch
or HackerNews religiously it can get tricky. The beauty of Google and
other search engines was that they provided a single entry point for web
content. You didn&#8217;t have to know anything else, and a lot of people
still google &#8220;facebook&#8221; to reach the facebook website.</p>

<p>But the UX of single entry point search is so bad on mobile that people
don&#8217;t bother using it. Instead they&#8217;re left with discovering content
through social media apps which offer a very decent UX for that. But they
cannot look for something from a single-entry point unless they muster
enough courage to deal with Google&#8217;s web app, and that&#8217;s too bad.</p>

<h2>Lets Go Back In Time</h2>

<p>When Windows arrived on the market, it represented a major shift in UX.
Before Windows, people interacted with computers using a command-line
interface(CLI), otherwise known as the shell. Command-line means that instead
of clicking around, navigating in your folders and moving files
visually, you gave a command to the computer and it executed your
command. The CLI was (and still is) a great UX for search of files in a
computer. Windows&#8217; graphical user interface, on the other hand, was absolutely terrible at this.</p>

<p>Can you remember when you still had Windows? Looking for a file was
absurdly hard and difficult, borderline impossible. That&#8217;s why most
people just used their brain to remember where they put their files on
their hard drive, and went looking for it by opening folder after
folder. So Windows was a huge regression in search UX from the days when there was no graphical
interface.</p>

<p>Windows was arguably more intuitive than the CLI, you didn&#8217;t have to
learn any commands to use it. All you had to do is click buttons and move your cursor
around. But as you gained intuitiveness, you lost the power of the CLI.</p>

<p>The reason why I&#8217;m talking about
all this is we are currently witnessing a similar change of paradigms
as websites are becoming webapps or even native mobile apps, that cannot
be cleanly separated into different pages anymore. And again search UX
is getting the bitter end of the deal.</p>

<p>Apps are more intuitive, there are no more files, no more links, it&#8217;s
pure visual and intuition heaven such that 2-year olds are comfortable with iPads,
but powerful search is not part of the experience.</p>

<h2>Enters Siri</h2>

<p>Siri is the new personal assistant that lives in all iPhones 4S. You
talk to her and she executes your wishes to the best of her abilities.</p>

<p>A lot of people say it&#8217;s a gadget, it&#8217;s not actionable,
it&#8217;s an Apple marketing ploy to sell you an iPhone 4 at a 20% premium. I
think however that it&#8217;s much more than that and that these critics are
missing the elephant in the room. For me, Siri is the new
command-line interface.</p>

<p>Think about what Siri does. You ask her to set your
alarm, to give you the weather, to find a restaurant, to look for places, all from a single entry point.
Basically, it&#8217;s a <strong>vocal recognition enabled command interface</strong>.
And even though it&#8217;s still rough on the
edges, I&#8217;m positive it&#8217;s going to become much more powerful in the near
future. Vocal commands are the ultimate user experience, everybody gets
it. The sole interface that beat vocal commands would be a mind-reading
interface.
So for the first time we have a <strong>search UX that is both intuitive
and powerful</strong> (or promising to be at least). Siri is abstracting links
and complicated queries from the end-user. Most people don&#8217;t care about
links, they just want the data, the resource that the links point to.</p>

<p>Siri is going to bring search back to mobile devices, and make search a
huge part of the mobile ecosystem once it opens its API to developers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SOPA, the entertainment industry and the future of culture]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T08:24:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The entertainment industry is busy trying to make the US adopt the SOPA
law which is considered dangerous for the Internet by <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2012/jan/18/sopa-wikipedia-blackout-google-reddit" title="many">many</a>. This brings two questions:</p>

<ul>
<li>What can the future model for accessing culture look like? Will today&#8217;s
giants be part of it?</li>
<li>How can we ensure that laws are made by people with sufficient
knowledge of the field they try to regulate?</li>
</ul>


<p>I give my consumer and tech enthusiast point of view on the first question in this post and I will tackle the second one in a few days.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/27539822@N05/3697785107/"><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2608/3697785107_579dac8a0f_n.jpg" alt="Concert" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.christianholmer.com/" title="Author">Christian Holmer</a></em></p>

<h2>How the Internet disrupted the entertainment industry&#8217;s business model</h2>

<p>The major movie and music producers (Hollywood, Sony, Universal to name a few) engage in the <a href="http://musicfacts2.wordpress.com/2010/06/25/15-analysis-of-the-cost-structure/">following activities</a>: content production (recording in the case of music), royalties payments to artists and copyrights holders,  marketing and promotion, purchase, manufacturing, warehousing and distribution. The first four can be referred to as &#8220;creating the content and making it known&#8221;, and the Internet didn&#8217;t have much impact on them.</p>

<p>On the contrary, the last four (&#8220;bringing the content to consumers&#8221;), have been completely disrupted by the arrival of the Internet, which brings these costs close to zero. In my opinion, the major labels have failed to accept this fact, which is why they took such a long time to open downloading services. And even then, the online prices have not gone down by as much as they could. They may have every right to tell consumers that they always have the option not to get music/videos, but I think that&#8217;s not a <a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/02/25/right-vs-pragmatic" title="pragmatic">pragmatic approach</a>. I want to listen to music and watch movies, but I don&#8217;t like to pay for CDs that are DRM-locked, or for a zone 1 DVD that only works in 2 countries and begins with an <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OWPfcEOr2Yg" title="Bender piracy warning">&#8220;illegal downloading is ripping out a beating human heart&#8221; ad</a>. In fact, I don&#8217;t even want to have to drive to the nearest Virgin Megastore to get the latest season of Game of Thrones. <em>What I want is to be able to get access to music and videos freely from my home</em>.</p>

<h2>People still want to pay for what they love</h2>

<p>Does that mean that labels and artists are doomed to be left destitute as we all get their work for free? I really don&#8217;t think so. People (myself included) <em>want</em> to pay for what they love. For example, you can look at <a href="http://flattr.com/" title="Flattr">Flattr</a>. Or you can consider the fact that <a href="http://www.wired.com/listening_post/2007/10/estimates-radio/" title="Radiohead">Radiohead made between $6M and $10M from a
&#8220;pay-what-you-want&#8221; downloadable album</a>.</p>

<p>But what I love is music, movies, tv series. In a word, <em>culture</em>. Now that I&#8217;ve seen how easy it is to access it on the Internet, I want the paying offer to be at least as good as the free one: a large choice, fast downloads and unlimited access from anywhere. I am sick of DVDs rendered unreadable due to copy-protection (happened again last week), and music I can&#8217;t copy however I wish.</p>

<h2>How labels and artists can get paid</h2>

<p>In my opinion, a <em>global subscription model</em>, much like Spotify&#8217;s, would be a very nice solution. I estimate the number of Internet subscriptions in North America to be 80M (it was <a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/am/us.htm">70M in the US alone in 2009</a>). The <a href="http://grabstats.com/statmain.asp?StatID=74">music industry made a total of $26.5B in the same region in 2011</a>, which corresponds to about $28 per subscribtion and per month. I share one subscription with my girlfriend whom I live with, so that means I would have to pay $14 per month for unlimited and legal music. I would do that gladly!</p>

<p>The exchanges could be
monitored so that the most downloaded artists receive more money than
the others. This redistribution system could also be tweaked in favor of smaller, unknown artists to support discovery.</p>

<p>The above only concerns personal content consumption. <em>There
are alternative revenue streams for artists and labels that cannot be copied nor downloaded</em>: concerts, movie theatres, goodies and so on. For example, <a href="http://grabstats.com/statmain.asp?StatID=73">the total 2011 revenue for live music in North America is $10.3B</a>. It seems to be enough to sustain music creation, doesn&#8217;t it?</p>

<p><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/">In a nutshell</a>, I think that major labels still have a role to play, but should focus on content creation and marketing, where their true value addition resides. I fear that if they continue to try to keep the old business model in place, they will be replaced by more suited players.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell&#8230;</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader&#8217;s curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It&#8217;s like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] BizDev vs SEO - Google+ value]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T16:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and then to encourage you to go read the complete post
should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h2><a href="http://also.roybahat.com/post/19307918051/bd-is-the-new-seo" title="Source">BizDev is the new SEO</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/roybahat">@roybahat</a> - Mar 16, 2012</em></p>

<p>Roy Bahat writes a follow up to Roger and Mike&#8217;s
<a href="http://rogerandmike.com/post/18870279638/what-is-the-hypernet" title="Hypernet">article on the Hypernet</a>.
He explains why business development may replace SEO in the next
Internet era.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Changes</strong>

<ul>
<li>the iPhone changed the internet, by taking us away from the SEO-driven world of URLs and websites</li>
<li>Search won’t come first. New services succeed without ever really needing to master search (Pinterest, Angry Birds etc.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New perspectives</strong>

<ul>
<li>Some think social media optimization will replace search engine optimization but that&#8217;s not all</li>
<li>In the next era, you can get discovered merely by having a strong relationship with one of the platforms of discovery</li>
<li>Business development may take the place of SEO.  This could be great for companies with well-known brands based on a quality service</li>
<li>That’s awful for new services with great content but no way to get an <em>in</em> – but it’s great for wonderful brands who might otherwise have struggled with the strange world of search algorithms</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases" title="Source">What you could do if you were google and had their databases</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a> - Mar 15, 2012</em></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij thinks about the value of Google+ for Google and why
they are pushing it so hard. This article outlines a hypothetical way in which Google+ could be of major strategic value for Google in its core business, search.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The value of links is decreasing</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>People that relied on links will now rely on Google reducing the value of links between sites</li>
<li>People that realize that Google values links will create lots of them still further reducing the value of links between sites</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Why Google is promoting Google+</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>analytics + social network tells you what social circles are reading which articles</li>
<li>Someone that is professionally engaged in a certain field carefully studying an article in that same field is likely a good indicator that such an article is at least worthy of some notice</li>
<li>There is no algorithm as good at discriminating bad content from good content as the human mind</li>
<li>Every user in Google+ is actually now an unpaid Google employee whose actions are used to influence the google search results as a way to stop further erosion of the results due to spam</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn&#8217;t consolidated in
some fashion. That&#8217;s why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author&#8217;s reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You&#8217;re asking that person for too much work. She doesn&#8217;t have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it&#8217;s high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you&#8217;ll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it&#8217;s spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Will Your Last Holidays Photos Become?]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my wife&#8217;s grand father funeral. Those moments are intense
family time where everybody gathers together and tells all the anecdotes they
have. The best place to dig into the past is the attic. That&#8217;s where my
wife found family photographic slides.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/917626896/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1203/917626896_dc53081d31_m.jpg" alt="Rosetta Stone" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/" title="Author">Nathan Wong</a></em></p>

<p>Those slides were from 35 to 50 years old. My wife and I were skeptical
about the state of the slides, could we get something out of them?
Definitely. They were in perfect state and I&#8217;m sure they will still be 50
years from now.  In the living room, we set up the slide projector which was still in great shape
as well. We spent hours and hours viewing 15 years of photos,
laughing at everybody that looked so young, trying to identify people we
had forgotten, remembering good moments spent together. Despite the
circumstances everyone had a great time and forgot one&#8217;s sadness for a
while.</p>

<p>This episode made me think that today people store their thousands of
photos they take a year on DVDs, hard drives and the cloud. Do you know anyone who has developed their last
holidays photos? I know I haven&#8217;t. Those new technologies
make for false advertising. They don&#8217;t last more than 10 to 15 years maximum under
optimal conditions. And at the current pace we won&#8217;t find an optical
disk reader in 15 years.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s why I was wondering if our grandchildren will live such
moments. They won&#8217;t find any usable DVDs nor our Dropbox password in
the attic. What will be the physical media storage support of our generation
that will allow our grandchildren to dive into our memories?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Article on Improving the Discoverability of Good Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/great-article-on-improving-the-discoverability-of-good-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T18:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/great-article-on-improving-the-discoverability-of-good-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases">What could you do if you were Google and had their databases?</a>
by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij explains his point of view on how Google+ is making its
user base work collaboratively towards better Google search results, for
free!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why so Many French are Not Entrepreneurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>France&#8217;s higher education trains world-class engineers, but is home to very few successful start-ups. Having studied engineering in France and then at Stanford University, I will try to explain this apparent paradox.</em></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/2417001179/"><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2168/2417001179_d5ce2d9362_m.jpg" alt="Test taking" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/" title="Author">billaday</a></em></p>

<h2>Party hard, study a bit, get straight As</h2>

<p>When I took my first classes at Stanford University, I was very
surprised by the difficulty level of engineering classes. My French friends and I found the material to be straightforward, the assignments and exams were easy and the grading more than forgiving. We would party a lot, study a bit, and still get close to 4.0 GPAs. Simply put, we thought we were on top of the world. Of course, we were wrong.</p>

<h2>The hard reality</h2>

<p>But then we took an entrepreneurship class (&#8220;hey, how hard can that
be ?&#8221;), and the professor asked us who had already created a company.
&#8220;What a joke, who creates a company at 22 ?&#8221; was the question that
crossed my mind. But three quarters of the class raised their hand,
and we realized that we were indeed not at the top of the world.</p>

<h2>Hone your test-taking skills</h2>

<p>If you are not French, you probably don&#8217;t know anything about its arcane
higher education, and you can read <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=1292">this PhD comic</a>
for a very good introduction. To sum it up, there is only one way to be part of the academic elite after high school,
and it is to enter the <em>&#8220;prepa&#8221;</em>, a two years long very intensive cursus at the end of which you take a competitive exam and get into the best school
(<em>&#8220;grande ecole&#8221;</em>) your rank enables you to. Once you get into one of these, you are assured you will easily land
one of the best/most well-paid jobs available.</p>

<p>There are good points to this system. It teaches us rigor, hard
work, how to handle pressure and a lot about theoretical science. But what we learn
best is how to do well at tests. And since it is so hard,
people from this system are still very proud of their
achievement 20 years later.</p>

<h2>&#8220;I can do it!&#8221;</h2>

<p>Basically in France, a lot of people believe that we can measure an
individual&#8217;s skills by how well he fared in a test 20 years ago. We tend
to favorably view people with a perfect pedigree: the best school, and
then a job at an elite consulting or investment-banking firm. Trying to create a start-up but failing is
not well preceived at all.</p>

<p>Americans are very different. They believe that you should use the most
recent achievements to judge a person&#8217;s skills, and that if you try, you
can do it. Where many a Frenchman would not even try for fear of failing,
Americans believe that success is inevitably down the road. And so
they try. And so they end up winning.</p>

<h2>The best of both worlds</h2>

<p>I don&#8217;t think the French system is inherently bad. It produces very good engineers with a strong Math background that is useful to become a good coder. But it is time we stopped having this &#8220;everything is a test&#8221;
mentality, and understand that <strong>failing is not necessarily a bad thing, if you seriously
tried</strong>. Thinking like this would radically change the French start-up
ecosystem: not only would we have more entrepreneurs, but also less
risk-adverse investors, and more ambitious ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Is Asynchronous Communication Superior?]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="last article">last article</a>
I detailed why synchronous communication is not
appropriate for work: it leads to interruptions, involves moving or
shouting, drifts and leaves no trace.<br/>
To solve this communication problem I believe in the asynchronous way of
doing it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/6370949347/"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6052/6370949347_a66d54d217_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/" title="Author">Modestas J</a></em></p>

<h2>Asynchronous?</h2>

<p>WTF is this? In an asynchronous communication
interlocutors can exchange and continue their discussion
whenever they want it. Examples of
asynchronous communication media are letter, text message, email,
chat. They all share a common something in common: they are <strong>written communication
media</strong>.</p>

<h2>Asynchronous Channels Are Superior</h2>

<p>The massive use of text messages illustrates the <strong>usefulness and the
advantages an asynchronous communication offers over an oral conversation.</strong>
It&#8217;s quick, efficient, you can respond hours later and  keep track of the history.
You should use different asynchronous communication media for different usecases. Your day-to-day conversation?
Do it by chat. A code review? Use Github and Pull Requests. Important annoucements? Write an email. Organize
your communication and insert it in your workflow. Segmenting your communication will help you manage it efficiently
and will diminish the pressure of a single overloaded inbox.</p>

<h2>Why Does Email Kill Your Productivity?</h2>

<p>At work, people seem to use email as the sole form of asynchronous communication. Emails are adapted for
internal communication like <strong>reports, formal announcements</strong>. If you write less-than-two-lines emails
you are doing it wrong. Do you really need an email to say <em>&#8220;Ok I&#8217;ll do it&#8221;</em> or <em>&#8220;Thanks&#8221;</em>?
For everyday use they are counter productive. You end up receiving tons
of emails a day, <strong>spending hours responding, deleting and archiving.</strong></p>

<h2>The Right Communication Medium: the Chat Room</h2>

<p>Setting up a chat room for your team is probably one of the most important
action you can do to improve its efficiency and productivity.
90% of its communication should occur there. With a chat room solution
<strong>conversations history is easily accessible, you can simultaneously participate to
multiple groups of discussions, sending a message is so much easier</strong>! Aren&#8217;t you bored of
clicking <em>New Message</em>, filling in recipients addresses? Even clicking on <em>Respond</em>
is painful.<br/>
Chat rooms are really the most adequate medium to communicate for your team.
<a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="Previous post">Even</a>
if you work at the same place.</p>

<p><strong>Don&#8217;t waste more time and set up your private chat room.</strong>
<a href="http://www.hipchat.com" title="HipChat">HipChat</a> is a great tool for that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Shouldn't Use Synchronous Communication At Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communication-at-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a recent <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/" title="Article">post</a>,
James Slavet (Greylock Partners) describes metrics we should consider to
be more productive. The top one is called Flow State Percentage and
measures the relative time we are deeply concentrated on what we are doing. Flow state has
an amazing impact on development cycles times. A big threat to flow state lies in synchronous communication.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/1226209342/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1209/1226209342_ad08767199_m.jpg" alt="Muzzle" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hand-nor-glove/" title="Author">This Year Love</a></em></p>

<h2>Synchronous communication?</h2>

<p>Synchronous forms of communication include face
to face conversation or phone discussion.
Synchronous because people talking do it at the
same exact moment: ever tried answering your colleagues
2 minutes or 1 hour after they asked you a question? That&#8217;s impossible
as oral conversations don&#8217;t work with delay.
Asynchronous communication solves that problem
by relies on a written exchange.</p>

<h2>What for?</h2>

<p>Oral conversations are <strong>only appropriate when a written exchange could take
much longer than it should</strong>: conflict resolution, detailed
explanation of a topic, etc. For other situations
synchronous communication is counter-productive.</p>

<h2>The pitfalls of synchronous communication at work</h2>

<p>For your everyday work conversations you should think twice
before having an oral discussion. Why? Here are <strong>4 reasons</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Oral discussion = interruption</strong> When somebody
asks you something it drains all your attention. You have to switch your
focus to provide the adequate answer which means you lose all the
concentration you had in your work.
The ten-seconds question becomes a ten-minutes perturbation, taking into
account the time you need to refocus (if you even manage to refocus)
and recall what your were doing.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>It involves moving and/or shouting in the office</strong>. Depending on
your work office configuration talking with somebody means moving to his
desk or shouting through the open space. In the former case it
magnifies your work interruption. In the latter case you&#8217;ll manage
to effectively disturb everyone of your coworkers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fatally you drift</strong> Oral conversations drift more than
a bobsleigh on ice. Have you ever started a conversation about
the crucial decision you should take and ended up speaking of the last
hilarious meme you read?</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Exchanges are lost for the posterity</strong> Oral conversations are not actionable, for you
or your teammates. What if you need to recall all the points
stated? How do you keep track of the history of your conversation?
What if the following week you&#8217;ll have the same question?
Won&#8217;t you feel bad disturbing your colleagues again?</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Before engaging in any kind of communication there is one thing
you should try: <strong>find an answer by yourself</strong>.
But sometimes it&#8217;s more efficient
to ask for somebody&#8217;s help instead of googling to find the appropriate
answer. In that case <strong>go for asynchronous communication.</strong></p>

<p>In a later post I&#8217;ll cover asynchronous communication
especially the pitfalls of emails and the benefits of having a chat room
for your team.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makers Don't Work With Deadlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A maker is someone who likes to make stuff, to build things. It can be
an artist, a craftsman, an architect, a designer. But it can also be a
software developer. I&#8217;m talking about good developers. Those that take
pride in their work.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aidanmorgan/2331754875/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3140/2331754875_e6a2a81429_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/24742305@N00/" title="Author">John-Morgan</a></em></p>

<h2>How we work</h2>

<p>Often times, people ask me how we work, how we manage things, and more
generally how software should be managed. And my response always
suprises them: no deadlines, <a href="http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch07_Meetings_Are_Toxic.php">no meetings</a>, we just make stuff as we go.</p>

<h2>Why French project managers mostly do it wrong</h2>

<p>In France most people think
software is a commodity, meaning they try to find the cheapest person
out there that will do the job. If your site is selling socks, that&#8217;s
probaly a decent bet because their isn&#8217;t a lot of technology involved
and your core business is selling socks, not your website.</p>

<p>So the problem with that thinking is that the premise is utterly wrong.
Good software is not a commodity, it comes at a price and not
everyone can do it. Even people who sell <a href="http://dollarshaveclub.com">shaving kits</a> have figured that
out.</p>

<h2>Let your artists work for you</h2>

<p>My point is good developers are not mere factory workers. They are elite
craftsmen or even artists, and they should be managed as such. Craftsmen
and artists can&#8217;t measure their work by the hour, they can&#8217;t follow a
well-defined schedule, you can&#8217;t tell them what are the priorities. They
will figure it out by themselves! Just let them work. If a bug needs to
be fixed, they will fix it because they care about the quality of their
code.</p>

<h2>Productivity cannot be commanded</h2>

<p>Developers, like artists, need to get &#8221;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_%28psycholog%29">in the zone</a>)&#8221; in order to be
productive. You can&#8217;t make them get in the zone, you let them do it. So
stop handing them a todolist lovingly prioritised with strict deadlines,
it is useless. They are makers, they will work becauses they like what
they do and they love building things. There is no need to tell them to
do it. And if they want to work from 3pm to 3am because that&#8217;s when they
are the most productive, let them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Keep Up With the Information Overload]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook notifications, Twitter feeds, RSS feeds, emails, news
aggregators and now so much
more. We are constantly hit by new information, throughout the day, and
the night. There are so many things we want to read or watch.
The fact that the Web is a strictly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">RESTful</a> application (or should I say
<a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2012-02-13-an-api-ontology">Hypermedia</a>) doesn&#8217;t help because one link usually leads to more links. I&#8217;m sure
you&#8217;ve already experienced having more than 20 tabs open in your browser
and thinking &#8221;<em>God, when am I going to read all of this?</em>&#8221; but instead
of starting reading you scan the links of the page in front of you and
just open more tabs. And this was only made worse by tools such as
<a href="http://instapaper.com" title="Instapaper">Instapaper</a> that make you feel good
about saving stuff for later, even if you know deep inside you&#8217;ll never
come back to it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/2925760927/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3244/2925760927_a9db10926e_m.jpg" alt="Information overload" /></a></p>

<h2>Current solutions</h2>

<p>It&#8217;s extremely hard to keep up with all that information, and you
basically have 3 options at the moment:</p>

<h4>Let loose</h4>

<p>Accept that you can&#8217;t follow it all and if something is really important
it will come back to you one way or another so that missing it the first
time is not a big deal.
I personnally don&#8217;t like this solution because it means giving up
control on what I read and learn, and it basically amounts to a random
filter with some bias towards the most important news that isn&#8217;t always
the most interesting.</p>

<h4>Algorithmic filters</h4>

<p>Use tools such as <a href="http://news.me" title="News.me">News.me</a> or <a href="http://focus.io" title="Focus.io">Focus.io</a> that
use machine learning techniques to serve you the stories you might be
interested in the most. However, again, not knowing how these algorithms
work exactly, I fear I am going to lose the serendipity of scanning
myself all the input and selecting the hidden little gem that would be
considered as noise by these algorithms. Again, I hate losing control. I
do think these are better solutions than just letting loose.</p>

<h4>Reducing the input</h4>

<p>This for me is the best alternative. Following sort of a <em>less is more</em> convention,
I am looking to reduce the number of sources rather than increasing it,
keeping only the outstanding ones. I am constantly reevaluating the
quality of the twitter accounts and bloggers I follow in order to remove
those that either tweet too much  or whose content quality has suffered.
I am very rarely looking for new people to follow, and when I try
someone new it is always an experiment, never set in stone. I&#8217;d actually
like it if an algorithm could do that for me, again, not knowing the
inner workings of the services that offer news recommendation is too
bad. I&#8217;m willing to bet none of them though is going to unfollow someone
on twitter for you, or experiment with a new follower, based on the
quality of the links provided in the tweets. Same for RSS feeds.</p>

<h2>We need a new tool to find good content</h2>

<p>Basically none of today&#8217;s tools are good at finding good news and
information. You can use a combination of tools (such as <a href="http://quora.com" title="Quora">Quora</a> and <a href="http://stackexchange.com" title="StackEchange">StackExchange</a> but it is more
difficult than one tool and is conducive to a lot of noise. Plus we are
missing a linking tool between content of the same nature and topics,
that would transcend time. There are services like <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a> that you
can browse by searching for tags, but it is not powerful enough in the
way it presents the information. There are still too many links and not
enough clues as to which are interesting and which are not.</p>

<p>But don&#8217;t worry, we&#8217;re working on it ;)</p>

<p>Photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/">Martino</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Habits, Realtime Analytics, Media Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/digest-habits-realtime-analytics-media-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/digest-habits-realtime-analytics-media-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://www.nirandfar.com/2012/02/habits-are-new-viral-why-startups-must.html" title="Source">Habits Are The New Viral: Why Startups Must Be Behavior Experts</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/nireyal">@nireyal</a> - Feb 26, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Nir Eyal describes the importance of habits besides virality for the
success of products in the Curated Web</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Habits are what matters. Web businesses success increasingly depends on the strength of their users&#8217; habitual behavior</li>
<li>Web 1.0 companies measured success by pageviews and CPM, whereas new (social) companies proved  to be valuable because they were habit-forming (hot triggers, variable rewards, regular check-in&#8230;)</li>
<li>At the dawn of the Curated Web, companies must build habit creation into their products and business models. Not only are users inundated by distractions, but acquiring users is also harder than ever before</li>
<li>Companies which successfully create user habits can build huge enterprises, even without viral growth (Evernote, Amazon)</li>
<li>The more the user engages with a Curated Web company, the more data the company has to tailor and improve the user&rsquo;s experience. This self-improving feedback loop has the potential to be more useful &ndash; and more addictive &mdash; than anything we&rsquo;ve seen before</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/26/facebook-insights-real-time/" title="Source">Facebook To Speed Up Biz Analytics Tool Insights To Report In Real-Time</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/joshconstine">@JoshConstine</a> - Feb 26, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Josh Constine reports the move of Facebook Analytics Tool Insights to
Real Time and describes all the possibilities it will enable</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Page performance data in (near) real-time rather than on average 48 hour delay could enable businesses to reach higher ROIs</li>
<li>Immediate &ldquo;people talking about this&rdquo; data could give marketers a sense of a post&rsquo;s virality, and indicate if they should modify the content or the apps they link to</li>
<li>&ldquo;Insights API give Page owners an opportunity to see how their Page actually lives and breathes&rdquo;.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s up to us as tool developers to turn that data into something awesome and present it in relevant actionable analytics.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/25/print-is-dead-long-live-print/" title="Source">Print is Dead! Long Live Print?</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jordankurzweil">@JordanKurzweil</a> - Feb 25, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Jordan Kurzweil describes the context of &ldquo;digital magazination&rdquo; of content. He states some recommendations to straighten up print business. At the heart of his reflexion is personalized and curated content</em></p>

<ul>
<li>PRINT IS DEAD. revenue, subscriptions and circulation are declining</li>
<li>What can Old Print do to survive? Stop rearranging the deck chairs on the Titanic, grow a pair, and change your business model:

<ul>
<li>Accept this evolution (aging and fragmentation of audience, concurrency from other digital media &#8230;) and embrace it</li>
<li>Start thinking like startups: use some of your profits to incubate new ideas (e.g. Washington post personalized headlines)</li>
<li>Rethink your organization : everyone should be a doer, contributing 100 percent of her/his work hours to making things</li>
<li>Stop thinking that technology serves content: they are now one and the same, each working with the other to delight and engage your users</li>
<li>Update web platforms</li>
<li>Use data to inform your editorial and product decisions</li>
<li>Break down the wall between editors, writers and readers</li>
<li>Consider your content as a currency, not the end-all be-all but a means to an end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Procrastinating, Start Scripting]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/05/stop-procrastinating-start-scripting/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-05T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/05/stop-procrastinating-start-scripting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When working on a project we always face repetitive tasks. But we shouldn&#8217;t have to spend as much time on those tasks as we usually do. We love
to think: &#8221;<em>I just have to do it once and I won&#8217;t have to do it again</em>&#8221; But we never have to do it only once, be it for the current project or
the next one.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1073/1352003098_1681416c2d_m.jpg" title="Keyboard" alt="Illustration" /></p>

<p><strong>Automate by scripting</strong><br/>
Task repetition can be solved in a painless way: scripting. When you don&#8217;t automate repetitive work you waste time. We should always see mechanical tasks as potential scripts. It&#8217;s only
because we tend to procrastinate and we don&#8217;t face this reality that we
postpone the moment we start scripting.</p>

<p><strong>Save your time</strong><br/>
I think scripting is a very important activity, above
all because it makes us save a lot of time. The inputs changed? No problem, just
rerun the script and you&#8217;re done.</p>

<p><strong>Ship a product</strong><br/>
I love scripting because a script is something concrete and useful. By writing our custom
script we <em>&#8220;scratch our own itch&#8221;</em>, we solve our own problem with our
own technical skills, which always provides an immense satisfaction. Coding a script is like shipping a
small product!</p>

<p>In addition, it helps us develop and extend our programming
skills. It improves our knowledge of the scripting language and it makes us
discover API wrappers.</p>

<p><strong>Do it right</strong><br/>
When working in a team, scripting is even more useful. It&#8217;s
more than likely that our teamates will have to do later whar we are doing now. On top of that, scripting for a team forces us
to write good quality code because our users are our teammates. They
won&#8217;t be as indulgent as we are regarding our work, we don&#8217;t want them
to think that we are poor coders, so we do it right.</p>

<p><strong>Improve creativity and productivity</strong><br/>
The next time you think &#8220;it would be so nice to automate this work&#8221;, spend some time to look for a scripting solution ! The more you script the better you will become at it. So take some time thinking about what you are doing, you will see
how it improves your creativity and your productivity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Time Dimension on the Web, Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://continuations.com/post/18605081084/bringing-time-back-to-the-web-or-the-struggle-for" title="Source">Bringing Time Back to the Web (Or: The Struggle for Depth)</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/albertwenger">Albert Wenger</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<ul>
<li>There is so much new content on the Web every day that one can barely
keep up with it</li>
<li>It is becoming ever harder to delve into the past, a problem
aggravated by Google&#8217;s recent tilt of their search algorithm towards
recency</li>
<li>We need to surface time explicitly. For example, imagine a version of
Techmeme where you can see the historical precedents of any post, or a
search engine that allows you to &#8220;scroll&#8221; into the past of any result</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/29/raspberry-pi_n_1310441.html" title="Source">Raspberry Pi Mini Computer Served Up For $35</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/courteney-palis">Courteney Palis, Huffington Post</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Palis describes the $35-a-piece Raspberry PI micro-computer and the
implications for the teaching of computer science</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The Raspberry Pi device</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>A complete computer for $35</li>
<li>Credit-card sized</li>
<li>&#8220;Last-decade&#8221; hardware (700 Mhz processor, 256 MB RAM) that&#8217;s still
enough to run Linux, code, browse the internet and even play games such
as Quake 3 !</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>What this means</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Programming can be learned by almost anyone</li>
<li>People in poor areas, children in poor schools get access to technology</li>
<li>Like the Kinect, the Raspberry Pi will enable hackers to build ever
more impressive prototypes. The possibilities are endless</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/raspberry-pi.html" title="Source">Fred Wilson on the Raspberry Pi</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fredwilson">@fredwilson</a> - March 1, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Fred Wilson explains why he thinks the Raspberry Pi is a game changer</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Hardware that&#8217;s currently expensive (phones and especially tablets)
is going to be cheaper and cheaper. We will see sub $100 tablets in 3 to
5 years</li>
<li>The Raspberry Pi&#8217;s goal is, according to the developper, to entice
children to learn to code. But all markets that can be end-to-end
digital, not just education, will be disrupted</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Lies from Losers, Web/Mobile Integration, Community Feedback]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-01T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://bhorowitz.com/2012/02/29/lies-that-losers-tell/" title="Source">Lies that Losers Tell</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/bhorowitz">@bhorowitz</a> - Feb 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Ben Horowitz describes the false explanations CEOs and employees find a
posteriori to justify their failure and why they do that. Stop burrying
your head in the sand.</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Familiar lies</strong>

<ul>
<li>“<em>She left, but we were going to fire her, or give her a bad performance review</em>” : Instead of justifying the departure of your employees giving false excuses, ask yourself why you couldn&#8217;t keep them.</li>
<li>“<em>We would have won, but the other guys gave the deal away</em>” : Validate this claim with the actual customer instead of believing the Sales Rep who doesn&#8217;t want to take the blame.</li>
<li>&#8220;<em>Just because we missed the intermediate milestones doesn’t mean we won’t hit our product schedule</em>&#8221; : When the facts don’t align with the good news, a clever manager will find the narrative to make everybody feel better&#8230; until the next meeting.</li>
<li>“<em>We have a very high churn rate, but as soon as we turn on email marketing to our user base, people will come back</em>” : The reason that people leave our service and don’t come back is that we have not been sending them enough spam ?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Why are the CEOs/employees lying ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Andy Grove explains that humans, particularly those who build things, only listen to leading indicators of good news and tend to justify bad news with false excuses.</li>
<li>Lying CEOs regularly take action on the positive indicator and look for alternative explanations on the negative indicator.</li>
<li>CEOs are not lying to investors, they are lying to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2012/01/28/web-second-mobile-first/" title="Source">Web Second, Mobile First</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=msuster">@msuster</a> - Jan 28, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Mark Suster reacts to Fred Wilson&#8217;s blog post <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2010/09/mobile-first-web-second.html" title="AVC blog post">Mobile First, Web Second</a> reminding startups not to forget the Web</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>For 1.5 year people forgot Web Second and just thought Mobile First</strong>

<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s important not give up on the power of the tethered web, of large screen real estate, of a keyboard.</li>
<li>What&#8217;s even more important is to have a strategy that matches
customers wants and not developers whims.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mobile has clearly critical attributes</strong>

<ul>
<li>They are personal, location aware, occupy a lot of people&#8217;s leisure
time.</li>
<li>They are one touch away from buying and represent the &#8221;<em>bottom
end of the sales funnel</em>&#8221;</li>
<li>The limited real estate forces less choice and offers more focus on
the content.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>But products have to be integrated</strong>

<ul>
<li>Many things cannot be done on a mobile</li>
<li>Mobile should serve a different experience, a different usecase of the service.</li>
<li>The web product can offer complementary services that make the
product even more attractive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leverage the web to :</strong>

<ul>
<li>Create a differentiated product vs your mobile-only competitors.</li>
<li>Enable content creation and curation to make mobile consumption a better experience.</li>
<li>Organize and make the most of the content created by the mobile</li>
<li>Build features that make using native-phones apps pointless.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tablets come third</strong>

<ul>
<li>Extension to mobile strategy (larger real estate make content
  discovery different, increase the features possible&#8230;)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/02/listen-to-your-community-but-dont-let-them-tell-you-what-to-do.html" title="Source">Listen to Your Community, But Don&#8217;t Let Them Tell You What to Do</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/codinghorror">@codinghorror</a> - Feb 3, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Jeff Atwoods talks about the need to organize your community feedback
to take the most out of it</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Having a meta place to discuss the product is important</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meta participation is the source of all meaningful leadership and governance in a community, so it is cultivated and monitored closely.</li>
<li>Meta is for people who care so deeply about their community that they&#8217;re willing to go one step further, to come together and spend even more of their time deciding how to maintain and govern it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to leverage this meta place ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Animate the place : listen, respond</li>
<li>Sort between feedback and feature requests</li>
<li>Know how to extract core information and underlying needs from feature requests</li>
<li>Know to sort between useless and awesome feedback, 10% of the feedback is useful and can be gems</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t hesitate to be honest explaining the choices the company did
about the features the product offers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Assets of a Consumer-Web Startup, Internal People Metrics]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://mporat.tumblr.com/post/16753414806/what-asset-are-you-building" title="Source">What assets are you building ?</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/mporat">@mporat</a> - Jan 30, 2012</em></p>

<p>If you are building a consumer internet startup, you need to think about the assets that you are building and how these fit with your scaling and fundraising strategies.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Number of users</strong>

<ul>
<li>Most difficult to execute and scale because the lifetime value of a user is typically very low</li>
<li>Needs low customer acquisition cost, high retention, high conversion, tremendous growth, a lot of financing runway until the sheer number of users can generate huge revenues via advertising or traffic generation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High lifetime value</strong>

<ul>
<li>No need for a lot of users, because you make a lot of money of them.</li>
<li>Rarely needs mass financing because they are cash cows</li>
<li>Can invest heavily in marketing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Massive data</strong>

<ul>
<li>Sometimes (twitter,instagram) the data inputted by the users is more important than the users</li>
<li>Free services to the user in order to leverage the data at scale</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A great platform</strong>

<ul>
<li>Monetization comes from 3rd parties (think facebook/zynga)</li>
<li>Main asset is user engagement with your platform</li>
<li>Need to build the platform as well as the first services on top of it</li>
<li>Needs a lot of financing</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/2/" title="Source">Five New Management Metrics You Need To Know</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jslavet">@jslavet</a> - Dec 13, 2011</em></p>

<p>Here is a list of 5 very important metrics that never appear in annual
reports. Most companies measure outputs but not inputs or throughput.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Flow State Percentage</strong>

<ul>
<li>Interruptions move us out of flow state which is the state that
enables the most productivity.</li>
<li>It takes seconds to get out of but can
take very long to get back in.</li>
<li>Measure how uninterrupted your
programmers are.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Anxiety-Boredom Continuum</strong>

<ul>
<li>People want to be challenged, but not to the point that they break
down.</li>
<li>On the other hand, people will leave if they are bored.</li>
<li>Check in often with your employees to make sure you are striking the
right balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Meeting Promoter Score</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meetings are very expensive and rarely productive</li>
<li>At the end of each meeting, ask each participant to rate it and
suggest improvements</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Compound weekly learning rate</strong>

<ul>
<li>The ability to learn is like compounding interest on an investment</li>
<li>Ask your team: how did you get 1% better this week?</li>
<li>Did you learn something valuable from our customers?</li>
<li>Did you make a change to the product that drove better results?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Positive Feedback ratio</strong>

<ul>
<li>Catch people doing good things and tell them</li>
<li>This way when you provide feedback on areas to improve, they will
really listen</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we&#8217;ll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
