<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: capitalize | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/capitalize/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-28T21:18:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capitalize on What You Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T14:27:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a lot, probably an average of 15 blogposts a day and a book every
two weeks. I find that I sometimes have a lot of trouble
remembering the things I just read. Well it's
usually not completely forgotten, the information is likely stored in my
unconscious brain and will trickle back to my consciousness when
somethings triggers it, such as a question or a situation that matches
the pattern my brain stored when I read said content. So that means I
just need a little prodding in order to remember. However there is I
think a more interesting question: how do you build upon what you read?
How do you effectively turn information into knowledge? The secret lies in
having an active attitude towards remembering things, and not just passively consume content.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/2641415853/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3061/2641415853_325ea48e8e_n.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/" title="Author">Shishberg</a></em></p>

<h2>Write it Down</h2>

<p>Writing things down has a number of wonderful consequences.</p>

<p>First of all
the information is "safer" in the sense that it is now written down in a
place from which it is easier to retrieve in its actual form than from
your unconscious brain. Not only that but it also ensures that the
information stays put and doesn't change. One cannot say the same holds
true for memories, as the brain changes them all the time. Memories are
very volatile and often the brain tampers with them to spin them more
positively or make them more relevant to the context. Writing down will prevent
information from being distorted by your unconscious brain.</p>

<p>Additionally, writing things down will actually strengthen your memories.
When you write full sentences that
are grammatically correct (or close to correct at least), you must
formalize relationships between facts, entities, people, and concepts.
The brain being better suited to memorize relationships and patterns,
it will be easier for you to memorize that way instead of simply highlighting a few
words or numbers here and there that aren't linked together by explicit relationships. (Think of a graph.)</p>

<p>Last but not least, text is universal. Information in writing is easily
accessible and shareable. This is important because for instance say you
store information in other formats such as audio or video, it
won't be as easily retrieved and accessed. This is why I love blogposts
but am not a fan of podcasts or videos that don't include a "textified"
version.</p>

<p>In that regard, I write summaries of what I read and find most
interesting and useful. It is important to summarize relationships and
not facts only, so that it matches the brain's memorizing process.</p>

<h2>Practice</h2>

<p>Musicians are known for their disciplined rehearsals. When I was 10
years old I started learning to play the piano. My parents would pay
this private tutor that came once a week and insisted I play 3 hours of
piano per day. At this time I was of course way to enthralled by my
Playstation to care, but I do regret it now. So I didn't practice like I
should have, and the promising career as a pianist that lied ahead of me
ground to a screeching halt. However some of my friends heroically put in the
effort and I can see now that practice makes perfect.</p>

<p>Where does that all fit with memorizing and building knowledge? The goal is to
apply the methods of musicians to the practice of building knowledge. In that
case, practicing means a few things:
* Write an interesting bit of knowledge down in different ways, targetting varied audiences (yourself, your family,
  friends, colleagues, etc.)
* Talk about it to people who have a varying level of understanding of
  that particular topic. They will ask you questions you didn't expect
  and force you to dig deeper and strengthen your knowledge.
* Weave blobs of knowledge together. By that I mean think about what one
  relationship in a given domain means if applied to another one. (For
  instance Math and Computer Science, or Sociology and Networks,
  Math and Art, etc.) Bridging domains will often make great insights and
  ideas pop in your head and further strengthen your understanding and
  memory of a bit of knowledge.</p>

<p>Capitalizing on what you read by writing it down and practicing will
slowly (but surely!) turn you in a walking encyclopedia. You will be able to remember
a lot more things than you are used to, and gradually gain a deeper
understanding of what you memorize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
