<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: collaboration | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/collaboration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-25T15:30:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Golden Age Of Community Organizing Platforms]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T08:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/">already wrote</a> about how
you can leverage some <a href="https://github.com/">social platforms</a> to build
your visibility on the internet, but they offer much more.
They provide appropriate tools that help people to be more productive
and better organized. They are much more functional than pure social networks
and even more valuable as the communities are active.</p>

<p><img src="http://cardview.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/nation-builder.jpg" height="220" alt="Keep the gist" /></p>

<h2>Platforms structure communities</h2>

<p>We can call such a platform a <em>community organizing platform</em> because
it allows a community to have a place to gather, discuss and share. It
provides the global structure the community needs to get organized.
Ten years ago the forums laid the foundation but today these platforms
achieve what's been initiated.</p>

<p>Using these platforms everyone creates and manages a business card that
is accessible by everyone else.
People can easily be identified, followed, consulted and appraised. You
don't have to go to as many conferences or events to meet new people
because it can be done very efficiently online.</p>

<h2>Community organizing platforms offer more than pure social networks</h2>

<p>Pure social networks like Twitter offer ways to
organize communities but don't provide the structure
and tools needed for effective collaboration. They are mainly focus on
sharing.</p>

<p>While community organizing platforms provide a social layer they
also offer services geared towards the community itself. This
combination is what's really valuable.
<a href="http://nationbuilder.com/">Nation Builder</a>
is the perfect example: it features volunteer organization, donation
monitoring, website creation... a comprehensive package
political leaders need to interact with their audience.</p>

<h2>Active communities are driven by knowledge</h2>

<p>We can distinguish communities built upon friendship, professional
activity or common interests. The most active
are the ones based on a common interest, where knowledge and
feedback is a valuable resource. In these ones people spend a lot of time
looking for information. They also create a lot of content in order to
improve their reputation. Such platforms are even more
important for small communities because the resources they want to access are not always well
indexed by search engines.</p>

<p>As sharing information, working collaboratively and giving feedbacks to peers is key in
these communities even a very little one
can be very active.
There is still lots of
them to structure out there, lots of people waiting to
share and collaborate with their peers. Who are they? What can we do for
them?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
