<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rasperrypi | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/rasperrypi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-18T10:51:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Time Dimension on the Web, Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://continuations.com/post/18605081084/bringing-time-back-to-the-web-or-the-struggle-for" title="Source">Bringing Time Back to the Web (Or: The Struggle for Depth)</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/albertwenger">Albert Wenger</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<ul>
<li>There is so much new content on the Web every day that one can barely
keep up with it</li>
<li>It is becoming ever harder to delve into the past, a problem
aggravated by Google's recent tilt of their search algorithm towards
recency</li>
<li>We need to surface time explicitly. For example, imagine a version of
Techmeme where you can see the historical precedents of any post, or a
search engine that allows you to "scroll" into the past of any result</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/29/raspberry-pi_n_1310441.html" title="Source">Raspberry Pi Mini Computer Served Up For $35</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/courteney-palis">Courteney Palis, Huffington Post</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Palis describes the $35-a-piece Raspberry PI micro-computer and the
implications for the teaching of computer science</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The Raspberry Pi device</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>A complete computer for $35</li>
<li>Credit-card sized</li>
<li>"Last-decade" hardware (700 Mhz processor, 256 MB RAM) that's still
enough to run Linux, code, browse the internet and even play games such
as Quake 3 !</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>What this means</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Programming can be learned by almost anyone</li>
<li>People in poor areas, children in poor schools get access to technology</li>
<li>Like the Kinect, the Raspberry Pi will enable hackers to build ever
more impressive prototypes. The possibilities are endless</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/raspberry-pi.html" title="Source">Fred Wilson on the Raspberry Pi</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fredwilson">@fredwilson</a> - March 1, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Fred Wilson explains why he thinks the Raspberry Pi is a game changer</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Hardware that's currently expensive (phones and especially tablets)
is going to be cheaper and cheaper. We will see sub $100 tablets in 3 to
5 years</li>
<li>The Raspberry Pi's goal is, according to the developper, to entice
children to learn to code. But all markets that can be end-to-end
digital, not just education, will be disrupted</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
