<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: launch | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/launch/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-19T20:03:30+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Need For Air, over and out. Say hello to the tldr.io blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2013/02/19/final-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2013/02/19/final-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>We are still alive!</h2>

<p>You may have noticed, we have been pretty silent lately. Our last
blogpost dates back to November 14th when we announced the first release of our Chrome extension.
As you can imagine, we were pretty busy working on
<a href="http://tldr.io">tldr.io</a> and didn't have enough time to maintain this
blog. Lots of crazy stuff happened: we won
<a href="http://www.seedcamp.com/2012/12/a-worthy-finish-to-2012-seedcamp-paris.html">Seedcamp Paris</a>, we built a lot of new features
including a brand new Chrome extension with which you can read or contribute the summary of any web page and
our community is growing faster than ever.</p>

<br><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Uq82yyl.jpg" alt="Haven't seen you in a while"><br><br>


<h2>What's next?</h2>

<p>We have decided to start blogging again, but as tldr.io and not
NeedForAir anymore. We'll use this <a href="http://blog.tldr.io">new blog</a> to
keep you updated about tldr.io feature releases, best content and we'll also
blog about engineering and entrepreneurial challenges.</p>

<p><a target="_blank" href="http://blog.tldr.io" style="padding:25px;background:#008CD4;display:block;width:200px;margin:30px auto 0px auto;font-size:22px;font-family:CassanetBold, Helvetica Neue, Helvetica,border-radius:5px;color:white;border-radius:5px; text-align: center;">Go read the tldr.io blog</a></p>

<h2>We won't kill NeedForAir though</h2>

<p>There are still a lot of people coming to this blog (mainly from
search) for the tutorials we posted, so we won't shut it down. If you liked what you found here, be
sure to check <a href="http://blog.tldr.io">the tldr.io blog</a> out and update your RSS subscription! And to wrap NeedForAir up, here are the five most-read articles:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/09/d3-tutorial/">Introduction to D3: Build an Animated Graph in 19 Lines of Code</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/22/dns-redirections/">Tutorial: Domain Name System for Beginners</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/07/09/jenkins-in-production/">How We Use Jenkins for Continuous Deployment</a> (a bit outdated since we don't use Jenkins anymore,
 we coded our own CI)</li>
  <li><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/18/game-of-go/">The Game of Go: A Programmer's Perspective</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/08/22/upstart-and-node/">What to Use Upstart (and Other Supervisors) For</a></li>

</ul>


<p>Thank you for reading us thus far!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome extension to read summaries of Hacker News links without leaving the front page]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/11/14/chrome-extension/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T18:04:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/11/14/chrome-extension</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Yo dawg, we heard you like reading Hacker News, so we put summaries in your links</h2>

<p>When you discovered that Superman could see through walls you told yourself that it was the awesomest thing ever. Naturally you wanted to have the same superpower.
Well let's say you can do that now on your browser and <strong>see through hyperlinks with our Chome Extension</strong>.</p>

<p>You love reading the <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> front page articles. But you don't always have the
time to click the links and read them all. That's
why we built this Chrome extension that enables you, <strong>simply by hovering over a
link, to read a summary of the article.</strong> How exciting is this?</p>

<p>Here is what this looks like:</p>

<br><img src="http://i.imgur.com/LEwCV.png" alt="Tldr extension screenshot">




<br>


<p><a target="_blank" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tldr/ohmamcbkcmfalompaelgoepcnbnpiioe" style="padding:25px;background:#008CD4;display:block;width:200px;margin:30px auto 0px auto;font-size:22px;font-family:CassanetBold, Helvetica Neue, Helvetica,border-radius:5px;color:white;border-radius:5px; text-align: center;" onClick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Buttons', 'Click', 'Go to CRX install page']);">Install this awesome extension!</a></p>

<h2>Why does it only work on Hacker News? I want it everywhere!</h2>

<p>We know. We want that too. But as you know, <strong>our summaries are
human-written</strong> because <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/">computers are bad at summarizing</a>.
Today, the community writing summaries is still very small and can't handle a huge load. We summaries
them to be of the highest quality, so we chose to focus on Hacker News
so that we could bring a lot of value to our users while still having
the time to run our company.</p>

<p>You can help! If you like to find the key information in a technical
blogpost, if you want to help other people fight the information
overload or if you simply want tldr.io's coverage of the front page to
be even higher, you can <a href="http://tldr.io/whatisit#install-bm-section"><strong>use our contribution bookmarklet</a>
and start creating summaries</strong> too. We review all the summaries our users
create to ensure they stick to the original author's point of view, but
your contributing really helps the community.</p>

<h2>Why is it a Chrome extension? I want it on Firefox!</h2>

<p>We too! We're currently focusing on a Chrome extension to see how people
use it and how useful they find it. Once we think we have a clear idea
of what the extension should be, we will make a Firefox version. If you
have some ideas, <a href="http://tldr.io/forum/topics/50a4b8f45f5d3cd04a0001b7">please tell us here, we are interested</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're launching tldr.io!]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/09/13/were-launching/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T18:04:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/09/13/were-launching</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><a href="http://tldr.io">tl;dr</a> (too long; didn't read)</h2>

<p>We're super excited to announce that we have finally launched our new product: <strong>tl;dr</strong>!
The three of us quit our dayjobs at the end of 2011 and for the past 5 months we've been hard at work on it, and we're very
proud of what we're releasing.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, our product solves the problem of wanting to know what's in a webpage
without losing precious time. It allows you to display a summary of the webpage you're
currently browsing. The summaries are written by people who found the
webpage interesting before you. If the summary you're asking for doesn't exist yet,
you'll be offered to create it. We decided to rely on people because summarizing
information is a skill people are vastly better at than computers.</p>

<h2>So why did we build this product?</h2>

<p>We read a lot of blogs, be it news or
more educational/topical content. It's been said and resaid that we're
in an age of information overload. There is simply too much content that
is published everyday and it's getting harder and harder to not only keep up with
the firehose but also filter what needs to be read and remembered. Often times we feel like it would
be nice to have access the few key ideas that are worth remembering of an
article we just read.</p>

<p>We also thought <em>'Wouldn't it be cool if upon arriving on a web page we
could display its summary to rapidly see what it's about?</em> Indeed
everyone now knows to choose catchy titles to attract readers. Other signals such as
likes, shares, or upvotes aren't really related to the actual content
and need of the reader. We wanted something that focused on the content,
so that people would be able to make their own opinion about it.
This is why we decided to allow people to attach one
summary to any URL on the web in order to describe what's in it. Sort of
an entry point to each webpage. Turns out there's already an name for
such a summary on the internet: it's <strong>tl;dr</strong>. Once it is written, the tl;dr benefits
everybody in the world. Anyone will be able to get a clean, standardized
preview of what the webpage they're about to browse contains. This can be
very useful on unknown busy webpages that are hard to sift through.</p>

<p>At this point we must point out that we do not want to prevent people
from reading original content. We simply want to pique the interest of the
right people and drive them to content they're looking for by lowering
its barrier to entry for them. Since we believe that summarized
information is one of the most powerful force that drives interest (as
evidenced by academic paper abstracts, google results extracts, etc.) we
think people-contributed summaries will work wonders.</p>

<h2>A word of caution</h2>

<p>This is our first release and shouldn't be considered perfect. There is
still a lot of work ahead of us, we have a big and clear vision for our
company but we're taking baby steps. You should expect new features
regularly, as well as bugs! Besides, since we are building a company,
and a company needs to make money, expect some pricing plans for our
service to come out very soon. For those interested, we've been
bootstrapping for now and haven't taken any investor money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
