<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tldr | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/tldr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T09:47:29+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Golden Age Of Community Organizing Platforms]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T08:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/">already wrote</a> about how
you can leverage some <a href="https://github.com/">social platforms</a> to build
your visibility on the internet, but they offer much more.
They provide appropriate tools that help people to be more productive
and better organized. They are much more functional than pure social networks
and even more valuable as the communities are active.</p>

<p><img src="http://cardview.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/nation-builder.jpg" height="220" alt="Keep the gist" /></p>

<h2>Platforms structure communities</h2>

<p>We can call such a platform a <em>community organizing platform</em> because
it allows a community to have a place to gather, discuss and share. It
provides the global structure the community needs to get organized.
Ten years ago the forums laid the foundation but today these platforms
achieve what's been initiated.</p>

<p>Using these platforms everyone creates and manages a business card that
is accessible by everyone else.
People can easily be identified, followed, consulted and appraised. You
don't have to go to as many conferences or events to meet new people
because it can be done very efficiently online.</p>

<h2>Community organizing platforms offer more than pure social networks</h2>

<p>Pure social networks like Twitter offer ways to
organize communities but don't provide the structure
and tools needed for effective collaboration. They are mainly focus on
sharing.</p>

<p>While community organizing platforms provide a social layer they
also offer services geared towards the community itself. This
combination is what's really valuable.
<a href="http://nationbuilder.com/">Nation Builder</a>
is the perfect example: it features volunteer organization, donation
monitoring, website creation... a comprehensive package
political leaders need to interact with their audience.</p>

<h2>Active communities are driven by knowledge</h2>

<p>We can distinguish communities built upon friendship, professional
activity or common interests. The most active
are the ones based on a common interest, where knowledge and
feedback is a valuable resource. In these ones people spend a lot of time
looking for information. They also create a lot of content in order to
improve their reputation. Such platforms are even more
important for small communities because the resources they want to access are not always well
indexed by search engines.</p>

<p>As sharing information, working collaboratively and giving feedbacks to peers is key in
these communities even a very little one
can be very active.
There is still lots of
them to structure out there, lots of people waiting to
share and collaborate with their peers. Who are they? What can we do for
them?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Computers in Text Summarization]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Stanislas explained in <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/" title="Information Overload">this previous post</a>, we believe we are dealing with too much information to keep up on the Internet. The natural solution is text summarization, and computers can help us there.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/3558255554/sizes/l/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3376/3558255554_9f9c480132_n.jpg" alt="Summary" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/" title="Author">Xeeiliz</a></em></p>

<p>There are roughly two kinds of summaries: the ones that consist of a few of
the most important sentences extracted from the text, the keyphrases, and the ones that
are written from scratch without necessarily using the same phrasing, called abstract summaries.</p>

<h2>Finding the most relevant content: keyphrase extraction</h2>

<p>The big advantage of keyphrase-based summaries is that there is no risk
of miscomprehension since they are composed of unrephrased pieces of the
text. Moreover, computers are able to compute them and get decent
results. There are two main ways to do it: supervised and unsupervised
extraction.</p>

<h3>When you know the context: extraction as supervised learning</h3>

<p>One way to perform this task is described by Peter Turney in <a href="http://webdocs.cs.ualberta.ca/~lindek/650/papers/turney.pdf">this paper</a>. He found that using a custom-designed algorithm that incorporates specialized domain knowledge on a text generates yields very good results: 80% of keyphrases are deemed acceptable by human readers. The problem with this approach is that it requires the computer to know the topic beforehand. It is possible to use a prior first step to determine what it is, but this is difficult and the results are terrible if we get it wrong.</p>

<h3>Applicable to any text: unsupervised keyphrase extraction</h3>

<p>This approaches enables us to extract keyphrases from a text without any
prior knowledge, which is a tremendous improvement upon the previous method. There a several algorithms, and one notable current example is <a href="http://www.summly.com/">Summly</a>. I will explain one of those, named TextRank, to give you a feeling of the kind of techniques used in this field.</p>

<p>The TextRank algorithm was developped by Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau in
<a href="http://acl.ldc.upenn.edu/acl2004/emnlp/pdf/Mihalcea.pdf">this paper</a>. The key idea is that a text
unit (word or phrase depending on the need) that is close to a lot of other important text units is likely a keyphrase. Using the parallel between the "close to" relation and the "referred to by" relation of hyperlinks, TextRank uses Google's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">PageRank</a> to determine which text units are the most important. It works well, its main author was even awarded a $100k grant by Google for her work on keyphrase extraction.</p>

<h2>The best: abstract summarization</h2>

<p>Even though they can be very useful, keyphrase-based summaries are still
rudimentary compared to abstract summaries, because they are much nicer
to read, and we are sure no important information was "left behind" (i.e a keyphrase was not extracted). Also, keyphrase extraction algorithms still find it hard to
summarize technical articles.</p>

<p>Abstract summarization is the limit of what computers can do today. The
main reason for this is that they struggle with the following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Coreferences understanding</strong>. For example, who does 'he'
references in the sentence 'Paul told John he should play squash'?</li>
<li><strong>Word sense disambiguation</strong>. In 'I need batteries for
my mouse', are we talking about the animal or the device?</li>
<li><strong>Sentiment analysis</strong>. Understanding the mood of the writer is often
key to understanding a text, all the more when there is sarcasm.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Computers can help humans summarize a text</h2>

<p>To sum it up, I believe that humans still cannot be replaced by
algorithms if we want to produce quality summaries. Nonetheless, a
computer really can help a us by providing a keyphrase-based summary,
so that we spend less time scanning the text for them. In addition, if
we were able to train algorithms by comparing their output with a human
summary a lot of times for articles on a certain topic, I think it is possible we see significant improvements.</p>

<p><em>Note: some examples were taken from <a href="https://class.coursera.org/nlp/">Stanford's Natural Language
Processing online class</a>. If you couldn't take
it this quarter, look for it, it is a terrific place to learn about this
topic</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell...</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader's curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It's like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn't consolidated in
some fashion. That's why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author's reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You're asking that person for too much work. She doesn't have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it's high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you'll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it's spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Keep Up With the Information Overload]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook notifications, Twitter feeds, RSS feeds, emails, news
aggregators and now so much
more. We are constantly hit by new information, throughout the day, and
the night. There are so many things we want to read or watch.
The fact that the Web is a strictly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">RESTful</a> application (or should I say
<a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2012-02-13-an-api-ontology">Hypermedia</a>) doesn't help because one link usually leads to more links. I'm sure
you've already experienced having more than 20 tabs open in your browser
and thinking "<em>God, when am I going to read all of this?</em>" but instead
of starting reading you scan the links of the page in front of you and
just open more tabs. And this was only made worse by tools such as
<a href="http://instapaper.com" title="Instapaper">Instapaper</a> that make you feel good
about saving stuff for later, even if you know deep inside you'll never
come back to it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/2925760927/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3244/2925760927_a9db10926e_m.jpg" alt="Information overload" /></a></p>

<h2>Current solutions</h2>

<p>It's extremely hard to keep up with all that information, and you
basically have 3 options at the moment:</p>

<h4>Let loose</h4>

<p>Accept that you can't follow it all and if something is really important
it will come back to you one way or another so that missing it the first
time is not a big deal.
I personnally don't like this solution because it means giving up
control on what I read and learn, and it basically amounts to a random
filter with some bias towards the most important news that isn't always
the most interesting.</p>

<h4>Algorithmic filters</h4>

<p>Use tools such as <a href="http://news.me" title="News.me">News.me</a> or <a href="http://focus.io" title="Focus.io">Focus.io</a> that
use machine learning techniques to serve you the stories you might be
interested in the most. However, again, not knowing how these algorithms
work exactly, I fear I am going to lose the serendipity of scanning
myself all the input and selecting the hidden little gem that would be
considered as noise by these algorithms. Again, I hate losing control. I
do think these are better solutions than just letting loose.</p>

<h4>Reducing the input</h4>

<p>This for me is the best alternative. Following sort of a <em>less is more</em> convention,
I am looking to reduce the number of sources rather than increasing it,
keeping only the outstanding ones. I am constantly reevaluating the
quality of the twitter accounts and bloggers I follow in order to remove
those that either tweet too much  or whose content quality has suffered.
I am very rarely looking for new people to follow, and when I try
someone new it is always an experiment, never set in stone. I'd actually
like it if an algorithm could do that for me, again, not knowing the
inner workings of the services that offer news recommendation is too
bad. I'm willing to bet none of them though is going to unfollow someone
on twitter for you, or experiment with a new follower, based on the
quality of the links provided in the tweets. Same for RSS feeds.</p>

<h2>We need a new tool to find good content</h2>

<p>Basically none of today's tools are good at finding good news and
information. You can use a combination of tools (such as <a href="http://quora.com" title="Quora">Quora</a> and <a href="http://stackexchange.com" title="StackEchange">StackExchange</a> but it is more
difficult than one tool and is conducive to a lot of noise. Plus we are
missing a linking tool between content of the same nature and topics,
that would transcend time. There are services like <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a> that you
can browse by searching for tags, but it is not powerful enough in the
way it presents the information. There are still too many links and not
enough clues as to which are interesting and which are not.</p>

<p>But don't worry, we're working on it ;)</p>

<p>Photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/">Martino</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
