<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tldr | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/tldr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-19T12:25:21+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome extension to read summaries of Hacker News links without leaving the front page]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/11/14/chrome-extension/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T18:04:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/11/14/chrome-extension</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Yo dawg, we heard you like reading Hacker News, so we put summaries in your links</h2>

<p>When you discovered that Superman could see through walls you told yourself that it was the awesomest thing ever. Naturally you wanted to have the same superpower.
Well let's say you can do that now on your browser and <strong>see through hyperlinks with our Chome Extension</strong>.</p>

<p>You love reading the <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> front page articles. But you don't always have the
time to click the links and read them all. That's
why we built this Chrome extension that enables you, <strong>simply by hovering over a
link, to read a summary of the article.</strong> How exciting is this?</p>

<p>Here is what this looks like:</p>

<br><img src="http://i.imgur.com/LEwCV.png" alt="Tldr extension screenshot">




<br>


<p><a target="_blank" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tldr/ohmamcbkcmfalompaelgoepcnbnpiioe" style="padding:25px;background:#008CD4;display:block;width:297px;margin:30px auto 0px auto;font-size:22px;font-family:CassanetBold, Helvetica Neue, Helvetica,border-radius:5px;color:white;border-radius:5px;" onClick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Buttons', 'Click', 'Go to CRX install page']);">Install this awesome extension!</a></p>

<h2>Why does it only work on Hacker News? I want it everywhere!</h2>

<p>We know. We want that too. But as you know, <strong>our summaries are
human-written</strong> because <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/">computers are bad at summarizing</a>.
Today, the community writing summaries is still very small and can't handle a huge load. We summaries
them to be of the highest quality, so we chose to focus on Hacker News
so that we could bring a lot of value to our users while still having
the time to run our company.</p>

<p>You can help! If you like to find the key information in a technical
blogpost, if you want to help other people fight the information
overload or if you simply want tldr.io's coverage of the front page to
be even higher, you can <a href="http://tldr.io/whatisit#install-bm-section"><strong>use our contribution bookmarklet</a>
and start creating summaries</strong> too. We review all the summaries our users
create to ensure they stick to the original author's point of view, but
your contributing really helps the community.</p>

<h2>Why is it a Chrome extension? I want it on Firefox!</h2>

<p>We too! We're currently focusing on a Chrome extension to see how people
use it and how useful they find it. Once we think we have a clear idea
of what the extension should be, we will make a Firefox version. If you
have some ideas, <a href="http://tldr.io/forum/topics/50a4b8f45f5d3cd04a0001b7">please tell us here, we are interested</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're launching tldr.io!]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/09/13/were-launching/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T18:04:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/09/13/were-launching</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><a href="http://tldr.io">tl;dr</a> (too long; didn't read)</h2>

<p>We're super excited to announce that we have finally launched our new product: <strong>tl;dr</strong>!
The three of us quit our dayjobs at the end of 2011 and for the past 5 months we've been hard at work on it, and we're very
proud of what we're releasing.</p>

<p>In a nutshell, our product solves the problem of wanting to know what's in a webpage
without losing precious time. It allows you to display a summary of the webpage you're
currently browsing. The summaries are written by people who found the
webpage interesting before you. If the summary you're asking for doesn't exist yet,
you'll be offered to create it. We decided to rely on people because summarizing
information is a skill people are vastly better at than computers.</p>

<h2>So why did we build this product?</h2>

<p>We read a lot of blogs, be it news or
more educational/topical content. It's been said and resaid that we're
in an age of information overload. There is simply too much content that
is published everyday and it's getting harder and harder to not only keep up with
the firehose but also filter what needs to be read and remembered. Often times we feel like it would
be nice to have access the few key ideas that are worth remembering of an
article we just read.</p>

<p>We also thought <em>'Wouldn't it be cool if upon arriving on a web page we
could display its summary to rapidly see what it's about?</em> Indeed
everyone now knows to choose catchy titles to attract readers. Other signals such as
likes, shares, or upvotes aren't really related to the actual content
and need of the reader. We wanted something that focused on the content,
so that people would be able to make their own opinion about it.
This is why we decided to allow people to attach one
summary to any URL on the web in order to describe what's in it. Sort of
an entry point to each webpage. Turns out there's already an name for
such a summary on the internet: it's <strong>tl;dr</strong>. Once it is written, the tl;dr benefits
everybody in the world. Anyone will be able to get a clean, standardized
preview of what the webpage they're about to browse contains. This can be
very useful on unknown busy webpages that are hard to sift through.</p>

<p>At this point we must point out that we do not want to prevent people
from reading original content. We simply want to pique the interest of the
right people and drive them to content they're looking for by lowering
its barrier to entry for them. Since we believe that summarized
information is one of the most powerful force that drives interest (as
evidenced by academic paper abstracts, google results extracts, etc.) we
think people-contributed summaries will work wonders.</p>

<h2>A word of caution</h2>

<p>This is our first release and shouldn't be considered perfect. There is
still a lot of work ahead of us, we have a big and clear vision for our
company but we're taking baby steps. You should expect new features
regularly, as well as bugs! Besides, since we are building a company,
and a company needs to make money, expect some pricing plans for our
service to come out very soon. For those interested, we've been
bootstrapping for now and haven't taken any investor money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Golden Age Of Community Organizing Platforms]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T08:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/11/community-organizing-platforms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/">already wrote</a> about how
you can leverage some <a href="https://github.com/">social platforms</a> to build
your visibility on the internet, but they offer much more.
They provide appropriate tools that help people to be more productive
and better organized. They are much more functional than pure social networks
and even more valuable as the communities are active.</p>

<p><img src="http://cardview.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/nation-builder.jpg" height="220" alt="Keep the gist" /></p>

<h2>Platforms structure communities</h2>

<p>We can call such a platform a <em>community organizing platform</em> because
it allows a community to have a place to gather, discuss and share. It
provides the global structure the community needs to get organized.
Ten years ago the forums laid the foundation but today these platforms
achieve what's been initiated.</p>

<p>Using these platforms everyone creates and manages a business card that
is accessible by everyone else.
People can easily be identified, followed, consulted and appraised. You
don't have to go to as many conferences or events to meet new people
because it can be done very efficiently online.</p>

<h2>Community organizing platforms offer more than pure social networks</h2>

<p>Pure social networks like Twitter offer ways to
organize communities but don't provide the structure
and tools needed for effective collaboration. They are mainly focus on
sharing.</p>

<p>While community organizing platforms provide a social layer they
also offer services geared towards the community itself. This
combination is what's really valuable.
<a href="http://nationbuilder.com/">Nation Builder</a>
is the perfect example: it features volunteer organization, donation
monitoring, website creation... a comprehensive package
political leaders need to interact with their audience.</p>

<h2>Active communities are driven by knowledge</h2>

<p>We can distinguish communities built upon friendship, professional
activity or common interests. The most active
are the ones based on a common interest, where knowledge and
feedback is a valuable resource. In these ones people spend a lot of time
looking for information. They also create a lot of content in order to
improve their reputation. Such platforms are even more
important for small communities because the resources they want to access are not always well
indexed by search engines.</p>

<p>As sharing information, working collaboratively and giving feedbacks to peers is key in
these communities even a very little one
can be very active.
There is still lots of
them to structure out there, lots of people waiting to
share and collaborate with their peers. Who are they? What can we do for
them?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Computers in Text Summarization]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Stanislas explained in <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/" title="Information Overload">this previous post</a>, we believe we are dealing with too much information to keep up on the Internet. The natural solution is text summarization, and computers can help us there.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/3558255554/sizes/l/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3376/3558255554_9f9c480132_n.jpg" alt="Summary" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/" title="Author">Xeeiliz</a></em></p>

<p>There are roughly two kinds of summaries: the ones that consist of a few of
the most important sentences extracted from the text, the keyphrases, and the ones that
are written from scratch without necessarily using the same phrasing, called abstract summaries.</p>

<h2>Finding the most relevant content: keyphrase extraction</h2>

<p>The big advantage of keyphrase-based summaries is that there is no risk
of miscomprehension since they are composed of unrephrased pieces of the
text. Moreover, computers are able to compute them and get decent
results. There are two main ways to do it: supervised and unsupervised
extraction.</p>

<h3>When you know the context: extraction as supervised learning</h3>

<p>One way to perform this task is described by Peter Turney in <a href="http://webdocs.cs.ualberta.ca/~lindek/650/papers/turney.pdf">this paper</a>. He found that using a custom-designed algorithm that incorporates specialized domain knowledge on a text generates yields very good results: 80% of keyphrases are deemed acceptable by human readers. The problem with this approach is that it requires the computer to know the topic beforehand. It is possible to use a prior first step to determine what it is, but this is difficult and the results are terrible if we get it wrong.</p>

<h3>Applicable to any text: unsupervised keyphrase extraction</h3>

<p>This approaches enables us to extract keyphrases from a text without any
prior knowledge, which is a tremendous improvement upon the previous method. There a several algorithms, and one notable current example is <a href="http://www.summly.com/">Summly</a>. I will explain one of those, named TextRank, to give you a feeling of the kind of techniques used in this field.</p>

<p>The TextRank algorithm was developped by Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau in
<a href="http://acl.ldc.upenn.edu/acl2004/emnlp/pdf/Mihalcea.pdf">this paper</a>. The key idea is that a text
unit (word or phrase depending on the need) that is close to a lot of other important text units is likely a keyphrase. Using the parallel between the "close to" relation and the "referred to by" relation of hyperlinks, TextRank uses Google's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">PageRank</a> to determine which text units are the most important. It works well, its main author was even awarded a $100k grant by Google for her work on keyphrase extraction.</p>

<h2>The best: abstract summarization</h2>

<p>Even though they can be very useful, keyphrase-based summaries are still
rudimentary compared to abstract summaries, because they are much nicer
to read, and we are sure no important information was "left behind" (i.e a keyphrase was not extracted). Also, keyphrase extraction algorithms still find it hard to
summarize technical articles.</p>

<p>Abstract summarization is the limit of what computers can do today. The
main reason for this is that they struggle with the following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Coreferences understanding</strong>. For example, who does 'he'
references in the sentence 'Paul told John he should play squash'?</li>
<li><strong>Word sense disambiguation</strong>. In 'I need batteries for
my mouse', are we talking about the animal or the device?</li>
<li><strong>Sentiment analysis</strong>. Understanding the mood of the writer is often
key to understanding a text, all the more when there is sarcasm.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Can computers help humans summarize text?</h2>

<p>Today, computers are not good at summarizing text, and they probably
will be for a long time. Nevertheless, we may be able to make
significant progress if we had a huge database of summarize. That's what
we're working on, so future will tell!</p>

<p><em>Note: some examples were taken from <a href="https://class.coursera.org/nlp/">Stanford's Natural Language
Processing online class</a>. If you couldn't take
it this quarter, look for it, it is a terrific place to learn about this
topic</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell...</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader's curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It's like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
