<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: UX | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/ux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-24T16:06:37+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siri or the Reinvention of Mobile Search User Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T17:58:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/31/siri-or-the-reinvention-of-mobile-search-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Search is a behavior, it is what people do when they want to find
something and don't know exactly what they're looking for, or when they
know what they're looking for but don't know where to find it.
But search on computers or on the web has traditionally been either
intuitive and useless or unintuitive and powerful, as I'm going to show
you.
Even searching on Google used to be <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2003/10/search.html">hard and
unintuitive</a>
for the layperson. But Google improved the UX and it was so
powerful that people just learned to use it.</p>

<p>Until now
search was basically equated to Google (a single-entry point to all of
the resources available on the web), but with the major
<a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/03/welcome-to-the-post-pc-era.html">shift</a> from computers to mobile devices,
search UX needs to be reinvented.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/6751892711/"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7143/6751892711_f59c0452e8.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37161567@N04/" title="Author">Yogesh Mhatre</a></em></p>

<h2>Fact: Mobile Search User Experience Sucks</h2>

<p>Searching on smartphones is currently a terrible user experience. Screens are
tiny, typos frequent, missclicks incredibly annoying. Search results
don't account well for the fact that smartphones are not simply smaller versions of
computers. Recently for instance, an <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/bw/app/quickmaps/id506283203?mt=8">iphone app</a> that is a
simple user interface for frequent
Google Maps queries received a very positive feedback and was an instant
success.</p>

<p>That's why most search on mobile is done on vertically differentiated
apps: one searches for places to stay on the Airbnb app, and looks for movies on the IMDB
app. These apps provide a better search experience, from the query to
the results "page". The problem with that scheme is when you don't know
the particular app that suits your needs. Unless you follow Techcrunch
or HackerNews religiously it can get tricky. The beauty of Google and
other search engines was that they provided a single entry point for web
content. You didn't have to know anything else, and a lot of people
still google "facebook" to reach the facebook website.</p>

<p>But the UX of single entry point search is so bad on mobile that people
don't bother using it. Instead they're left with discovering content
through social media apps which offer a very decent UX for that. But they
cannot look for something from a single-entry point unless they muster
enough courage to deal with Google's web app, and that's too bad.</p>

<h2>Lets Go Back In Time</h2>

<p>When Windows arrived on the market, it represented a major shift in UX.
Before Windows, people interacted with computers using a command-line
interface(CLI), otherwise known as the shell. Command-line means that instead
of clicking around, navigating in your folders and moving files
visually, you gave a command to the computer and it executed your
command. The CLI was (and still is) a great UX for search of files in a
computer. Windows' graphical user interface, on the other hand, was absolutely terrible at this.</p>

<p>Can you remember when you still had Windows? Looking for a file was
absurdly hard and difficult, borderline impossible. That's why most
people just used their brain to remember where they put their files on
their hard drive, and went looking for it by opening folder after
folder. So Windows was a huge regression in search UX from the days when there was no graphical
interface.</p>

<p>Windows was arguably more intuitive than the CLI, you didn't have to
learn any commands to use it. All you had to do is click buttons and move your cursor
around. But as you gained intuitiveness, you lost the power of the CLI.</p>

<p>The reason why I'm talking about
all this is we are currently witnessing a similar change of paradigms
as websites are becoming webapps or even native mobile apps, that cannot
be cleanly separated into different pages anymore. And again search UX
is getting the bitter end of the deal.</p>

<p>Apps are more intuitive, there are no more files, no more links, it's
pure visual and intuition heaven such that 2-year olds are comfortable with iPads,
but powerful search is not part of the experience.</p>

<h2>Enters Siri</h2>

<p>Siri is the new personal assistant that lives in all iPhones 4S. You
talk to her and she executes your wishes to the best of her abilities.</p>

<p>A lot of people say it's a gadget, it's not actionable,
it's an Apple marketing ploy to sell you an iPhone 4 at a 20% premium. I
think however that it's much more than that and that these critics are
missing the elephant in the room. For me, Siri is the new
command-line interface.</p>

<p>Think about what Siri does. You ask her to set your
alarm, to give you the weather, to find a restaurant, to look for places, all from a single entry point.
Basically, it's a <strong>vocal recognition enabled command interface</strong>.
And even though it's still rough on the
edges, I'm positive it's going to become much more powerful in the near
future. Vocal commands are the ultimate user experience, everybody gets
it. The sole interface that beat vocal commands would be a mind-reading
interface.
So for the first time we have a <strong>search UX that is both intuitive
and powerful</strong> (or promising to be at least). Siri is abstracting links
and complicated queries from the end-user. Most people don't care about
links, they just want the data, the resource that the links point to.</p>

<p>Siri is going to bring search back to mobile devices, and make search a
huge part of the mobile ecosystem once it opens its API to developers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
