<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: platform | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/platform/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-06T10:23:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Didn't Learn In College]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T23:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Albert Wenger is right:
<a href="http://continuations.com/post/20112755144/students-are-woefully-prepared-for-internet-age-job">we are woefully prepared for internet age job market</a>.
The three of us graduated in Computer Science in college, following a solid
engineering cursus. But during the
numerous courses we took we never heard of <a href="http://github.com/">Github</a> nor <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">StackOverflow</a>.
People attending creative and artistic
formation don't hear of <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a> neither.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7044/7046351459_53d8ed3283.jpg" alt="Jeff Atwood" /></p>

<p>You could argue: "What's the problem with that? You aren't supposed to learn
how to use these platforms in school but core skills in your field!"</p>

<p>But that would be missing a point. The education we all receive has one final
goal: be prepared to get the best job as possible. In our current
era <strong>finding a job doesn't come down to respond to job offers by sending
cover letters and resume</strong> nor spam by email all our contacts in the industry
to get an interview.</p>

<p>We are lucky to live through the emergence and the
expansion of specialized platforms which can help us build our personal
and professional identity. With these platforms <strong>we can easily have a
professional visibility, expose our skills so they can be assessed by
everyone and acquire real experience with real work.</strong></p>

<p>The very first recommendation we should receive beginning a course in
a topic is registering on all the platforms related to this topic. The
professors should foster us to leverage these platform to develop our
skills, build our expertise and gain some fame. Such platforms work this way: they play with
our ego to encourage us to contribute more and more and make our
achievements visible for everyone in return. <strong>They are built to be our showcase</strong> and
we should take advantage of it. We do so many interesting projects in
school, sometimes state of the art implementations in CS, that get lost
on our machine. They should be public to catch recruiters' attention on
our profile and skills or help us <a href="http://cdixon.org/2012/02/26/the-internet-is-reshaping-our-economy-from-one-of-huge-corporations-with-lots-of-jobs-to-huge-platforms-with-lots-of-income-streams/">create our future income streams</a>.</p>

<p>So at which level can we improve the promotion of such platforms? At the school's level?
At the professors' level? They should all keep up with the internet economy like they
usually keep up with the <em>real</em> economy. Schools should increase professors' awareness, who
are mainly researchers in engineering schools for example, to this
concern but it's up to the professors to promote personaly the right
platforms. Professors do already a great job teaching us their
knowledge, <strong>they should go further and encourage us to capitalize on their
teaching</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
