<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-30T10:57:53+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Lies from Losers, Web/Mobile Integration, Community Feedback]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-01T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://bhorowitz.com/2012/02/29/lies-that-losers-tell/" title="Source">Lies that Losers Tell</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/bhorowitz">@bhorowitz</a> - Feb 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Ben Horowitz describes the false explanations CEOs and employees find a
posteriori to justify their failure and why they do that. Stop burrying
your head in the sand.</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Familiar lies</strong>

<ul>
<li>“<em>She left, but we were going to fire her, or give her a bad performance review</em>” : Instead of justifying the departure of your employees giving false excuses, ask yourself why you couldn't keep them.</li>
<li>“<em>We would have won, but the other guys gave the deal away</em>” : Validate this claim with the actual customer instead of believing the Sales Rep who doesn't want to take the blame.</li>
<li>"<em>Just because we missed the intermediate milestones doesn’t mean we won’t hit our product schedule</em>" : When the facts don’t align with the good news, a clever manager will find the narrative to make everybody feel better... until the next meeting.</li>
<li>“<em>We have a very high churn rate, but as soon as we turn on email marketing to our user base, people will come back</em>” : The reason that people leave our service and don’t come back is that we have not been sending them enough spam ?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Why are the CEOs/employees lying ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Andy Grove explains that humans, particularly those who build things, only listen to leading indicators of good news and tend to justify bad news with false excuses.</li>
<li>Lying CEOs regularly take action on the positive indicator and look for alternative explanations on the negative indicator.</li>
<li>CEOs are not lying to investors, they are lying to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2012/01/28/web-second-mobile-first/" title="Source">Web Second, Mobile First</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=msuster">@msuster</a> - Jan 28, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Mark Suster reacts to Fred Wilson's blog post <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2010/09/mobile-first-web-second.html" title="AVC blog post">Mobile First, Web Second</a> reminding startups not to forget the Web</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>For 1.5 year people forgot Web Second and just thought Mobile First</strong>

<ul>
<li>It's important not give up on the power of the tethered web, of large screen real estate, of a keyboard.</li>
<li>What's even more important is to have a strategy that matches
customers wants and not developers whims.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mobile has clearly critical attributes</strong>

<ul>
<li>They are personal, location aware, occupy a lot of people's leisure
time.</li>
<li>They are one touch away from buying and represent the "<em>bottom
end of the sales funnel</em>"</li>
<li>The limited real estate forces less choice and offers more focus on
the content.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>But products have to be integrated</strong>

<ul>
<li>Many things cannot be done on a mobile</li>
<li>Mobile should serve a different experience, a different usecase of the service.</li>
<li>The web product can offer complementary services that make the
product even more attractive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leverage the web to :</strong>

<ul>
<li>Create a differentiated product vs your mobile-only competitors.</li>
<li>Enable content creation and curation to make mobile consumption a better experience.</li>
<li>Organize and make the most of the content created by the mobile</li>
<li>Build features that make using native-phones apps pointless.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tablets come third</strong>

<ul>
<li>Extension to mobile strategy (larger real estate make content
  discovery different, increase the features possible...)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/02/listen-to-your-community-but-dont-let-them-tell-you-what-to-do.html" title="Source">Listen to Your Community, But Don't Let Them Tell You What to Do</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/codinghorror">@codinghorror</a> - Feb 3, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Jeff Atwoods talks about the need to organize your community feedback
to take the most out of it</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Having a meta place to discuss the product is important</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meta participation is the source of all meaningful leadership and governance in a community, so it is cultivated and monitored closely.</li>
<li>Meta is for people who care so deeply about their community that they're willing to go one step further, to come together and spend even more of their time deciding how to maintain and govern it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to leverage this meta place ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Animate the place : listen, respond</li>
<li>Sort between feedback and feature requests</li>
<li>Know how to extract core information and underlying needs from feature requests</li>
<li>Know to sort between useless and awesome feedback, 10% of the feedback is useful and can be gems</li>
<li>Don't hesitate to be honest explaining the choices the company did
about the features the product offers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Assets of a Consumer-Web Startup, Internal People Metrics]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://mporat.tumblr.com/post/16753414806/what-asset-are-you-building" title="Source">What assets are you building ?</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/mporat">@mporat</a> - Jan 30, 2012</em></p>

<p>If you are building a consumer internet startup, you need to think about the assets that you are building and how these fit with your scaling and fundraising strategies.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Number of users</strong>

<ul>
<li>Most difficult to execute and scale because the lifetime value of a user is typically very low</li>
<li>Needs low customer acquisition cost, high retention, high conversion, tremendous growth, a lot of financing runway until the sheer number of users can generate huge revenues via advertising or traffic generation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High lifetime value</strong>

<ul>
<li>No need for a lot of users, because you make a lot of money of them.</li>
<li>Rarely needs mass financing because they are cash cows</li>
<li>Can invest heavily in marketing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Massive data</strong>

<ul>
<li>Sometimes (twitter,instagram) the data inputted by the users is more important than the users</li>
<li>Free services to the user in order to leverage the data at scale</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A great platform</strong>

<ul>
<li>Monetization comes from 3rd parties (think facebook/zynga)</li>
<li>Main asset is user engagement with your platform</li>
<li>Need to build the platform as well as the first services on top of it</li>
<li>Needs a lot of financing</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/2/" title="Source">Five New Management Metrics You Need To Know</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jslavet">@jslavet</a> - Dec 13, 2011</em></p>

<p>Here is a list of 5 very important metrics that never appear in annual
reports. Most companies measure outputs but not inputs or throughput.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Flow State Percentage</strong>

<ul>
<li>Interruptions move us out of flow state which is the state that
enables the most productivity.</li>
<li>It takes seconds to get out of but can
take very long to get back in.</li>
<li>Measure how uninterrupted your
programmers are.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Anxiety-Boredom Continuum</strong>

<ul>
<li>People want to be challenged, but not to the point that they break
down.</li>
<li>On the other hand, people will leave if they are bored.</li>
<li>Check in often with your employees to make sure you are striking the
right balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Meeting Promoter Score</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meetings are very expensive and rarely productive</li>
<li>At the end of each meeting, ask each participant to rate it and
suggest improvements</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Compound weekly learning rate</strong>

<ul>
<li>The ability to learn is like compounding interest on an investment</li>
<li>Ask your team: how did you get 1% better this week?</li>
<li>Did you learn something valuable from our customers?</li>
<li>Did you make a change to the product that drove better results?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Positive Feedback ratio</strong>

<ul>
<li>Catch people doing good things and tell them</li>
<li>This way when you provide feedback on areas to improve, they will
really listen</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
