<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-19T12:30:03+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[History is Repeating Itself: from Online Poker to Startups]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/21/history-is-repeating-itself-from-online-poker-to-startups/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T12:49:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/21/history-is-repeating-itself-from-online-poker-to-startups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://i38.tinypic.com/34telxc.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Graph of Isildur1's winnings against durrrr" src="http://i38.tinypic.com/34telxc.jpg" height="450px" width="600px"></a>
<em>Image courtesy of <a href="http://highstakesdb.com">High Stakes DB</a></em></p>

<p>Poker is often used as an analogy for <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/from-the-archives-the-poker-analogy.html">investing</a>
or daytrading. The rationale being that there is money at stake, some randomness involved and people are actually winning
in all these "games". However in this blogpost I don't want to focus on
these elements but rather on how the startup ecosystem is going through
exactly the same thing the online poker ecosystem went through a few
years ago. In
order to clear the air, I've started playing poker when I was in
college/grad school, and won mid 6 figures playing heads-up cash games in quite a short time
starting from a free 50 bucks, rising
pretty fast once I "got it". But I was never even close to a top
player like <a href="http://www.highstakesdb.com/profiles/jungleman12.aspx">jungleman12</a> or <a href="http://www.highstakesdb.com/profiles/pokerstars/Sauce123.aspx">Sauce123</a> who made millions by the
time they were 21. The
highest I played good players was 1000nl
with some drunken stunts much higher (these didn't go too well). <em>For those
who don't know, 1000nl means $5/$10 blinds no limit, meaning you usually
play with a $1000+ stack).</em></p>

<h2>A Brief History of Online Poker</h2>

<h3>Early On</h3>

<p>Online poker started in
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_poker">1998</a> but I was still
playing Lego(TM) then. However, from what I gathered during my insanely
long hours reading poker blogs and
<a href="http://forumserver.twoplustwo.com">twoplustwo</a>, it was pretty awesome,
nobody had a clue what they were doing, and a few smart guys made
millions at 16 years old because they were a bit more creative, ruthless
and self-controlled than the others. All the winners were completely
self-taught, information about winning strategies, psychological
pitfalls were very scarce, and theory was completely absent of most
winning poker players' thought processes.</p>

<h3>Poker Reaches For Everyone</h3>

<p>I entered the online poker world belatedly, around 2008-9. At this point, poker training sites such
as <a href="http://cardrunners.com">Cardrunners</a>, <a href="http://leggopoker.com">Leggopoker</a>, <a href="http://deucescracked.com">DeucesCracked</a>
already existed and were growing pretty rapidly. These sites would
charge you a measly $30 a month for incredible insights from some very
good poker players, and probably enabled thousands of people to earn a
ton of money they would have never hoped for. In Europe,
<a href="http://pokerstrategy.com">Pokerstrategy</a> was even more daring, and
decided to give a free $50 (it was really free, no CC required or any
other bullshit) to anyone asking for it that passed a 20-question quizz
(and that surely didn't weed out anybody but the laziest chumps). It
worked phenomenally well from the rumors I heard.
The point is, online poker had matured to the stage at which people were
now making money coaching it (I coached small stakes for $200/hour, but high-stakes coaching rates were closer to $1-2k/hour), teaching it via video, writing and selling <a href="http://www.dailyvariance.com/poker-books/let-there-be-range/">books</a>
about it for seemingly obscene <a href="http://bestpokercoaching.com/shop/product/the-blue-book-of-poker-by-shootaa-aka-reid-young/">prices</a>,
blogging about it, etc. It was really an incredible thing. Now anyone
with a bit of self-control, normal intelligence and a good deal of
dedication could become a winning poker player and live the dream.
Someone once said on Two Plus Two that it was probably the only place on
earth where a 16-year old would feel bad about making only $100k in a
year and complain that he had been unlucky.</p>

<h3>The Level Goes Up Globally</h3>

<p>However, it made the global level go up steeply and quickly.
It got harder than ever to get past micro-stakes as most people there
were actually trying to win, watching videos, getting coaching. They
were still terrible, but much better than the people playing the same stakes 5
years earlier.
The same held true at every stake, and at mid-stakes, people were really
starting to get pretty good, high stakes was reserved to elite
hard-working players. By the time I got the bankroll to comfortably play
mid-stakes, it had become really tough. Fish would get eaten alive
extremely quickly and a lot of hitherto winning players started breaking
even, becoming <a href="http://forumserver.twoplustwo.com/32/beginners-questions/being-rakeback-pro-389038/">rakeback pros</a>, <a href="http://forumserver.twoplustwo.com/29/news-views-gossip/remember-h-llingol-700116/">went broke</a> or quit the game altogether.</p>

<h3>Good Players Start Accelerators</h3>

<p>A few good players saw how their students went from donk to very good
quickly, and how little money they made from it (relatively). So they
started devising group-staking programs, formed stables of young eager
horses that wanted to benefit from their insights and threw them enough
money to get them started. I'm pretty sure this went very well for a few
elite players, but terribly wrong for other people with lower quality
insights that just tried to follow the money.</p>

<h3>People Go The Easiest Way When It Gets Too Hard</h3>

<p>So a lot of people learned to game select better (some would say
<a href="http://www.kokev.in/2010/12/19/pokers-tragedy-of-the-commons-bumhunting/">bumhunt</a>), which means choosing
profitable tables where there are weaker players. Some (including
myself), took it to the extreme by only playin heads up (one-to-one)
with significantly worse players than themselves at stakes they cared
about. This is not wrong in and of itself, anyone's entitled to his
choices, and some people were after the money, not the glory. This
highly annoyed the greatest players though, because they couldn't find
anyone to play with.</p>

<h3>Stakes Rise</h3>

<p>Stakes also gradually rose. There was a time when 400nl was the highest
online stake offered, then it went to 2knl and when I first played, the highest stakes
offered were already 10knl. A few months later, 100knl tables were <a href="http://www.highstakesdb.com/548-railheaven-5001000-nl-holdem-6-seats-new-table.aspx">introduced</a>
on Full Tilt Poker (rip).</p>

<h3>Established Top Players Help Each Other</h3>

<p>As available stakes rose from 2knl to 100knl, swings became huge and few
players were properly bankrolled for those stakes. High stakes players
started taking a piece of one another all the time, leading to confusing
and some time embarassing or devastating scenarios, although some
probably did very well at staking and swapping percentages.</p>

<h3>People Say It's Now Impossible to Become a Legend</h3>

<p>People were saying rising to high stakes let alone
nosebleeds was impossible, and yet a few people did it, through sheer
hard work, passion and probably talent. The most legendary of all is
<a href="http://www.pokertableratings.com/fulltilt-player-search/jungleman12">Jungleman</a>.</p>

<h2>So How Does the Startup World Compare?</h2>

<p>I'm obviously very new to the startup world, having started my own only 2
months ago. (Yeah while at Stanford, I foolishly (or brilliantly) chose to
play 25nl instead of going to my entrepreneurship classes, ah the
allure of quick money). I won't talk about the early days because I
really haven't read enough about it and most of you probably know more
about it than I do.</p>

<h3>Startup Are For Everyone</h3>

<p>But I feel like I'm entering the startup world at roughly the same stage
I entered the online poker world. The early goldrush is over, meaning
it's not about being at the right place at the right time any more. The
starting, building, growing processes are getting theorized and written
about everywhere on the internet. <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker
News</a> is the equivalent of <a href="http://forumserver.twoplustwo.com">Two Plus
Two</a>.
People are writing books, <a href="http://theleanstartup.com/book">The Lean Startup</a>,
The Startup Manual and a
slew of others come to
mind (although these are much more affordable than poker books). Hell
even we wrote a <a href="http://leanpub.com/startupflow">book</a>!
People are making <a href="http://www.udemy.com/search?q=startup">videos</a>, <a href="http://www.skillshare.com/Course-Launching-Your-Startup-Idea/2055575858">selling</a>
<a href="http://www.skillshare.com/Employee-Equity-Overview/890814338">classes</a> about
<a href="http://www.skillshare.com/site/search?q=startup&amp;city=nyc">startups</a> on
<a href="http://skillshare.com">Skillshare</a>.</p>

<p>Even the core engineering competencies are given away for free by sites
such as <a href="http://udacity.com">Udacity</a> or <a href="http://coursera.org">Coursera</a>.</p>

<p>And this is really great. It opens opportunities to millions of people
that didn't grow up in the Silicon Valley to gain invaluable insights
into what made successes and failures, it makes people dream and
motivates people, like I used to dream reading Cole South's <a href="http://cts687.livejournal.com/">blog</a> (a fascinating read about his lightning-fast rise to legend status).
Now I read stories about the Paypal Mafia, Zuckerberg, Drew Houston,
Brian Chesky, Kevin Rose or Kevin Systrom. Again the stakes are not the
same, and it's incredible to be able to dream like that.</p>

<h3>Good Players Start Accelerators</h3>

<p>Y Combinator and so many others start forming stables of promising
teams that they stake and give insights to. The best do make a lot of
money from it and produce some of today's rising stars. All the
less selective followers probably won't be as lucky.</p>

<h3>The Level Goes Up Globally</h3>

<p>However what this means is that the global level is also rising, and
rising quickly and globally. More and more talented people now know that
they can apply their skills and time to doing a startup, and the
standards for traction, quality of product, quality of team, revenues
are going up before you can be considered for an investment.</p>

<p>A lot more people are now competing, not only for funding but also for
spots in Google results pages, Google Ads rankings, app-stores rankings,
share of time, share of mind, etc.</p>

<h3>People Go The Easiest Way When It Gets Too Hard</h3>

<p>A lot of ideas are now X as a service, or X for Y, where you just
replace X and Y by an existing service, company, market or geography. Sometimes that might
a genuinely great idea, but I feel that this way of thinking is just
never going to yield to real breakthroughs, and more importantly it is
going to lead to ton of mediocre, unambitious ideas. However, if we
follow the poker analogy, it is very likely the best way to have enjoy
very decent monetary success and to build a thriving business. Shooting
for the stars is harder than ever, as was rising to nosebleed stakes in
2009.</p>

<h3>Stakes Rise</h3>

<p>We're reading about it every other day on Techcrunch, Twitter and tech
blogs, valuations are through the roof, it's a bubble, blablabla. I have
no idea if it's a bubble or not but the facts are here: it's not
uncommon now to talk of a $3million seed round or a $10million series A
round and $50million series B (100knl does seem small compared to these
numbers). Facebook is going to be the biggest tech
IPO in history. Services are now reaching millions or even billions of
users.</p>

<h3>Established Top Players Help Each Other</h3>

<p>Established entrepreneurs, are taking pieces of each other's companies
all the time as most of them are very active angel investors from what I
can read on Techcrunch, just like high-stakes players would stake each
other. Not sure how this will end for most of them, if we follow the poker analogy,
probably badly in a lot of cases. However I'm sure these investments are
dealt with in a more professional way than 18 year-old kids simply chatting on AIM and transfering hundreds
of thousands of $ to one another just by clicking a few buttons
on a poker site, which led to a lot of confusion and scams.</p>

<h3>People Say It's Now Impossible to Become a Legend</h3>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/Jason">Jason Calacanis</a>'s last newsletter was
about <em>The Age of Excellence</em>. In his words, <em>There's no room left in 2012 for average, or even good, products.</em>
Meaning that if you want to make it to the top, you know need to battle
as hard as ever, work extremely hard (not necessarily in a long hours
way) and consistently outsmart your competition. And the rise of those
who do everything right will be meteoric (Instagram rings a bell?) like
jungleman12's rise was in online poker.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>So I feel like history is really repeating itself for me, except this
time I won't settle for bumhunting or an easy way out.
Also I actually will make something useful instead of
just taking people's money by just clicking buttons at 4am in my
underpants with pizza boxes and bottle of cokes surrounding me.
Hopefully the startup world won't crash like online poker did
on <a href="http://www.pokernews.com/news/2011/04/a-closer-look-at-online-poker-black-friday-indictment-10224.htm">Black Friday</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
