<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: summary | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/summary/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-29T16:57:16+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capitalize on What You Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T14:27:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a lot, probably an average of 15 blogposts a day and a book every
two weeks. I find that I sometimes have a lot of trouble
remembering the things I just read. Well it's
usually not completely forgotten, the information is likely stored in my
unconscious brain and will trickle back to my consciousness when
somethings triggers it, such as a question or a situation that matches
the pattern my brain stored when I read said content. So that means I
just need a little prodding in order to remember. However there is I
think a more interesting question: how do you build upon what you read?
How do you effectively turn information into knowledge? The secret lies in
having an active attitude towards remembering things, and not just passively consume content.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/2641415853/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3061/2641415853_325ea48e8e_n.jpg" alt="Siri helps Doggy" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/42625902@N00/" title="Author">Shishberg</a></em></p>

<h2>Write it Down</h2>

<p>Writing things down has a number of wonderful consequences.</p>

<p>First of all
the information is "safer" in the sense that it is now written down in a
place from which it is easier to retrieve in its actual form than from
your unconscious brain. Not only that but it also ensures that the
information stays put and doesn't change. One cannot say the same holds
true for memories, as the brain changes them all the time. Memories are
very volatile and often the brain tampers with them to spin them more
positively or make them more relevant to the context. Writing down will prevent
information from being distorted by your unconscious brain.</p>

<p>Additionally, writing things down will actually strengthen your memories.
When you write full sentences that
are grammatically correct (or close to correct at least), you must
formalize relationships between facts, entities, people, and concepts.
The brain being better suited to memorize relationships and patterns,
it will be easier for you to memorize that way instead of simply highlighting a few
words or numbers here and there that aren't linked together by explicit relationships. (Think of a graph.)</p>

<p>Last but not least, text is universal. Information in writing is easily
accessible and shareable. This is important because for instance say you
store information in other formats such as audio or video, it
won't be as easily retrieved and accessed. This is why I love blogposts
but am not a fan of podcasts or videos that don't include a "textified"
version.</p>

<p>In that regard, I write summaries of what I read and find most
interesting and useful. It is important to summarize relationships and
not facts only, so that it matches the brain's memorizing process.</p>

<h2>Practice</h2>

<p>Musicians are known for their disciplined rehearsals. When I was 10
years old I started learning to play the piano. My parents would pay
this private tutor that came once a week and insisted I play 3 hours of
piano per day. At this time I was of course way to enthralled by my
Playstation to care, but I do regret it now. So I didn't practice like I
should have, and the promising career as a pianist that lied ahead of me
ground to a screeching halt. However some of my friends heroically put in the
effort and I can see now that practice makes perfect.</p>

<p>Where does that all fit with memorizing and building knowledge? The goal is to
apply the methods of musicians to the practice of building knowledge. In that
case, practicing means a few things:
* Write an interesting bit of knowledge down in different ways, targetting varied audiences (yourself, your family,
  friends, colleagues, etc.)
* Talk about it to people who have a varying level of understanding of
  that particular topic. They will ask you questions you didn't expect
  and force you to dig deeper and strengthen your knowledge.
* Weave blobs of knowledge together. By that I mean think about what one
  relationship in a given domain means if applied to another one. (For
  instance Math and Computer Science, or Sociology and Networks,
  Math and Art, etc.) Bridging domains will often make great insights and
  ideas pop in your head and further strengthen your understanding and
  memory of a bit of knowledge.</p>

<p>Capitalizing on what you read by writing it down and practicing will
slowly (but surely!) turn you in a walking encyclopedia. You will be able to remember
a lot more things than you are used to, and gradually gain a deeper
understanding of what you memorize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Role of Computers in Text Summarization]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T08:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/06/why-computers-are-bad-at-summarizing-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Stanislas explained in <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/" title="Information Overload">this previous post</a>, we believe we are dealing with too much information to keep up on the Internet. The natural solution is text summarization, and computers can help us there.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/3558255554/sizes/l/in/photostream/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3376/3558255554_9f9c480132_n.jpg" alt="Summary" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xeeliz/" title="Author">Xeeiliz</a></em></p>

<p>There are roughly two kinds of summaries: the ones that consist of a few of
the most important sentences extracted from the text, the keyphrases, and the ones that
are written from scratch without necessarily using the same phrasing, called abstract summaries.</p>

<h2>Finding the most relevant content: keyphrase extraction</h2>

<p>The big advantage of keyphrase-based summaries is that there is no risk
of miscomprehension since they are composed of unrephrased pieces of the
text. Moreover, computers are able to compute them and get decent
results. There are two main ways to do it: supervised and unsupervised
extraction.</p>

<h3>When you know the context: extraction as supervised learning</h3>

<p>One way to perform this task is described by Peter Turney in <a href="http://webdocs.cs.ualberta.ca/~lindek/650/papers/turney.pdf">this paper</a>. He found that using a custom-designed algorithm that incorporates specialized domain knowledge on a text generates yields very good results: 80% of keyphrases are deemed acceptable by human readers. The problem with this approach is that it requires the computer to know the topic beforehand. It is possible to use a prior first step to determine what it is, but this is difficult and the results are terrible if we get it wrong.</p>

<h3>Applicable to any text: unsupervised keyphrase extraction</h3>

<p>This approaches enables us to extract keyphrases from a text without any
prior knowledge, which is a tremendous improvement upon the previous method. There a several algorithms, and one notable current example is <a href="http://www.summly.com/">Summly</a>. I will explain one of those, named TextRank, to give you a feeling of the kind of techniques used in this field.</p>

<p>The TextRank algorithm was developped by Rada Mihalcea and Paul Tarau in
<a href="http://acl.ldc.upenn.edu/acl2004/emnlp/pdf/Mihalcea.pdf">this paper</a>. The key idea is that a text
unit (word or phrase depending on the need) that is close to a lot of other important text units is likely a keyphrase. Using the parallel between the "close to" relation and the "referred to by" relation of hyperlinks, TextRank uses Google's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PageRank">PageRank</a> to determine which text units are the most important. It works well, its main author was even awarded a $100k grant by Google for her work on keyphrase extraction.</p>

<h2>The best: abstract summarization</h2>

<p>Even though they can be very useful, keyphrase-based summaries are still
rudimentary compared to abstract summaries, because they are much nicer
to read, and we are sure no important information was "left behind" (i.e a keyphrase was not extracted). Also, keyphrase extraction algorithms still find it hard to
summarize technical articles.</p>

<p>Abstract summarization is the limit of what computers can do today. The
main reason for this is that they struggle with the following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Coreferences understanding</strong>. For example, who does 'he'
references in the sentence 'Paul told John he should play squash'?</li>
<li><strong>Word sense disambiguation</strong>. In 'I need batteries for
my mouse', are we talking about the animal or the device?</li>
<li><strong>Sentiment analysis</strong>. Understanding the mood of the writer is often
key to understanding a text, all the more when there is sarcasm.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Computers can help humans summarize a text</h2>

<p>To sum it up, I believe that humans still cannot be replaced by
algorithms if we want to produce quality summaries. Nonetheless, a
computer really can help a us by providing a keyphrase-based summary,
so that we spend less time scanning the text for them. In addition, if
we were able to train algorithms by comparing their output with a human
summary a lot of times for articles on a certain topic, I think it is possible we see significant improvements.</p>

<p><em>Note: some examples were taken from <a href="https://class.coursera.org/nlp/">Stanford's Natural Language
Processing online class</a>. If you couldn't take
it this quarter, look for it, it is a terrific place to learn about this
topic</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell...</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader's curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It's like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
