<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: education | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/education/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-20T20:04:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Pirate Party Will Help Improve Internet Regulation]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/09/why-the-pirate-party-will-help-improve-internet-regulation/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T10:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/09/why-the-pirate-party-will-help-improve-internet-regulation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past years, we have seen a lot of developped countries
governments pushing for more regulation of the Internet, and less
privacy for users. There are three main reasons: protection of
children, prevention of terrorism and <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/29/sopa-hadopi-future-of-culture/">fight against illegal downloading</a>. This has led to very repressive and usually inefficient laws, for example in Australia, in France (Hadopi) and <a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/hillicon-valley/technology/220181-dodd-says-sopa-can-live-again">possibly soon</a> in the US. I think that a big part of this problem is that a very large portion of the people making these laws understand next to nothing about the Internet, and are thus afraid of it. What can we do about it?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/20888197@N00/103031916/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/43/103031916_5c6c0a51af_m.jpg" alt="Pirate" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/opid/" title="Author">sereneonion</a></em></p>

<h2>Direct education is not enough</h2>

<p>Direct education is the most natural answer. Initiatives like Google's
<a href="http://www.20thingsilearned.com/en-US">20 things I learned about browsers and the Web</a> for example, aim at explaining very simply the basics to beginners. More focused initiatives like the <a href="http://www.eg8forum.com/en/">electronic G8 forum</a>, which was held last year in Paris are interesting too. But unfortunately, none of these will make a real impact as long as politicians have so little interest for this world. What we really need is to make them <strong>want</strong> to learn about the Internet.</p>

<h2>The Pirate Party can play a significant role</h2>

<p>What politicians really care about is of course to get (re)elected. And
since they are busy people, they only tackle the subjects they feel are the
most importants for voters, which are nowadays the economic crisis and
unemployment. This is where I think the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pirate_Party">Pirate Party</a> has a huge role to play. Even though they are still a fringe party today, they <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/09/20/world/europe/in-berlin-pirates-win-8-9-percent-of-vote-in-regional-races.html">have had some electoral success</a> and have shown the political world that voters do care about Internet-related issues. If they continue to be successful, I am pretty sure that mainstream politicians, who hold the real power, will want to understand the Internet better, leading to a more fruitful public debate.</p>

<p>It will surely take some time, but I think <strong>it will happen</strong>, because it already happened in the past: 30 years ago, neither voters nor politicians cared about the environment, and the Green parties were regarded the same way the Pirate party is today. Now, ecology is a significant political topic in many European countries. The Internet is next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Didn't Learn In College]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T23:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/04/what-we-didnt-learn-in-college</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Albert Wenger is right:
<a href="http://continuations.com/post/20112755144/students-are-woefully-prepared-for-internet-age-job">we are woefully prepared for internet age job market</a>.
The three of us graduated in Computer Science in college, following a solid
engineering cursus. But during the
numerous courses we took we never heard of <a href="http://github.com/">Github</a> nor <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">StackOverflow</a>.
People attending creative and artistic
formation don't hear of <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a> neither.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7044/7046351459_53d8ed3283.jpg" alt="Jeff Atwood" /></p>

<p>You could argue: "What's the problem with that? You aren't supposed to learn
how to use these platforms in school but core skills in your field!"</p>

<p>But that would be missing a point. The education we all receive has one final
goal: be prepared to get the best job as possible. In our current
era <strong>finding a job doesn't come down to respond to job offers by sending
cover letters and resume</strong> nor spam by email all our contacts in the industry
to get an interview.</p>

<p>We are lucky to live through the emergence and the
expansion of specialized platforms which can help us build our personal
and professional identity. With these platforms <strong>we can easily have a
professional visibility, expose our skills so they can be assessed by
everyone and acquire real experience with real work.</strong></p>

<p>The very first recommendation we should receive beginning a course in
a topic is registering on all the platforms related to this topic. The
professors should foster us to leverage these platform to develop our
skills, build our expertise and gain some fame. Such platforms work this way: they play with
our ego to encourage us to contribute more and more and make our
achievements visible for everyone in return. <strong>They are built to be our showcase</strong> and
we should take advantage of it. We do so many interesting projects in
school, sometimes state of the art implementations in CS, that get lost
on our machine. They should be public to catch recruiters' attention on
our profile and skills or help us <a href="http://cdixon.org/2012/02/26/the-internet-is-reshaping-our-economy-from-one-of-huge-corporations-with-lots-of-jobs-to-huge-platforms-with-lots-of-income-streams/">create our future income streams</a>.</p>

<p>So at which level can we improve the promotion of such platforms? At the school's level?
At the professors' level? They should all keep up with the internet economy like they
usually keep up with the <em>real</em> economy. Schools should increase professors' awareness, who
are mainly researchers in engineering schools for example, to this
concern but it's up to the professors to promote personaly the right
platforms. Professors do already a great job teaching us their
knowledge, <strong>they should go further and encourage us to capitalize on their
teaching</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why so Many French are Not Entrepreneurs]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/16/why-so-many-french-are-not-entrepreneurs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>France's higher education trains world-class engineers, but is home to very few successful start-ups. Having studied engineering in France and then at Stanford University, I will try to explain this apparent paradox.</em></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/2417001179/"><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2168/2417001179_d5ce2d9362_m.jpg" alt="Test taking" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/billselak/" title="Author">billaday</a></em></p>

<h2>Party hard, study a bit, get straight As</h2>

<p>When I took my first classes at Stanford University, I was very
surprised by the difficulty level of engineering classes. My French friends and I found the material to be straightforward, the assignments and exams were easy and the grading more than forgiving. We would party a lot, study a bit, and still get close to 4.0 GPAs. Simply put, we thought we were on top of the world. Of course, we were wrong.</p>

<h2>The hard reality</h2>

<p>But then we took an entrepreneurship class ("hey, how hard can that
be ?"), and the professor asked us who had already created a company.
"What a joke, who creates a company at 22 ?" was the question that
crossed my mind. But three quarters of the class raised their hand,
and we realized that we were indeed not at the top of the world.</p>

<h2>Hone your test-taking skills</h2>

<p>If you are not French, you probably don't know anything about its arcane
higher education, and you can read <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=1292">this PhD comic</a>
for a very good introduction. To sum it up, there is only one way to be part of the academic elite after high school,
and it is to enter the <em>"prepa"</em>, a two years long very intensive cursus at the end of which you take a competitive exam and get into the best school
(<em>"grande ecole"</em>) your rank enables you to. Once you get into one of these, you are assured you will easily land
one of the best/most well-paid jobs available.</p>

<p>There are good points to this system. It teaches us rigor, hard
work, how to handle pressure and a lot about theoretical science. But what we learn
best is how to do well at tests. And since it is so hard,
people from this system are still very proud of their
achievement 20 years later.</p>

<h2>"I can do it!"</h2>

<p>Basically in France, a lot of people believe that we can measure an
individual's skills by how well he fared in a test 20 years ago. We tend
to favorably view people with a perfect pedigree: the best school, and
then a job at an elite consulting or investment-banking firm. Trying to create a start-up but failing is
not well preceived at all.</p>

<p>Americans are very different. They believe that you should use the most
recent achievements to judge a person's skills, and that if you try, you
can do it. Where many a Frenchman would not even try for fear of failing,
Americans believe that success is inevitably down the road. And so
they try. And so they end up winning.</p>

<h2>The best of both worlds</h2>

<p>I don't think the French system is inherently bad. It produces very good engineers with a strong Math background that is useful to become a good coder. But it is time we stopped having this "everything is a test"
mentality, and understand that <strong>failing is not necessarily a bad thing, if you seriously
tried</strong>. Thinking like this would radically change the French start-up
ecosystem: not only would we have more entrepreneurs, but also less
risk-adverse investors, and more ambitious ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
