<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: time | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/time/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-30T11:00:36+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn't consolidated in
some fashion. That's why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author's reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You're asking that person for too much work. She doesn't have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it's high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you'll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it's spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Keep Up With the Information Overload]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/how-to-keep-up-with-the-information-overload</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook notifications, Twitter feeds, RSS feeds, emails, news
aggregators and now so much
more. We are constantly hit by new information, throughout the day, and
the night. There are so many things we want to read or watch.
The fact that the Web is a strictly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">RESTful</a> application (or should I say
<a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2012-02-13-an-api-ontology">Hypermedia</a>) doesn't help because one link usually leads to more links. I'm sure
you've already experienced having more than 20 tabs open in your browser
and thinking "<em>God, when am I going to read all of this?</em>" but instead
of starting reading you scan the links of the page in front of you and
just open more tabs. And this was only made worse by tools such as
<a href="http://instapaper.com" title="Instapaper">Instapaper</a> that make you feel good
about saving stuff for later, even if you know deep inside you'll never
come back to it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/2925760927/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3244/2925760927_a9db10926e_m.jpg" alt="Information overload" /></a></p>

<h2>Current solutions</h2>

<p>It's extremely hard to keep up with all that information, and you
basically have 3 options at the moment:</p>

<h4>Let loose</h4>

<p>Accept that you can't follow it all and if something is really important
it will come back to you one way or another so that missing it the first
time is not a big deal.
I personnally don't like this solution because it means giving up
control on what I read and learn, and it basically amounts to a random
filter with some bias towards the most important news that isn't always
the most interesting.</p>

<h4>Algorithmic filters</h4>

<p>Use tools such as <a href="http://news.me" title="News.me">News.me</a> or <a href="http://focus.io" title="Focus.io">Focus.io</a> that
use machine learning techniques to serve you the stories you might be
interested in the most. However, again, not knowing how these algorithms
work exactly, I fear I am going to lose the serendipity of scanning
myself all the input and selecting the hidden little gem that would be
considered as noise by these algorithms. Again, I hate losing control. I
do think these are better solutions than just letting loose.</p>

<h4>Reducing the input</h4>

<p>This for me is the best alternative. Following sort of a <em>less is more</em> convention,
I am looking to reduce the number of sources rather than increasing it,
keeping only the outstanding ones. I am constantly reevaluating the
quality of the twitter accounts and bloggers I follow in order to remove
those that either tweet too much  or whose content quality has suffered.
I am very rarely looking for new people to follow, and when I try
someone new it is always an experiment, never set in stone. I'd actually
like it if an algorithm could do that for me, again, not knowing the
inner workings of the services that offer news recommendation is too
bad. I'm willing to bet none of them though is going to unfollow someone
on twitter for you, or experiment with a new follower, based on the
quality of the links provided in the tweets. Same for RSS feeds.</p>

<h2>We need a new tool to find good content</h2>

<p>Basically none of today's tools are good at finding good news and
information. You can use a combination of tools (such as <a href="http://quora.com" title="Quora">Quora</a> and <a href="http://stackexchange.com" title="StackEchange">StackExchange</a> but it is more
difficult than one tool and is conducive to a lot of noise. Plus we are
missing a linking tool between content of the same nature and topics,
that would transcend time. There are services like <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a> that you
can browse by searching for tags, but it is not powerful enough in the
way it presents the information. There are still too many links and not
enough clues as to which are interesting and which are not.</p>

<p>But don't worry, we're working on it ;)</p>

<p>Photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/martinofranchi/">Martino</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Time Dimension on the Web, Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://continuations.com/post/18605081084/bringing-time-back-to-the-web-or-the-struggle-for" title="Source">Bringing Time Back to the Web (Or: The Struggle for Depth)</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/albertwenger">Albert Wenger</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<ul>
<li>There is so much new content on the Web every day that one can barely
keep up with it</li>
<li>It is becoming ever harder to delve into the past, a problem
aggravated by Google's recent tilt of their search algorithm towards
recency</li>
<li>We need to surface time explicitly. For example, imagine a version of
Techmeme where you can see the historical precedents of any post, or a
search engine that allows you to "scroll" into the past of any result</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/29/raspberry-pi_n_1310441.html" title="Source">Raspberry Pi Mini Computer Served Up For $35</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/courteney-palis">Courteney Palis, Huffington Post</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Palis describes the $35-a-piece Raspberry PI micro-computer and the
implications for the teaching of computer science</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The Raspberry Pi device</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>A complete computer for $35</li>
<li>Credit-card sized</li>
<li>"Last-decade" hardware (700 Mhz processor, 256 MB RAM) that's still
enough to run Linux, code, browse the internet and even play games such
as Quake 3 !</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>What this means</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Programming can be learned by almost anyone</li>
<li>People in poor areas, children in poor schools get access to technology</li>
<li>Like the Kinect, the Raspberry Pi will enable hackers to build ever
more impressive prototypes. The possibilities are endless</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/raspberry-pi.html" title="Source">Fred Wilson on the Raspberry Pi</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fredwilson">@fredwilson</a> - March 1, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Fred Wilson explains why he thinks the Raspberry Pi is a game changer</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Hardware that's currently expensive (phones and especially tablets)
is going to be cheaper and cheaper. We will see sub $100 tablets in 3 to
5 years</li>
<li>The Raspberry Pi's goal is, according to the developper, to entice
children to learn to code. But all markets that can be end-to-end
digital, not just education, will be disrupted</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
