<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: makers | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/makers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-26T19:03:31+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makers Don't Work With Deadlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/makers-dont-work-with-deadlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A maker is someone who likes to make stuff, to build things. It can be
an artist, a craftsman, an architect, a designer. But it can also be a
software developer. I'm talking about good developers. Those that take
pride in their work.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/aidanmorgan/2331754875/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3140/2331754875_e6a2a81429_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/24742305@N00/" title="Author">John-Morgan</a></em></p>

<h2>How we work</h2>

<p>Often times, people ask me how we work, how we manage things, and more
generally how software should be managed. And my response always
suprises them: no deadlines, <a href="http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch07_Meetings_Are_Toxic.php">no meetings</a>, we just make stuff as we go.</p>

<h2>Why French project managers mostly do it wrong</h2>

<p>In France most people think
software is a commodity, meaning they try to find the cheapest person
out there that will do the job. If your site is selling socks, that's
probaly a decent bet because their isn't a lot of technology involved
and your core business is selling socks, not your website.</p>

<p>So the problem with that thinking is that the premise is utterly wrong.
Good software is not a commodity, it comes at a price and not
everyone can do it. Even people who sell <a href="http://dollarshaveclub.com">shaving kits</a> have figured that
out.</p>

<h2>Let your artists work for you</h2>

<p>My point is good developers are not mere factory workers. They are elite
craftsmen or even artists, and they should be managed as such. Craftsmen
and artists can't measure their work by the hour, they can't follow a
well-defined schedule, you can't tell them what are the priorities. They
will figure it out by themselves! Just let them work. If a bug needs to
be fixed, they will fix it because they care about the quality of their
code.</p>

<h2>Productivity cannot be commanded</h2>

<p>Developers, like artists, need to get "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_%28psycholog%29">in the zone</a>)" in order to be
productive. You can't make them get in the zone, you let them do it. So
stop handing them a todolist lovingly prioritised with strict deadlines,
it is useless. They are makers, they will work becauses they like what
they do and they love building things. There is no need to tell them to
do it. And if they want to work from 3pm to 3am because that's when they
are the most productive, let them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
