<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SEO | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/seo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-20T20:04:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] BizDev vs SEO - Google+ value]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T16:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and then to encourage you to go read the complete post
should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h2><a href="http://also.roybahat.com/post/19307918051/bd-is-the-new-seo" title="Source">BizDev is the new SEO</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/roybahat">@roybahat</a> - Mar 16, 2012</em></p>

<p>Roy Bahat writes a follow up to Roger and Mike's
<a href="http://rogerandmike.com/post/18870279638/what-is-the-hypernet" title="Hypernet">article on the Hypernet</a>.
He explains why business development may replace SEO in the next
Internet era.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Changes</strong>

<ul>
<li>the iPhone changed the internet, by taking us away from the SEO-driven world of URLs and websites</li>
<li>Search won’t come first. New services succeed without ever really needing to master search (Pinterest, Angry Birds etc.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New perspectives</strong>

<ul>
<li>Some think social media optimization will replace search engine optimization but that's not all</li>
<li>In the next era, you can get discovered merely by having a strong relationship with one of the platforms of discovery</li>
<li>Business development may take the place of SEO.  This could be great for companies with well-known brands based on a quality service</li>
<li>That’s awful for new services with great content but no way to get an <em>in</em> – but it’s great for wonderful brands who might otherwise have struggled with the strange world of search algorithms</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases" title="Source">What you could do if you were google and had their databases</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a> - Mar 15, 2012</em></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij thinks about the value of Google+ for Google and why
they are pushing it so hard. This article outlines a hypothetical way in which Google+ could be of major strategic value for Google in its core business, search.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The value of links is decreasing</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>People that relied on links will now rely on Google reducing the value of links between sites</li>
<li>People that realize that Google values links will create lots of them still further reducing the value of links between sites</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Why Google is promoting Google+</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>analytics + social network tells you what social circles are reading which articles</li>
<li>Someone that is professionally engaged in a certain field carefully studying an article in that same field is likely a good indicator that such an article is at least worthy of some notice</li>
<li>There is no algorithm as good at discriminating bad content from good content as the human mind</li>
<li>Every user in Google+ is actually now an unpaid Google employee whose actions are used to influence the google search results as a way to stop further erosion of the results due to spam</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
