<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: server | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/server/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-19T11:25:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What To Use Upstart (And Other Supervisors) For]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/08/22/upstart-and-node/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/08/22/upstart-and-node</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="tldr-embed-widget" data-align="center">      <p>      <a href="http://tldr.io/tldrs/504def5fe1eaddb23a00002c/what-to-use-upstart-and-other-supervisors-for-" class="link-to-tldr-page" target="_blank">Summary of "What To Use Upstart (And Other Supervisors) For -"</a> (via <a href="http://tldr.io" target="_blank">tldr.io</a>)      <ul>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">We should stop having software handle system tasks like daemonization or privilege-dropping</li>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">That’s a job for a supervisor. For example we use Upstart</li>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">Nodejs plays nicely with Upstart, article links to an Upstart script for launching a nodejs application</li>      </ul>      </p></blockquote>


<script async src="http://needforair.com//tldr.io/embed/widget-embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>We are currently building a webapp with the following stack: nodejs,
mongoDB, nginx and redis. We also use a certain number of services,
like <a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/07/09/jenkins-in-production/">Jenkins</a> and Graphite.
To use these softwares in production, we need to be able to daemonize
them, run them as specific users (usually with low privileges), and have
tham restart automatically if case of an unexpected crash.</p>

<p><a href="http://upstart.ubuntu.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="Jenkins CI" src="http://upstart.ubuntu.com/img/upstart80.png"></a></p>

<p>These are quite common needs. But people are often confused as to what
part of the system is responsible for what task. I often see software
handling the privilege drop (for example the otherwise excellent
<a href="http://graphite.wikidot.com/">Graphite</a>), or the daemonization (for
example <a href="http://gunicorn.org/">gunicorn</a> - which is also great
otherwise). It's bad, because as a result, some of these softwares don't
play nicely with supervisors like Upstart. People tend to resort to
strange and not well understood scripts (I even saw an Upstart script
that called the <em>start_stop_daemon</em> to launch a gunicorn process which
daemonized itself!).</p>

<p>There is a simple rule to follow to avoid this confusion:
<strong>softwares should not daemonize or handle privilege drop</strong>. These are
jobs for the supervisor. That's all, separation of concerns, folks. For
example, we use Upstart to launch our processes as services. That way,
we get added benefits: they get respawned in case they crash, they
restart automatically if we need to reboot the server, and we can
specify rules such as "service A should not start before service B has started
and is ready". I see no reason not to it that way!</p>

<p>An example of software that respects these rules is nodejs. Here is <a href="https://gist.github.com/3385102">the
Upstart script</a> we use with it. It enables us to start our app as any
user, log all output and get the added benefits I was referring to
earlier. It really is all you need with nodejs and most software you
will use. This is not an Upstart tutorial (<a href="http://upstart.ubuntu.com/cookbook/">their doc</a> is pretty good),
but let me explain the most important parts:</p>

<ul>
<li>The privilege drop is done through the <code>su -s /bin/sh -c 'exec "$0" "$@"' $RUN_AS -- command</code> part.
This line executes <code>command</code> as user <code>$RUN_AS</code>. Unfortunately, we have to use this method because the standard
<code>sudo -u</code> doesn't work from within an Upstart script.</li>
<li>The log file needs to be <code>touch</code>ed in case it doesn't exist, then <code>chown</code>ed to user <code>$RUN_AS</code>, because otherwise
it will belong to user root (which the user executing the Upstart script)</li>
<li>The rest is pretty standard</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, this script doesn't work just for nodejs! So you have no excuse not to use it now :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Use Jenkins for Continuous Deployment]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/07/09/jenkins-in-production/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-09T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/07/09/jenkins-in-production</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="tldr-embed-widget" data-align="center">      <p>      <a href="http://tldr.io/tldrs/50b88a6e094d8edc2b00013e/how-we-use-jenkins-for-continuous-deployment" class="link-to-tldr-page" target="_blank">Summary of "How We Use Jenkins for Continuous Deployment"</a> (via <a href="http://tldr.io" target="_blank">tldr.io</a>)      <ul>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">Continuous integration is a must for software projects. It makes deployment stressless and lets you spot problems as soon as they arrive, not 3 months later.</li>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">We take it one step further and use continuous deployment. Whenever one of us Git-pushes to master, the new code is tested and goes live right away.</li>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">Jenkins makes it easy. With the Github plugin, you connect Jenkins to Github's post-receive hook so that any code pushed to our repo triggers the Jenkins job.</li>          <li style="margin-bottom: 10px; line-height: 130%;">The Hipchat plugin lets Jenkins notify us whether the build was successful or not. That way we can react quickly if something goes wrong.</li>      </ul>      </p></blockquote>


<script async src="http://needforair.com//tldr.io/embed/widget-embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>As all teams working on a web application, we had to setup a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration">continuous
integration</a> server. This is
a fairly well-known engineering practice, where you want your code to be built and tested
regularly on the server so that you spot problems as soon as they arrive and not when
you push three months' worth of work to production. Also, it makes deployment a much less
stressful experience, because you know it will work. You avoid getting in the situation
of a friend of mine who could not have coffee with me because he was deploying and didn't want
to mess it up!</p>

<p>We also wanted to take it one
step further, and use continuous deployment. As the name implies, this
means that any new code pushed to the server will automatically be
built, tested and then go live and be used by our users right away. It
turns out that is fairly easy to set up -except for a few caveats-, and
I will describe our setup. This by no means a step-by-step tutorial but
rather a "here is what you can do" article.</p>

<p><a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/" target="_blank"><img alt="Jenkins CI" src="http://jenkins-ci.org/sites/default/files/jenkins_logo.png"></a></p>

<h2>Our Tech Stack - The Part Of It That Matters For This Article</h2>

<p>Our server runs on Ubuntu 12.04 LTS, our version control system is Git
(we use <a href="http://scottchacon.com/2011/08/31/github-flow.html">Github flow</a>) and our
code is hosted on Github. We chose to use <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins</a> as
the CI server. Even though it is poorly documented and has a definite
'so nineties' feel, it is very easy to deploy and intuitive. Basically, you use it
to set up jobs that are run when you launch them manually or when an external event, such
as a code push, is triggered. These jobs can be anything that's executable, I usually use
simple bash scripts but you can use any kind of script, makefiles and so on.</p>

<h2>Install And Keep Jenkins Up And Running At All Times</h2>

<p>Jenkins is contained in a WAR file, so you can simply download and execute it with
java (command <code>java -jar /path/to/jenkins.war</code>). Of course, this is only
suitable for testing purposes. In production, you will want to use an
<a href="http://upstart.ubuntu.com/">Upstart</a> script so that Jenkins respawns if
it crashes unexpectedly and starts on boot.</p>

<p>When Jenkins is up, you have
access to a web interface to manage it (you can configure the port on which
it listens). Make sure to enable security -I recommend matrix based security- unless you want anyone to be
able to take control of your servers! One thing to watch out for is that
you need to enable the "overall read" permission for the anonymous user,
or else Jenkins won't be able to communicate with third-party services - in our case Github and Hipchat. Pretty stupid
behaviour I know, but at least it doesn't create security holes.</p>

<h2>Build On Push To Master</h2>

<p>We have the Git and Github plugins enabled. The <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Github+Plugin">Github plugin</a>
enables us to connect Jenkins to Github's post-receive hook. That way,
whenever someone pushes to master (usually by merging a feature branch),
our Jenkins "build" job pulls the new version of the code, builds it and
test it. For us, that's really a two-line script, as we <a href="http://www.mikealrogers.com/posts/nodemodules-in-git.html">check all
modules in to Git</a>.</p>

<p>If everything was successful, the "deploy" job is now called. It pulls
the new version of the code in the live repository, then restarts the
node server (since we use nodejs, we can overwrite the javascript files
when the server is running without impacting it). Node starts pretty
fast, so we only have ~0.1s downtime (no load balancer to achieve 0s downtime - for now!). And since we use an external store
to manage sessions, nobody gets logged out.</p>

<h2>Be Notified</h2>

<p>The last part of the puzzle is how we get notified of the build result.
We use <a href="https://www.hipchat.com/">Hipchat</a>, so we installed the Hipchat
plugin that notifies us of build results in a dedicated chat room. Most
of the time it just says "Build successful". But no sweat if a build
fails, since the "deploy" job was not called our users don't see
anything wrong!</p>

<h2>And That's All There's To It!</h2>

<p>Yup. It is indeed simple enough to get a robust continuous deployment
system up and running, that most of the time safely deploys your code
through a simple <code>git push</code> on your part. I'm interested in anything you
would have to say on this setup or any tip you'd like to share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
