<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: digest | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/digest/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-25T15:30:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] BizDev vs SEO - Google+ value]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T16:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/digest-bizdev-new-seo-google-plus-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and then to encourage you to go read the complete post
should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h2><a href="http://also.roybahat.com/post/19307918051/bd-is-the-new-seo" title="Source">BizDev is the new SEO</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/roybahat">@roybahat</a> - Mar 16, 2012</em></p>

<p>Roy Bahat writes a follow up to Roger and Mike's
<a href="http://rogerandmike.com/post/18870279638/what-is-the-hypernet" title="Hypernet">article on the Hypernet</a>.
He explains why business development may replace SEO in the next
Internet era.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Changes</strong>

<ul>
<li>the iPhone changed the internet, by taking us away from the SEO-driven world of URLs and websites</li>
<li>Search won’t come first. New services succeed without ever really needing to master search (Pinterest, Angry Birds etc.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New perspectives</strong>

<ul>
<li>Some think social media optimization will replace search engine optimization but that's not all</li>
<li>In the next era, you can get discovered merely by having a strong relationship with one of the platforms of discovery</li>
<li>Business development may take the place of SEO.  This could be great for companies with well-known brands based on a quality service</li>
<li>That’s awful for new services with great content but no way to get an <em>in</em> – but it’s great for wonderful brands who might otherwise have struggled with the strange world of search algorithms</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2><a href="http://www.jacquesmattheij.com/What+you+could+do+if+you+were+google+and+had+their+databases" title="Source">What you could do if you were google and had their databases</a></h2>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jmattheij">@jmattheij</a> - Mar 15, 2012</em></p>

<p>Jacques Mattheij thinks about the value of Google+ for Google and why
they are pushing it so hard. This article outlines a hypothetical way in which Google+ could be of major strategic value for Google in its core business, search.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The value of links is decreasing</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>People that relied on links will now rely on Google reducing the value of links between sites</li>
<li>People that realize that Google values links will create lots of them still further reducing the value of links between sites</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Why Google is promoting Google+</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>analytics + social network tells you what social circles are reading which articles</li>
<li>Someone that is professionally engaged in a certain field carefully studying an article in that same field is likely a good indicator that such an article is at least worthy of some notice</li>
<li>There is no algorithm as good at discriminating bad content from good content as the human mind</li>
<li>Every user in Google+ is actually now an unpaid Google employee whose actions are used to influence the google search results as a way to stop further erosion of the results due to spam</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn't consolidated in
some fashion. That's why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author's reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You're asking that person for too much work. She doesn't have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it's high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you'll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it's spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Habits, Realtime Analytics, Media Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/06/digest-habits-realtime-analytics-media-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/06/digest-habits-realtime-analytics-media-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://www.nirandfar.com/2012/02/habits-are-new-viral-why-startups-must.html" title="Source">Habits Are The New Viral: Why Startups Must Be Behavior Experts</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/nireyal">@nireyal</a> - Feb 26, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Nir Eyal describes the importance of habits besides virality for the
success of products in the Curated Web</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Habits are what matters. Web businesses success increasingly depends on the strength of their users' habitual behavior</li>
<li>Web 1.0 companies measured success by pageviews and CPM, whereas new (social) companies proved  to be valuable because they were habit-forming (hot triggers, variable rewards, regular check-in...)</li>
<li>At the dawn of the Curated Web, companies must build habit creation into their products and business models. Not only are users inundated by distractions, but acquiring users is also harder than ever before</li>
<li>Companies which successfully create user habits can build huge enterprises, even without viral growth (Evernote, Amazon)</li>
<li>The more the user engages with a Curated Web company, the more data the company has to tailor and improve the user&rsquo;s experience. This self-improving feedback loop has the potential to be more useful &ndash; and more addictive &mdash; than anything we&rsquo;ve seen before</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/26/facebook-insights-real-time/" title="Source">Facebook To Speed Up Biz Analytics Tool Insights To Report In Real-Time</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/joshconstine">@JoshConstine</a> - Feb 26, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Josh Constine reports the move of Facebook Analytics Tool Insights to
Real Time and describes all the possibilities it will enable</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Page performance data in (near) real-time rather than on average 48 hour delay could enable businesses to reach higher ROIs</li>
<li>Immediate &ldquo;people talking about this&rdquo; data could give marketers a sense of a post&rsquo;s virality, and indicate if they should modify the content or the apps they link to</li>
<li>&ldquo;Insights API give Page owners an opportunity to see how their Page actually lives and breathes&rdquo;.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s up to us as tool developers to turn that data into something awesome and present it in relevant actionable analytics.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/25/print-is-dead-long-live-print/" title="Source">Print is Dead! Long Live Print?</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jordankurzweil">@JordanKurzweil</a> - Feb 25, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Jordan Kurzweil describes the context of &ldquo;digital magazination&rdquo; of content. He states some recommendations to straighten up print business. At the heart of his reflexion is personalized and curated content</em></p>

<ul>
<li>PRINT IS DEAD. revenue, subscriptions and circulation are declining</li>
<li>What can Old Print do to survive? Stop rearranging the deck chairs on the Titanic, grow a pair, and change your business model:

<ul>
<li>Accept this evolution (aging and fragmentation of audience, concurrency from other digital media ...) and embrace it</li>
<li>Start thinking like startups: use some of your profits to incubate new ideas (e.g. Washington post personalized headlines)</li>
<li>Rethink your organization : everyone should be a doer, contributing 100 percent of her/his work hours to making things</li>
<li>Stop thinking that technology serves content: they are now one and the same, each working with the other to delight and engage your users</li>
<li>Update web platforms</li>
<li>Use data to inform your editorial and product decisions</li>
<li>Break down the wall between editors, writers and readers</li>
<li>Consider your content as a currency, not the end-all be-all but a means to an end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Time Dimension on the Web, Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/04/digest-getting-time-back-on-the-web-raspberry-pie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://continuations.com/post/18605081084/bringing-time-back-to-the-web-or-the-struggle-for" title="Source">Bringing Time Back to the Web (Or: The Struggle for Depth)</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/albertwenger">Albert Wenger</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<ul>
<li>There is so much new content on the Web every day that one can barely
keep up with it</li>
<li>It is becoming ever harder to delve into the past, a problem
aggravated by Google's recent tilt of their search algorithm towards
recency</li>
<li>We need to surface time explicitly. For example, imagine a version of
Techmeme where you can see the historical precedents of any post, or a
search engine that allows you to "scroll" into the past of any result</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/29/raspberry-pi_n_1310441.html" title="Source">Raspberry Pi Mini Computer Served Up For $35</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/courteney-palis">Courteney Palis, Huffington Post</a> - February 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Palis describes the $35-a-piece Raspberry PI micro-computer and the
implications for the teaching of computer science</em></p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>The Raspberry Pi device</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>A complete computer for $35</li>
<li>Credit-card sized</li>
<li>"Last-decade" hardware (700 Mhz processor, 256 MB RAM) that's still
enough to run Linux, code, browse the internet and even play games such
as Quake 3 !</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>What this means</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Programming can be learned by almost anyone</li>
<li>People in poor areas, children in poor schools get access to technology</li>
<li>Like the Kinect, the Raspberry Pi will enable hackers to build ever
more impressive prototypes. The possibilities are endless</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2012/03/raspberry-pi.html" title="Source">Fred Wilson on the Raspberry Pi</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fredwilson">@fredwilson</a> - March 1, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Fred Wilson explains why he thinks the Raspberry Pi is a game changer</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Hardware that's currently expensive (phones and especially tablets)
is going to be cheaper and cheaper. We will see sub $100 tablets in 3 to
5 years</li>
<li>The Raspberry Pi's goal is, according to the developper, to entice
children to learn to code. But all markets that can be end-to-end
digital, not just education, will be disrupted</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Lies from Losers, Web/Mobile Integration, Community Feedback]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-01T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/01/digest-lies-from-losers-web-mobile-integration-community-feedback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://bhorowitz.com/2012/02/29/lies-that-losers-tell/" title="Source">Lies that Losers Tell</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/bhorowitz">@bhorowitz</a> - Feb 29, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Ben Horowitz describes the false explanations CEOs and employees find a
posteriori to justify their failure and why they do that. Stop burrying
your head in the sand.</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Familiar lies</strong>

<ul>
<li>“<em>She left, but we were going to fire her, or give her a bad performance review</em>” : Instead of justifying the departure of your employees giving false excuses, ask yourself why you couldn't keep them.</li>
<li>“<em>We would have won, but the other guys gave the deal away</em>” : Validate this claim with the actual customer instead of believing the Sales Rep who doesn't want to take the blame.</li>
<li>"<em>Just because we missed the intermediate milestones doesn’t mean we won’t hit our product schedule</em>" : When the facts don’t align with the good news, a clever manager will find the narrative to make everybody feel better... until the next meeting.</li>
<li>“<em>We have a very high churn rate, but as soon as we turn on email marketing to our user base, people will come back</em>” : The reason that people leave our service and don’t come back is that we have not been sending them enough spam ?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Why are the CEOs/employees lying ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Andy Grove explains that humans, particularly those who build things, only listen to leading indicators of good news and tend to justify bad news with false excuses.</li>
<li>Lying CEOs regularly take action on the positive indicator and look for alternative explanations on the negative indicator.</li>
<li>CEOs are not lying to investors, they are lying to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2012/01/28/web-second-mobile-first/" title="Source">Web Second, Mobile First</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=msuster">@msuster</a> - Jan 28, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Mark Suster reacts to Fred Wilson's blog post <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2010/09/mobile-first-web-second.html" title="AVC blog post">Mobile First, Web Second</a> reminding startups not to forget the Web</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>For 1.5 year people forgot Web Second and just thought Mobile First</strong>

<ul>
<li>It's important not give up on the power of the tethered web, of large screen real estate, of a keyboard.</li>
<li>What's even more important is to have a strategy that matches
customers wants and not developers whims.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mobile has clearly critical attributes</strong>

<ul>
<li>They are personal, location aware, occupy a lot of people's leisure
time.</li>
<li>They are one touch away from buying and represent the "<em>bottom
end of the sales funnel</em>"</li>
<li>The limited real estate forces less choice and offers more focus on
the content.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>But products have to be integrated</strong>

<ul>
<li>Many things cannot be done on a mobile</li>
<li>Mobile should serve a different experience, a different usecase of the service.</li>
<li>The web product can offer complementary services that make the
product even more attractive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leverage the web to :</strong>

<ul>
<li>Create a differentiated product vs your mobile-only competitors.</li>
<li>Enable content creation and curation to make mobile consumption a better experience.</li>
<li>Organize and make the most of the content created by the mobile</li>
<li>Build features that make using native-phones apps pointless.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tablets come third</strong>

<ul>
<li>Extension to mobile strategy (larger real estate make content
  discovery different, increase the features possible...)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/02/listen-to-your-community-but-dont-let-them-tell-you-what-to-do.html" title="Source">Listen to Your Community, But Don't Let Them Tell You What to Do</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/codinghorror">@codinghorror</a> - Feb 3, 2012</em></p>

<p><em>Jeff Atwoods talks about the need to organize your community feedback
to take the most out of it</em></p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Having a meta place to discuss the product is important</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meta participation is the source of all meaningful leadership and governance in a community, so it is cultivated and monitored closely.</li>
<li>Meta is for people who care so deeply about their community that they're willing to go one step further, to come together and spend even more of their time deciding how to maintain and govern it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to leverage this meta place ?</strong>

<ul>
<li>Animate the place : listen, respond</li>
<li>Sort between feedback and feature requests</li>
<li>Know how to extract core information and underlying needs from feature requests</li>
<li>Know to sort between useless and awesome feedback, 10% of the feedback is useful and can be gems</li>
<li>Don't hesitate to be honest explaining the choices the company did
about the features the product offers.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
