<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startup | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-09T16:09:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup, Music and Buzz]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/15/startup-music-and-buzz/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T11:33:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/15/startup-music-and-buzz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Various creative initiatives face the same challenges as startups.
In its
<a href="http://leanpub.com/manifesto">manifesto</a>, <a href="http://leanpub.com/">Leanpub</a> points out the similarities
between writing a book and launching a startup: <em>both are risky, creative
processes, often undertaken in stealth mode and with hit-driven economics.</em></p>

<p>The same parallel can be drawn with the music industry or more generally
with independant creative activities. Crowdfunding platforms
<a href="http://www.mymajorcompany.com/">MyMajorCompany</a> or <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/">KickStarter</a>
illustrate the similarities between all these processes.
Independant singers who are not supported by famous productors bear the risk,
have to build their <em>product</em> and develop their marketing
strategy on their own.</p>

<p>Once the beta version of the product is ready to showcase, a single in
the case of singers, the difficulty is to market it. How can one achieve
some traction? One option that seems profitable is to place the
product in a favourable context by attaching it to an event which
benefits from a good media coverage. Mainstream and new medias alike have such a big impact
on the crowd that they can drain lots of attention. Leveraging these
media can be key.</p>

<p>Recently in France a singer succeeded in creating a buzz
on the internet, hitting more than 600 000 views on Youtube, with its
single on a candidate for the presidential elections. In the same vein
as <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKsoXHYICqU"><em>I got a crush on Obama</em></a> she drew the media attention in a very
effective way by leveraging the current context.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/40084651"><img src="http://www.lalsace.fr/fr/images/A7098988-85DA-4603-8E31-654249FE82BB/ALS_03/capture-d-ecran-du-clip-musical-de-victoire-passage-prends-le-pouvoir-sur-moi-jean-luc-melenchon.jpg" width="400" alt="Video" /></a></p>

<p>Making a buzz gives the impression of success. But how can we be assured it is going to last? Does a spike in the audience really help to succeed with
one's product? When one realize that <a href="http://simply.io/blog/2012/03/welcome-to-the-real-world-just-because-youre-on-techcrunch-doesnt-mean-youve-won/">90% of the companies appearing on TC
are abandoned within 6 months</a>
one can question the relevance of the press coverage and the buzz one
can create to build a durable success. Instead, one should be focused
on building one's audience. Successfull startups and creators don't
rely on a single shot try, they build their success gradually at the same
time as their audience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
