<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: metrics | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/metrics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-26T17:06:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Digest] Assets of a Consumer-Web Startup, Internal People Metrics]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/assets-of-a-consumer-web-startup-internal-people-metrics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digests are summaries of articles posted by entrepreneurs, VCs, and
other people who write about startups and technology in general, curated
by yours truly. The goal is to make them shorter to read by extracting the most relevant
information from our point of view and to encourage you to go read the
complete post should you find the topic interesting.</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://mporat.tumblr.com/post/16753414806/what-asset-are-you-building" title="Source">What assets are you building ?</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/mporat">@mporat</a> - Jan 30, 2012</em></p>

<p>If you are building a consumer internet startup, you need to think about the assets that you are building and how these fit with your scaling and fundraising strategies.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Number of users</strong>

<ul>
<li>Most difficult to execute and scale because the lifetime value of a user is typically very low</li>
<li>Needs low customer acquisition cost, high retention, high conversion, tremendous growth, a lot of financing runway until the sheer number of users can generate huge revenues via advertising or traffic generation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High lifetime value</strong>

<ul>
<li>No need for a lot of users, because you make a lot of money of them.</li>
<li>Rarely needs mass financing because they are cash cows</li>
<li>Can invest heavily in marketing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Massive data</strong>

<ul>
<li>Sometimes (twitter,instagram) the data inputted by the users is more important than the users</li>
<li>Free services to the user in order to leverage the data at scale</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A great platform</strong>

<ul>
<li>Monetization comes from 3rd parties (think facebook/zynga)</li>
<li>Main asset is user engagement with your platform</li>
<li>Need to build the platform as well as the first services on top of it</li>
<li>Needs a lot of financing</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2011/12/13/five-new-management-metrics-you-need-to-know/2/" title="Source">Five New Management Metrics You Need To Know</a></h3>

<p><em>by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/jslavet">@jslavet</a> - Dec 13, 2011</em></p>

<p>Here is a list of 5 very important metrics that never appear in annual
reports. Most companies measure outputs but not inputs or throughput.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Flow State Percentage</strong>

<ul>
<li>Interruptions move us out of flow state which is the state that
enables the most productivity.</li>
<li>It takes seconds to get out of but can
take very long to get back in.</li>
<li>Measure how uninterrupted your
programmers are.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Anxiety-Boredom Continuum</strong>

<ul>
<li>People want to be challenged, but not to the point that they break
down.</li>
<li>On the other hand, people will leave if they are bored.</li>
<li>Check in often with your employees to make sure you are striking the
right balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Meeting Promoter Score</strong>

<ul>
<li>Meetings are very expensive and rarely productive</li>
<li>At the end of each meeting, ask each participant to rate it and
suggest improvements</li>
<li>Usually requires a lot of financing until monetization is effective</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Compound weekly learning rate</strong>

<ul>
<li>The ability to learn is like compounding interest on an investment</li>
<li>Ask your team: how did you get 1% better this week?</li>
<li>Did you learn something valuable from our customers?</li>
<li>Did you make a change to the product that drove better results?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Positive Feedback ratio</strong>

<ul>
<li>Catch people doing good things and tell them</li>
<li>This way when you provide feedback on areas to improve, they will
really listen</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><em>If you would like your article not to be summarized on this blog,
please contact us and we'll take it down
asap</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
