<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: content discovery | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/content-discovery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-19T12:30:03+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Lets You Talk to World-Class Experts]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/20/twitter-lets-you-talk-to-wordclass-experts/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-20T04:35:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/20/twitter-lets-you-talk-to-wordclass-experts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I had a conversation on Twitter with <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/rjs">Ryan
Singer</a> of <a href="http://37signals.com">37 Signals</a>
fame. Ryan is a world-class expert in product design and had just posted an <a href="http://feltpresence.com/articles/16-managing-product-development-by-integrating-around-concerns">article</a>
on his excellent <a href="http://feltpresence.com/">blog</a>. The thing is I am a
nobody in product design or in the tech scene in general. I'm not saying
I'm dumb or anything, just that nobody knows me. And yet I was
still able to have a great and stimulating conversation with an expert
who's email inbox is presumably very full, lives thousands of kilometers
away from me and doesn't know anything about me. This was not the first
time I've been amazed by the power of Twitter, so I decided to blog about
it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brajeshwar/3428525318/in/photostream"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3393/3428525318_0729579705_n.jpg" alt="Twitter Mosaic" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brajeshwar/" title="Author">Brajeshwar</a></em></p>

<h2>140 characters Enable Improbable Conversations</h2>

<p>That length constraint compels people to get straight to the point.
There is no fluff. No awkward openings, no pompous endings, no walls of
text. People expect direct questions and answers and wouldn't have it any other
way.</p>

<p>This magically enables you to talk to some people you would never have sent an
email to. And busy people that don't know you at all, that might be
thought leaders or experts, will answer you if
you ask an interesting question. Because the constraint also works for
the response: they don't have to send you a long well thought-out answer,
they don't need to get context to answer, they can just type 140
characters.</p>

<p>I have asked questions to succesful entrepreneurs, or VCs, and almost
always gotten a quick answer. This is incredibly cool and powerful. And
these people don't know me at all.</p>

<h2>No Social Pressure or Awkwardness</h2>

<p>The Twitter feed moves so swiftly that conversations are extremely
ephemeral. I think this is key to enabling these kinds of improbable
conversations. The fact that it moves so quickly reduces the social
pressure: few people will see it, it will not mark your Twitter profile
for a long time, and nobody will assume that the two people conversing
are great friends or anything. Twitter enables conversations in a
vacuum, without having to build up a relationship. There is no pressure
for the expert to become friend with the person he is talking to.</p>

<p>When you try to email or talk on the phone to an expert, you always want to be super apologetic,
respectful and you don't really focus on the content of the
conversation you're trying to have but instead you focus on the
asymmetry of the relationship and that makes you uncomfortable. Twitter makes all these concerns vanish.</p>

<p>I love Twitter for these opportunities.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
