<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: article | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/article/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-09T12:12:42+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show Me the Gist]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/07/show-me-the-gist/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T10:29:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/07/show-me-the-gist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day on Hacker News I came across this
<a href="http://www.inc.com/magazine/201205/burt-helm/turntable-founders-sxsw-where-did-our-love-go.html">article of the Inc. Magazine</a>. Article seemed very interesting, talking about
<a href="http://turntable.fm">Turntable.fm</a>. It had been a while since I hadn't read about Turnable,
all news about collaborative experiences on the web excite me,
the title was linkbaity: I clicked.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7094/7151646789_12625e7615.jpg" width="350" alt="Abstract" /></p>

<p>The first thing I do when I come to a new page is to check the length of
the article. <em>How long will it take me to read this article?</em> This one
made me wince: a very long article split in 4 pages. Two things
scared me: pagination and length.</p>

<p>First I don't like pagination on news website. I am under the
impression of being on Google looking for something and having to go to
page 4 to find it. This article was also too long for me because it was not the only one
I was planning to read. My time is not extensible, there was still work
waiting for me. As I don't want to be a
<a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/04/27/capitalize-on-what-you-read/">passive reader</a> a long article
requires a lot of time to deal with.</p>

<p>I told myself <em>Ok, this article is quite long but I will
force myself to go till the end because that's something really
intriguing</em>. That's how it began. I read the first page without
skipping a line then began the second page. But I couldn't do it.
The article was too long. Way too long. Not boring but inappropriately long for what I expected.
How did it end? I skipped most of the article, read some random
statements to grasp the main ideas. I'm not proud of myself as I really
wanted to get more involved in the subject but
<a href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/">I'm a nutcracker</a>.</p>

<p>I don't think I am the only one in this situation. I <em>really</em> like reading,
documenting myself but I can't always make it with theses long articles. They make
the web interesting to browse, they bring a lot of value but their
barrier to entry is too high and they don't fit into every reading time. We could
really lower this barrier to entry for such articles though, by providing a summary.
That's what scientific researchers do with the abstract
they add to their publications, so couldn't web writers do it too?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
