<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: article | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/article/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-29T17:15:26+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are All Nutcrackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T18:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/we-are-all-nutcrackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In a nutshell...</em> Have you never been looking for this expression
while reading an article? The fact is that we are all fond of digested
information. With Internet and social medias the quantity of information
one has access to has become huge; we are coping with an
<a href="http://needforair.com/information-overload-and-how-to-keep-up-with-5849" title="Overload">information overload problem</a>.
We can potentially be aware of everything that is going on everywhere, instantaneously
and regarding any topic. <strong>In this context, the demand for digested
information is growing tremendously.</strong><br/>
Recently, many startups have been leveraging that fondness to
succeed. <a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/" title="Fanbridge">Franbridge</a> with its
<a href="http://www.fanbridge.com/blog/introducing-social-digest" title="Social Digest">Social digest</a>
will soon reach <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/03/21/as-it-turns-out-fanbridges-most-exciting-product-is-boring-old-email/">10 millions subscribers</a>!<br/>
Why people do love and value digested information so much?</p>

<p><a href="http://freshcode.co/post/Nameservers-in-a-Nutshell-Fresh-Insights-7.aspx"><img src="http://freshcode.co/image.axd?picture=2011%2f7%2fnutshell.jpg" width="220" alt="Nutshell" /></a>
<em>by <a href="http://freshcode.co/" title="Author">FreshCode</a></em></p>

<h2>Digested information is our natural representation of information</h2>

<p>We all love digested information because it makes the information easy
to grasp.
It is very popular because it replicates the mental
process we do when reading. We look for headlines, bold text, headers,
we scan the text to form our overall picture of the content. Digested
information gathers all those clues and eases this process.<br/>
Part of this cognitive process is the memorisation. Digested information
makes memorisation more accessible. Remember those cheatsheets you
religiously wrote down for your exam preparation in college? Reading the digest of an
article has the same effect. When building our personal knowledge
database we store those keywords, key sentences. Digested information is
the natural form of information our brain manipulates when it internally
classifies, archives, queries our memory.</p>

<h2>Digested information piques reader's curiosity</h2>

<p>While reading we like it when the content arouses our curiosity. I would even say
that we expect an article to <em>catch</em> us. Digested information provides
the gist that drives us to the dive in the details. It avoids the wall of text effect and
stimulates our willingness to dig further into subject. It's like reading gossips! You
get hooked and then you want to know more about it.</p>

<p>Digested information is a very valuable resource and its era should come soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
