<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: chat | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/chat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-26T18:11:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Is Asynchronous Communication Superior?]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/14/why-is-asynchronous-communication-superior</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="last article">last article</a>
I detailed why synchronous communication is not
appropriate for work: it leads to interruptions, involves moving or
shouting, drifts and leaves no trace.<br/>
To solve this communication problem I believe in the asynchronous way of
doing it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/6370949347/"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6052/6370949347_a66d54d217_m.jpg" alt="Carrier Pigeon" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/%20licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/68346521@N08/" title="Author">Modestas J</a></em></p>

<h2>Asynchronous?</h2>

<p>WTF is this? In an asynchronous communication
interlocutors can exchange and continue their discussion
whenever they want it. Examples of
asynchronous communication media are letter, text message, email,
chat. They all share a common something in common: they are <strong>written communication
media</strong>.</p>

<h2>Asynchronous Channels Are Superior</h2>

<p>The massive use of text messages illustrates the <strong>usefulness and the
advantages an asynchronous communication offers over an oral conversation.</strong>
It's quick, efficient, you can respond hours later and  keep track of the history.
You should use different asynchronous communication media for different usecases. Your day-to-day conversation?
Do it by chat. A code review? Use Github and Pull Requests. Important annoucements? Write an email. Organize
your communication and insert it in your workflow. Segmenting your communication will help you manage it efficiently
and will diminish the pressure of a single overloaded inbox.</p>

<h2>Why Does Email Kill Your Productivity?</h2>

<p>At work, people seem to use email as the sole form of asynchronous communication. Emails are adapted for
internal communication like <strong>reports, formal announcements</strong>. If you write less-than-two-lines emails
you are doing it wrong. Do you really need an email to say <em>"Ok I'll do it"</em> or <em>"Thanks"</em>?
For everyday use they are counter productive. You end up receiving tons
of emails a day, <strong>spending hours responding, deleting and archiving.</strong></p>

<h2>The Right Communication Medium: the Chat Room</h2>

<p>Setting up a chat room for your team is probably one of the most important
action you can do to improve its efficiency and productivity.
90% of its communication should occur there. With a chat room solution
<strong>conversations history is easily accessible, you can simultaneously participate to
multiple groups of discussions, sending a message is so much easier</strong>! Aren't you bored of
clicking <em>New Message</em>, filling in recipients addresses? Even clicking on <em>Respond</em>
is painful.<br/>
Chat rooms are really the most adequate medium to communicate for your team.
<a href="http://needforair.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-synchronous-communicatio-70441" title="Previous post">Even</a>
if you work at the same place.</p>

<p><strong>Don't waste more time and set up your private chat room.</strong>
<a href="http://www.hipchat.com" title="HipChat">HipChat</a> is a great tool for that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
