<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: memory | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/categories/memory/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-26T17:41:01+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://czzarr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why We Write Digests of Interesting Content]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/why-we-write-digests-of-interesting-content</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All three of us read a lot. Blogs, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com" title="Hacker News">Hacker News</a>, links we get through
Twitter, etc. Browsing dozens of articles a week to stay informed is great but do we get the most out of it? <strong>Do we
actually memorize the gist of all that content we are reading?</strong> Spending
so much time reading would be a huge waste if it wasn't consolidated in
some fashion. That's why we decided to write summaries of the best
articles we find.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00/102673733/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/42/102673733_39cbb51495_n.jpg" alt="Keep the gist" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/60546721@N00">aroid</a></em></p>

<h2>It forces you to really understand what the article is about</h2>

<p>My Math and Physics professors would always say that the best way to learn
was to get to the point where you are able to
<strong>recap the course materials in writing</strong> (theroems, proofs, case studies).</p>

<p>In order to select the most critical parts of an article you need to
really read through the whole article and pick up the signal that you
want to remember. This means you should understand thoroughly what the
article is about and the author's reasoning. Why she spent time on some
subject and not on others.</p>

<p>When writing up a summary, be it by mere copy/pasting or rephrasing, you put yourself
in an active cognitive process. You are not simply consuming
anymore, you are disecting and structuring information. Not only will
your memory be more deeply impressed than if you just read but it will
be more structured and organized.</p>

<h2>You can go back to it later</h2>

<p>Bookmarking is currently the only way of organizing and keeping up with the content that you
loved and that you would want to be able to find again later and share
to others via tools such as <a href="http://delicious.com" title="Delicious">Delicious</a>,
or <a href="http://pinboard.in" title="Pinboard">Pinboard</a>.
However you still need to reread the whole article once you go back to
it, which can be a waste of time in some cases. <a href="http://evernote.com" title="Evernote">Evernote</a> is better in that regard as
you make save notes on any topic.</p>

<p><strong>If you had summaries for each of your bookmarks</strong>, you could go back to
that content and filter it in a much more effective fashion, deciding
whether or not you want to delve into the whole article or not. It is
something between the title and the article that is missing to help you
filter through your bookmarks and consume your content.</p>

<p>We keep all of our digests in an organized way so that they are easily
searchable and consumable.</p>

<h2>Sharing becomes easier</h2>

<p>Digests also make it easier to share content. Ever tried to send a link
to someone, and never got any feedback? Chances are they
are receiving hundreds of links per day, by email, facebook, twitter, etc.
You're asking that person for too much work. She doesn't have enough time
to read yet another whole article without knowing it's high quality content.</p>

<p><strong>If you include a short digest</strong> of the article or video or podcast in your
email, you can be sure there is a much higher chance that she reads the
digest and eventually clicks the link, intrigued. And you'll be
able to have a conversation about it. That is sharing. Sending naked links is not sharing,
it's spamming.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Will Your Last Holidays Photos Become?]]></title>
    <link href="http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://czzarr.github.com/blog/2012/03/19/what-will-your-last-holiday-photos-become</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my wife's grand father funeral. Those moments are intense
family time where everybody gathers together and tells all the anecdotes they
have. The best place to dig into the past is the attic. That's where my
wife found family photographic slides.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/917626896/"><img src="http://farm2.staticflickr.com/1203/917626896_dc53081d31_m.jpg" alt="Rosetta Stone" /></a>
<em><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0" title="license">CC license</a> - by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nathan-w/" title="Author">Nathan Wong</a></em></p>

<p>Those slides were from 35 to 50 years old. My wife and I were skeptical
about the state of the slides, could we get something out of them?
Definitely. They were in perfect state and I'm sure they will still be 50
years from now.  In the living room, we set up the slide projector which was still in great shape
as well. We spent hours and hours viewing 15 years of photos,
laughing at everybody that looked so young, trying to identify people we
had forgotten, remembering good moments spent together. Despite the
circumstances everyone had a great time and forgot one's sadness for a
while.</p>

<p>This episode made me think that today people store their thousands of
photos they take a year on DVDs, hard drives and the cloud. Do you know anyone who has developed their last
holidays photos? I know I haven't. Those new technologies
make for false advertising. They don't last more than 10 to 15 years maximum under
optimal conditions. And at the current pace we won't find an optical
disk reader in 15 years.</p>

<p>That's why I was wondering if our grandchildren will live such
moments. They won't find any usable DVDs nor our Dropbox password in
the attic. What will be the physical media storage support of our generation
that will allow our grandchildren to dive into our memories?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
