<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: IPO | Need for Air]]></title>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/categories/ipo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://needforair.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-30T15:07:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://needforair.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Need for Air]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://ryandeussing.com/">Ryan Deussing</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Positive Thoughts About the Facebook IPO]]></title>
    <link href="http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/29/facebook-ipo/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-29T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://needforair.com/blog/2012/05/29/facebook-ipo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since the Facebook's IPO fiasco, many commenters (mainly bloggers and Wall Street analysts)
seem keen to say that Facebook is really not worth that much. I don't agree, because I think
that trying to determine Facebook's value is premature.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinkrejci/7218818780/" target="_blank"><img alt="Facebook headquarters" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5320/7218818780_9507a57365_n.jpg" height="320px" width="320px"></a>
<em>CC Licence - Author: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kevinkrejci/">Kevin Krejci</a></em></p>

<h2>Facebook's IPO Surely Didn't Go Well</h2>

<p>It's a well-known fact, but it always makes me cringe: I still don't
understand why <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/daniel-dicker/facebook-retail-investors_b_1549602.html">well-connected people would have the right to buy shares
at a better price than "normal" investors</a>.
But it's a fact: if you are one of the underwriters' best clients, you
will be able to purchase the stock at its opening price (in Facebook's
case $38 per share). You will even able to purchase the stock before the IPO, at a lower price than $38.
If you're not, you will have to wait. In this IPO,
retail ("normal") investors had to <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/47043815//">wait until the stock traded at $42 a
share</a> before being able to buy. On
top of this common IPO problem, key information was known to insiders but not
shared with all investors, which is why <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57439918-93/facebook-zuckerberg-sued-over-ipo/">Facebook has been sued</a>.
In that regard, Facebook's IPO surely didn't go well.</p>

<h2>Nobody Knows Facebook's True Worth</h2>

<p>But even though it didn't go well, I am puzzled to read so many negative
comments about Facebook itself. All kinds of people, from bloggers to
Wall Street analyst seem to forget that Facebook still is a
multi-billion dollars business. What I think many fail to see is that,
in fact, nobody can seriously pretend to know Facebook's true worth. It
could be <a href="http://cdixon.org/2012/05/15/facebooks-business-model/">worth a lot more, or a lot less</a>.
This is different from a traditional company, for which everybody knows
the business model (think GM, Total or even Apple). In Facebook's case,
we don't know how they're going to monetize their 900M users. Is it
going to be through advertising? A premium version? Will they be able to
make money on mobile platforms? We (at least I) don't know. A Facebook share is a lottery
ticket, whose value today has nothing to do with its value tomorrow. I for one am
no Facebook expert, so instead of trying to guess the future, I will
just sit back, relax, and see how the Facebook team continues to innovate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
